<bug>
          <bug_id>1036</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-07-07 10:46:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Migration: Make migration data and processing library-specific</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:46:57 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.migration</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>info</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>3665</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2008-07-07 10:46:30 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Migration data should be maintained library-specific (&quot;library&quot; in the generator sense, something that has a &quot;source/class&quot; structure, e.g. the framework, the applications, contribs, ...), e.g. in &quot;source/migration&quot;.

Then, all libraries provide their migration data independently. If migration is invoked on an application, the generator would go through all used libraries and run their migration data on the current application.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>3666</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2008-07-07 10:55:50 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>There are a couple of considerations necessary with this:

* If we want to provide fine-grained migration we need more information:
* The currently used version of each library has to be available (In the old system, only the qooxdoo version was gathered from the Makefile or a command-line option).
* This affects probably also our &quot;library&quot; config.json entry: it has to include a version ID (currently is has only &quot;manifest&quot; and &quot;uri&quot; entries, the latter of which will be removed eventually).
* Then, from each library, newer available versions have to be retrieved, and the user has to specify to which of those he wants to migrate to (&quot;current&quot; or &quot;newest&quot; could be the default).
* Then, the generator can apply the specific migration data for each target version for each library, thus accomplishing the migration of the app under consideration.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>3667</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2008-07-07 11:02:04 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The next evolutionary step here would be to do dependency tracking:

* Libraries of a certain version might depend on other libraries having a certain version. To migrate to a newer version of one library might incur the migration of another library to a certain version.
* On the other hand, if you want to stick with a certain library version, you might not be able to migrate another since the first one would not work with the newer version.
* Basically, the infrastructure to support this is already availabe, since e.g. contribs qualify the qooxdoo version they run against in their manifest.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>4452</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2008-08-19 16:13:40 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>to me</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5246</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-04 15:31:43 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This can wait.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35730</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:46:57 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>