<bug>
          <bug_id>118</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2006-07-30 02:53:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Implement missing features, documentation.</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:22:16 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core</component>
          <version>0.5.2</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://dojotoolkit.org</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.5.3</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Alexander Trauzzi">atrauzzi</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>254</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Trauzzi">atrauzzi</who>
            <bug_when>2006-07-30 02:53:53 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Qooxdoo has a lot of neat features that dojo doesn&#39;t.  Qooxdoo looks a lot more programmer-friendly, even in spite of dojo&#39;s their &quot;package management&quot;.  The biggest I can think of is asynchronous JSON calls and the features surrounding it all.  Dojo just didn&#39;t seem to care when I brought that to their attention.

There are some widgets and features however that put dojo a few steps ahead of you guys.  Text editor, widget appearances.  Your windows are better, but how do I use them?!
Documentation and tutorials are a must.

If there are any developers willing to sit online on some weekends and put up with my painful questions, I&#39;ll help write documents...

It would really be a good idea not to just put this to some time in the future and assign it a meaningless priority.  The more users qooxdoo can attract, the more momentum you&#39;ll gather.  Right now I want to make some UIs using qooxdoo but I simply have no documents and examples to easily learn off of.

Good luck!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>255</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2006-07-30 03:03:40 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Alexander,

Your help in generating better documentation would most certainly be appreciated!  I think you&#39;ll find that if you ask questions on the mailing list rather than &quot;sit online on some weekends&quot; as you suggest, you&#39;ll get better input from more people.  There are different people with expertise in various areas of the code.  If there are particular areas that require a discussion rather than email, moving the discussion to IRC is certainly an option.

The 0.5.2 version that you&#39;re using (or at least that you reference in this bug report) is not being actively developed any longer; it&#39;s the &quot;previous generation&quot;.  Bug fixes are still being done for it, but very little new development.  Pretty much all of the new development is going into the &#39;namespaces&#39; branch, which is in fact about to become &#39;trunk&#39; in svn.  In &#39;namespaces&#39;, there is &quot;better&quot; documentation and a much better method of finding/viewing the documentation.  From a user perspective, though, there&#39;s still a *very* lot that can be done to document overall usage vs. usage of a particular function or class.  Having someone like you dedicated to writing user documentation would be wonderful!

Please, start asking your questions.  I will answer what I can, although my knowledge areas in qooxdoo are still somewhat limited.  I&#39;m quite sure that others will help answer your questions as well.  Ask away!

Derrell
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>723</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2006-11-29 14:19:04 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Should be presented in separate bugs. Maybe some of your ideas are already fixed.... Closing this bug.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37609</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:22:16 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>