<bug>
          <bug_id>1261</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-08-25 14:33:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Website: New organization concept/ideas for manual</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:27:48 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>website</product>
          <component>documentation</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>2.0</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Chris Banford">dev</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>4678</commentid>
            <who name="Chris Banford">dev</who>
            <bug_when>2008-08-25 14:33:00 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I think the move to a single standardized SDK is a good one.

I think what is causing Jason grief is really the current state of the qooxdoo documentation on the site. Although there is a lot of good documentation, there is also a lot missing, or even (it seems) mixing a bit of 0.8 and 0.7?

As soon as the 0.8 release is sorted, I think the biggest area that the qooxdoo project could benefit from would be to do a big push on refining and extending the wiki -- the API and Demo apps are already rather fantastic, but dropping into the qooxdoo universe from outside can be rather daunting, and requires a bit of persistence to get to the point where things start to click.


What I would personally suggest is to reorganize your wiki docs to take the view of someone coming to qooxdoo for the first time. Make the main heading sections be things that new users will want to &#39;discover&#39; and then give them a good portion of &quot;why&quot; things are done, before dumping them into the lower levels of &quot;how&quot; they&#39;re done.

This is just a rough idea -- I don&#39;t know enough of all the system details to make an accurate list...

    * Get all the document detail wiki pages up and working (http://qooxdoo.org/documentation/0.8/) in their current layout state.

    * Identify &quot;Areas&quot; of functionality, that need a higher level set of documentation. These Areas could be things like:

          o qooxdoo Quick Start - Installing the SDK and getting your fist app runing.
                + The ideas and concepts behind qooxdoo
                + Unix-like installation &amp; setup
                      # Standard or SVN
                + Windows installation &amp; setup
                      # Standard or SVN
                + Mac OSX installation &amp; setup
                      # Standard or SVN
                + Hello qooxdoo World
                + Simple Stand Alone app (a full qooxdoo based &quot;desktop-style&quot; app)
                + Simple Inline app (adding a small qooxdoo app to an existing html web page)
          o The qooxdoo Generator
                + An overview of how to generate your apps with qooxdoo
                + The different types of applications you can generate.
                + The organization of a generated qooxdoo project - what goes where, and why.
                + ...
          o Unit Testing how to help make sure your apps work
                + The idea behind Unit Tests.
                + How to add and use the qooxdoo Test Runner in your app
                + Intermediate Testing
                + Advanced Testing
          o Debugging &amp; Profiling
          o OO Programing with qooxdoo
                + All the Class, Interface, Mixin stuff here.
          o GUI Development
                + Widgets
                + Layouts
                + ...
          o Events
          o AJAX server communication
          o Custom Widgets customizing qooxdoo and skinning existing widgets.
          o API Browser
          o Demo application browser
          o qooxdoo libraries user contributed additions to qooxdoo
          o ...


Two things here;

   1. The first is that you&#39;re organizing this documentation from a complete qooxdoo &quot;noob&#39;s&quot; point of view, by starting with the points that are the most relevant for them. So the concept of the wiki documentation overview page would be Novice -&gt; Expert as you move down the page.
   2. The second is that I think that you have a good deal of this information already. It needs to be updated for qooxdoo 0.8 (obviously) and some more in depth &quot;How to do things&quot; articles, that cover both the basics and in-depth details for more advanced users.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>4727</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2008-08-25 19:57:51 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8304</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-05 12:51:28 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>There have been many improvements in the documentation since the 0.8 release. The users&#39; feedback usually is quite positive. Nevertheless, improving documentation - and particularly the manual - is important at all times and often an ongoing effort. Especially for the next major versions 0.9 and 1.0 the documentation as a whole, also depending on the advancements of technical infrastructure, is to be reviewed. Targeting 0.9 now.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14871</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-24 20:48:32 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>mass renaming of 0.9 target for documentation issues to 1.0</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>16125</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2010-01-12 11:13:25 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>adjusted title, moved to 1.1 for review</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29046</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2012-04-03 17:30:08 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I think there have been substantial improvements to the manual since the initial report. Also switching to Sphinx in qooxdoo 1.2 improved things. As there is ongoing work on further improving the contents (thanks to Thomas et al.), taking care of qooxdoo&#39;s 4 usage scenarios, I&#39;ll close this old report.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>39593</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:27:48 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>