<bug>
          <bug_id>1300</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-08-29 09:58:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Performance: Cursor &quot;shape change&quot; lags</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-07-22 13:53:55 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.8.3</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</assigned_to>
          <cc>ged</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>4838</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2008-08-29 09:58:11 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Reported by Gaetan de Menten:

&quot;I just noticed an annoying oddity: when there is lots of stuff on a page (for example in the API viewer with inherited, and protected methods visible, the cursor &quot;shape change&quot; seem to lag.
This is noticeable for example, when going over the splitpane separator in the API viewer: when the page on the right is short, no problem. When there is a lot of data, the cursor change to its &quot;resize&quot; shape only after half a sec and stays that way for at least one full second after it left the separator. When the &quot;lag&quot; happens, I see my CPU usage go up to 100%. 

I suspect Qooxdoo is doing some useless computation behind the scene.&quot;</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5256</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-04 22:50:36 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Performance related.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9274</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-15 08:31:42 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>@Johnny, is this still an issue (after your recent work on the split pane)?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9280</commentid>
            <who name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-15 10:21:18 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This behavior is by design. We set the global cursor via a new CSS rule *{ 
cursor:foo;!important } which applies to ALL elements in the document. Applying 
this rule to all elements can be slow on some browsers.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9465</commentid>
            <who name="Gaëtan de Menten">ged</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-22 12:58:27 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>What kind of response is this? You basically say &quot;it&#39;s okay to lag because the way we do it lags&quot;.
Why use that method to change the cursor then?

What&#39;s wrong with the simple:
document.body.style.cursor = value;
that everybody use and was apparently used in 0.7?

And if you want to be more specific, why not be very really specific and target the single element that needs its style changed? And in that case, why not have that particular element style constant. For example, for a splitpane, the border need to always have its specific cursor style set, not only when you hover on it (ie, you don&#39;t need to add and remove the style on the fly, it can stay there).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9900</commentid>
            <who name="Gaëtan de Menten">ged</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-11 12:29:25 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Any follow-up on my questions?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9920</commentid>
            <who name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-12 11:16:40 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Gaëtan!

You said, that the method of setting the global cursor was different in 0.7, which is new for me.

I do not know why we changed this method, but there has to be a good reason for this, since the documentation of the global cursor property says &quot;Please note that in the current implementation this has no effect in IE.&quot;. We also have a bug report for this issue bug #1009.

You are welcome to comment on the global cursor bug.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26193</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-22 13:53:55 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>closing</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>