<bug>
          <bug_id>1359</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-09-02 15:23:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Meta Bug: Testing qooxdoo releases</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2010-11-24 14:16:49 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.8.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          <cc>fabian.jakobs</cc>
    
    <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>4993</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-02 15:23:30 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This bug groups issues and efforts concerning the testing of a qooxdoo release - of course before it is released :).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>4995</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-02 15:44:58 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Release testing can be split up into two major activities:
1. Browser testing
2. Build testing

1. Browser testing
Browser testing is concerned with the question if the various applications of the release run correctly in all supported browsers.
- To that end, the release will be installed under a commonly accessible web server (e.g. on the test pc, pcthron7, or similar).
- The SDK will be unpacked on the common web server machine, and the necessary targets will be built.
- The common web server will offer both source and build versions of the applications; if deemed helpful, it can also offer api and test versions of the applications.
- All supported browsers from all supported platforms will be run against this central web server (as explicated in a test plan, see #1347).

2. Build testing
Build testing is concerned with running the tool chain of the release on all supported platforms (Linux, MacOSX, Windows,...).
- Various team members download the release kit to one of the platforms, unpack it, and run necessary jobs against the kit (as explicated in a test plan, see #1347).
- The results of the build jobs are tested locally with an available browser.

The aggravation of this partitioning of test activities would be to build the application targets on *all* platforms, expose each through a web server, and then test from *all* browsers against *all* of these builds. But this seems not feasible currently.

The aim of all of these tests is to produce fail/pass test reports, not to start fixing immediately. After the test round has been completed, all found issues are discussed in a status meeting, and then e.g. a fixing round is started, followed by another test round.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5084</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-03 20:04:50 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>To 0.8.1 because already assigned. Otherwise please free from the assigner and make target milestone unspecified again.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5394</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-08 09:48:47 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Close Meta Bug as this is a not intended usage of bugzilla and makes issues 
when re-adressing bugs and priorize them</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>