<bug>
          <bug_id>1391</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-09-10 17:32:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Modern theme looks bad  when font got enlarged in browser (buttons, scrollbars ...)</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:19:38 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.theming</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.8.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Oleksiy Golovko">zindel</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</assigned_to>
          <cc>veigl</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5473</commentid>
            <who name="Oleksiy Golovko">zindel</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-10 17:32:38 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>To reproduce:
  - open any app containing buttons and scrollbars in Firefox;
  - press Ctrl-+ (probably several times). 
See, buttons/scrollbars look ugly.

Quote from Alexander Back&#39;s email (describing the nature of the bug):
Buttons, scrollbars and other widgets are 
using the &quot;grid&quot; decorator for styling. This decorator takes a couple of 
images to get rounded borders. It seems the decorator fails to scale 
with the font size changes.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5512</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-12 12:24:15 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>To 0.8.1</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5522</commentid>
            <who name="Stephan Veigl">veigl</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-12 20:04:33 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Tables and trees are also effected by this issue (see qooxdoo demo browser).

Tables:
The cell height does not change with font height. The text is not abbreviated if cell width get’s to small. (see table -&gt; Table_Cell_Editor demo )

Trees:
The cell height does not change with font height. In the treevirtual -&gt; TreeVirtual Demo text is not  abbreviated at all. In the demo browser tree on the left side text is abbreviated as soon as the standard font width is exceeded, even if there would be enough space left. IMHO best solution would be to abbreviated if the width of the whole tree column is reached. Or, even better, if there would be a treevirtual proberty enable/disable abbreviated.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5523</commentid>
            <who name="Tobias Oetiker">tobi</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-12 21:02:29 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The Table title row does not seem to care for font size at all ... most other things seem to try to some extend ... </thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5533</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-15 15:36:17 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The reported issues are issues of the browsers. Hitting &quot;Ctrl-+&quot; and &quot;Ctrl--&quot; are internal browser functionalities which increase/decrease the result of the rendering process. 

Thus it cannot be fixed in qooxdoo it has to be handled correctly by the browsers.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5534</commentid>
            <who name="Oleksiy Golovko">zindel</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-15 15:58:34 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hm... I understand this concept, but are you really sure about it? 
For example, i open http://qooxdoo.org/demo in the same browser (FF 3), do ctrl++/- and see rounded corners of &quot;Demo Browser&quot;, &quot;Feed Reader&quot; look correctly... 

</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5535</commentid>
            <who name="Oleksiy Golovko">zindel</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-15 16:04:03 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Even more: I open http://demo.qooxdoo.org/current/demobrowser/#widget-TabView.html, do ctrl++, then &lt;F5&gt;. The page re-renders, correct? But the result still looks incorrect.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5536</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-15 16:33:36 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>To comment #3:
If I open the &quot;Feed Reader&quot; the scrollbars still look incorrect after doing the text-zoom with Ctrl-+.

To comment #4:
Firefox does apply the text-zooming at the rendered result. If you do the text-zoom with Ctrl-+ and reload the page is re-rendered and AFTER being fully rendered the text-zoom is applied. Leaving the user with an incorrect result.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5537</commentid>
            <who name="Oleksiy Golovko">zindel</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-15 16:48:52 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Sorry, I didn&#39;t realized the difference between full zoom and text-only zoom. I treated all zoom as text-only.

Here is the sort of recipe how I managed to make it work in FF3. Perhaps it might be useful for other people (there are elder people/scientists among our application users, so they can&#39;t stand with default qooxdoo font which is too small for them).

Open FF3, url: http://demo.qooxdoo.org/current/demobrowser/#widget-TabView.html
Go to View -&gt; Zoom -&gt; Zoom Text Only (check it)
Press Ctrl++ several times. Then Press F5 and see application looks great and with bigger font!

Alexander, thank you for pointing to different zoom methods!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36566</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:19:38 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>