<bug>
          <bug_id>1395</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-09-12 02:59:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Credit for Icons?</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2008-09-17 15:26:51 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>website</product>
          <component>other</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Vadim Peretokin">vperetokin</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5502</commentid>
            <who name="Vadim Peretokin">vperetokin</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-12 02:59:28 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi,

Where can I find the credits for the Gnome (and Tango) icons that are being used in the site demos? 

(their license says the following:

You may copy and distribute verbatim copies of the Program&#39;s
source code as you receive it, in any medium, provided that you
conspicuously and appropriately publish on each copy an appropriate
copyright notice and disclaimer of warranty; keep intact all the
notices that refer to this License and to the absence of any warranty;
and give any other recipients of the Program a copy of this License
along with the Program.)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5509</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-12 11:19:50 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The information is available in the SVN:

http://qooxdoo.svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/qooxdoo/trunk/qooxdoo/framework/source/resource/qx/icon/

and is also packaged into the SDK you can download at sourceforge.

This is more a question than a bug. Closing.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5521</commentid>
            <who name="Vadim Peretokin">vperetokin</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-12 15:47:05 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I see.

But the online instance is still lacking that.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5561</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-17 15:26:27 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5562</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-17 15:26:51 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Vadim,

the license terms you cite do not belong to the gTango icon set used. Please see the AUTHORS and COPYING/LICENSE files in qooxdoo that are verbatim copies of the original files in the downloadable package (http://www.gnome-look.org/content/show.php/gTango?content=73176).

Despite the slightly different license terms, credits for the icon set should be given sufficiently. As with other parts of the framework all external work is covered explicitly by corresponding license terms (i.e. deviations from qooxdoo&#39;s LGPL/EPL dual license). Also consult the top-level LICENSE file. 

As the icon set&#39;s license suggests, it may not be required/&quot;reasonably practicable&quot; to also include such credits/pointers for each online demo. So IMHO there isn&#39;t a issue here for merely displaying such online demos. If you still think there is, you may want to contact me directly.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>