<bug>
          <bug_id>1406</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-09-18 01:31:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Remote model doesn`t request new data</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2008-09-22 15:49:58 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.table</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>INVALID</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Guilherme Krycek">gradinf</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5570</commentid>
            <who name="Guilherme Krycek">gradinf</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-18 01:31:43 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>On a remote model with more than 10000 lines, if I scroll down to the end of the table, nothing happens - no requests are made and not even the lines are draw.

If I keep scrooling up and down, sometimes the schoolbar dissapear.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5597</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-22 05:18:30 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This problem appears to be fixed with my latest commits.  Using the new Remote Table Model test in qooxdoo-contrib&#39;s RpcExample, and changing the return value to the getRowCount method in RpcPhp&#39;s qooxdoo.tableModelTest class from 121 to 12100, the table appears to update properly at any scroll point I&#39;ve tried.

Please confirm that this bug is fixed.

Thanks,

Derrell
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5600</commentid>
            <who name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-22 11:25:56 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Derrell, your commits (16411 in qooxdoo, 17426 in contrib) are only related to the form of the data in the remote table model. I would be concerned that there is another issue here. However, your tests probably rule out a problem with qooxdoo code, and more to do with Guilherme&#39;s code.

Hugh</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5609</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-22 15:45:57 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The reported bug was very similar to what I saw when the data was not accessible due to accessing the data model via the ID values rather than via the column index.  I agree, though, that this looks like a bug outside of qooxdoo.

I&#39;ll close this bug for now.  Guilherme, please re-open if you still believe there is a bug in qooxdoo.

Derrell
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5611</commentid>
            <who name="Guilherme Krycek">gradinf</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-22 15:49:58 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&#39;ve found the problem.

I&#39;m using json_encode to encode the respose of the request (PHP). And it converts integers into strings before sending the data. So when it was calling _onRowCountLoaded actually it was using a string and not a integer to set the number os rows:

this._onRowCountLoaded(parseInt(response.count));

That solved the problem.

Sorry for that.

And Derrel, It was working before your changes. But it keeps working after them.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>