<bug>
          <bug_id>1418</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-09-22 14:36:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>inWindow parameter changed with Selenium 1.0</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2009-02-04 14:34:12 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>contrib</product>
          <component>Simulator</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          <votes>1</votes>
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5603</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-22 14:36:06 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>With Selenium 1.0, apparently the inWindow parameter to find methods has changed. It is not a JS Window object anymore, but a XPCNativeWrapper object.
Consequently, accessing the Window object has to change, e.g. from
inWindow.qx  to
inWindow.wrappedJSObject.qx</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5604</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-22 14:37:56 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>From Pradeep on the mailing list:

   I was using the qx locator in Selenium IDE 0.8.7 for identifying the
Qooxdoo elements. I was using Firefox 2.0 then. It was working fine.

   But, when I installed Firefox 3.0, I need to update the Selenium IDE as
well to 1.0b2. But now, when I use the qx locator, it is not working. It is
throwing the following error
     [error] locator not found: qx=Login, error = Error: Element qx=Login
not found 

   I tried debugging it and found that the Window object getting passed in
the locateElementByQx method has changed. Now, it is coming as a URL and
when it tries to do a inWindow.qx, it fails. Earlier, I used to get the
actual window object which has qx residing in it.

   Am I doing something wrong with the new Selenium IDE. I am using the new
user extension only.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5605</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-22 14:38:49 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>A follow-up from Pradeep on the ml:

    I found the issue for the problem. One correction is that, the window
object was not a URL but a window object wrapped by XPCNativeWrapper. The
XPCNativeWrapper is for security purposes which avoids exposing the
javascript objects of the actual object (hides them). With the latest
Selenium IDE, this is what is happening. Prior to this, it was the actual
window object in which we can access the qx object directly by using
inWindow.qx. 

    To overcome this issue, I  am using the wrappedJSObject  in
XPCNativeWrapper window object. I am accessing the qx object by using
inWindow.wrappedJSObject.qx which works. I updated the user extension by
replacing inWindow.qx to inWindow.wrappedJSObject.qx.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>7604</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-04 14:34:12 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed in Simulator trunk (revision 18026).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>