<bug>
          <bug_id>142</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2006-09-02 04:19:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>menu &#39;execute&#39; event fires on mousedown</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:24:37 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>0.6-rc1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>n/a</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>minor</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.6</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Tomek Loboda">the.snake</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>316</commentid>
            <who name="Tomek Loboda">the.snake</who>
            <bug_when>2006-09-02 04:19:57 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>It&#39;s more of a usability issue than a code bug. Unlike all the system I&#39;ve used, in qooxdoo the menu item is executed on mousedown and not mouseup event. One of the usability heuristics, Consistency and standards, states that the bahavior of an application should be as close to user&#39;s environment as possible to avoid confusion. Maybe it would be beneficial to change it to mouseup which would give the user another while to decide before releasing the mouse button.

Appologies if it is not the case I described above and my thinking is driven by the lack of understanding of the library.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>321</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2006-09-04 09:29:28 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The problem is currently another and maybe that&#39;s why we use mousedown here, instead of mouseup. We generally hide all menus, popup, tooltips on a mousedown event. This occours globally from the EventHandler. Generally this is the same behavior known from other applications/toolkits. The only case where we don&#39;t want to do this with a menu, is when a menubutton inside the menu itself was clicked (mousedown). The problem is that we must also respect sub-menus here (the parents depend on this button, too).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>322</commentid>
            <who name="Tomek Loboda">the.snake</who>
            <bug_when>2006-09-04 09:57:22 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)

I checked in Windows and OpenBSD and menus are being hidden on mouseup (tooltips on mousedown). I don&#39;t know how would other similar toolkits work, but YouOS, developed using dojo, seems to be using mouseup. Since QX is designed with desktop-like rich applications in mind, I thought it would be beneficial to provide users with the same experienes. To let them forget that they are switching to the browser.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>324</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2006-09-04 11:18:32 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&#39;ve changed the behavior in SVN. Please test it and give feedback. Thanks.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>385</commentid>
            <who name="Tomek Loboda">the.snake</who>
            <bug_when>2006-09-04 22:57:29 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Just checked -- IMHO it&#39;s much better. Thanks!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>38452</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:24:37 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>