<bug>
          <bug_id>1461</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-10-08 16:47:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>High level overview of Config.json + Manifest.json for docs</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:21:57 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>website</product>
          <component>documentation</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P5</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.0</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Chris Banford">dev</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5794</commentid>
            <who name="Chris Banford">dev</who>
            <bug_when>2008-10-08 16:47:08 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Thomas,

Really an excellent email this one -- I&#39;m sure that this belongs in the wiki docs somewhere where new users would read it.

I&#39;ve figured these things out, but I&#39;m sure it would have been a very informative read for me at some point not long ago, and I&#39;m sure there will be future qooxdoo converts who will benefit from it...

I&#39;ve read the docs on the wiki many times and can follow the gist of them, but where it get tough it trying to make first steps in modifying/changing the contents of the config.json file. A few really simple examples of how to start with a project skeleton&#39;s config.json/manifest files and then make small and easy to follow changes, would be a huge help. At the moment I read and think I&#39;ve got some insight on how some specific config bit works, but when I try it out I either get cryptic errors in the generatory.py console or it just doesn&#39;t do anything.

For example: a short and simple wiki page of how to extend an existing job (for a newly created Skeleton proj) that then makes several simple and easy to follow changes to say &#39;build&#39; or &#39;source&#39;. Once new users can get something working, it quickly becomes easy to keep trying/changing things and soon one has the required insights as to what magic is happening behind the curtain :-) .

Keep up the great work!

Cheers,
-Chris



&gt;&gt; The Tool-chain (config.json, jobs, etc) is still over my head. I&#39;m 
&gt;&gt; hoping that there are a few more wiki docs/how-to&#39;s in store, from 
&gt;&gt; those who feel comfortable with this stuff.
&gt;&gt;     
&gt;
&gt; I mentioned in another post there are just three wiki documents 
&gt; concerned with the 0.8 generator configuration. These are:
&gt;
&gt; - a general overview page 
&gt; (http://qooxdoo.org/documentation/0.8/generator_config)
&gt; - a reference page for the config keys 
&gt; (http://qooxdoo.org/documentation/0.8/generator_config_ref)
&gt; - a page with assorted paragraphs on various config topics that deserve 
&gt; a bit more background 
&gt; (http://qooxdoo.org/documentation/0.8/generator_config_articles)
&gt;
&gt; There is also a more general document on the generator, but this is more 
&gt; like your typical product feature-list flyer 
&gt; (http://qooxdoo.org/documentation/0.8/generator). So it&#39;s more about 
&gt; impressing than informing you :).
&gt;
&gt; Of the basic structure, every application/library must contain a 
&gt; config.json and a Manifest.json file in its top directory. From this 
&gt; directory, a &#39;source/class&#39; subdirectory is expected, which contains a 
&gt; name space subdirectory and some class files therein. All other 
&gt; subdirectories in the top directory are then created during generator 
&gt; runs (&#39;build&#39;, &#39;api&#39;, &#39;test&#39;, ...).
&gt;
&gt; The most important of these sudirectories is of course &#39;source&#39; since it 
&gt; contains your source code. Aside from the &#39;&lt;name space&gt;&#39; subdirectory it 
&gt; has to have a &#39;resource&#39; subdir (for icons, style files, flash files, 
&gt; etc.) and a &#39;translation&#39; subdir (for string translation files). All 
&gt; these are mandatory, but might be empty. During a &#39;generate.py source&#39; a 
&gt; source/script directory is created which contains the generator output 
&gt; (basically a Javascript file that references all necessary class files, 
&gt; icons, etc.). This one has to be referenced from the application&#39;s 
&gt; index.html (usually in source/index.html).
&gt;
&gt; The &#39;build&#39; dir (created with &#39;generate.py build&#39;) has a very similar 
&gt; structure as the &#39;source&#39; dir, with &#39;script&#39;, &#39;translation&#39; and 
&gt; &#39;resource&#39; subdirs. The main difference is that everything that is 
&gt; necessary for your application to run is copied under this common root, 
&gt; and that the generator output script in &#39;build/script&#39; contains the 
&gt; actual class definitions, not just references to their source files. The 
&gt; build dir is therefore self-contained, and doesn&#39;t have references that 
&gt; point outside it.
&gt;
&gt; Create some vanilla skeleton apps (with &#39;tool/bin/create-application.py 
&gt; -t [gui|migration] ...&#39;) and look at their initial file structure, to 
&gt; get a feel for it. Tailor the source/class/&lt;namespace&gt;/Application.js as 
&gt; the main application entry class, add further classes to your needs, and 
&gt; let the tool chain take care of the rest. You will have to run 
&gt; &#39;generate.py source&#39; initially, and then once in a while, and you can 
&gt; just try out your app opening source/index.html directly in your 
&gt; browser, reloading it to see changes to the code. If you are comfortable 
&gt; with that, run a &#39;generate.py build&#39; and open build/index.html in your 
&gt; browser. If that is fine, copy the whole &#39;build&#39; tree to your web server.
&gt;
&gt; HTH,
&gt; Thomas
&gt;
&gt;
&gt;</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8445</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-09 16:38:51 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Thomas, this one apparently slipped bug triage. Please see if documentation can be improved, also taking into account your useful email answer as suggested.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>11663</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-08-27 17:20:21 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>as enhancement</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12092</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-09 15:06:50 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>to 0.9</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13092</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-12 13:02:02 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>down prio for docu</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14884</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-24 20:48:38 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>mass renaming of 0.9 target for documentation issues to 1.0</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>15682</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2009-12-11 10:48:52 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>to me for 1.0</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>15867</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2009-12-14 16:26:14 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Updated http://qooxdoo.org/documentation/1.0/application_structure according to 
bug summary.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37490</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:21:57 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>