<bug>
          <bug_id>1480</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-10-16 15:03:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Zooming in or out distorts text on widgets in IE7</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:23:18 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>0.7.3</version>
          <rep_platform>IE</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://demo.qooxdoo.org/0.7.3/demobrowser/#example~Window_1.html</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.8.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Rüdiger Herrmann">rherrmann</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</assigned_to>
          <cc>stefan.hansel</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Internet Explorer</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5867</commentid>
            <who name="Rüdiger Herrmann">rherrmann</who>
            <bug_when>2008-10-16 15:03:55 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Whenever you change the zoom factor in IE7 to any other value than the default (1:1), you get strange behaviour of Widgets with Texts while dragging windows around. 
The Text on buttons for example stays fixed on a vertical axis, even if the surrounding window is dragged.

To reproduce, change the zoom factor, open the Demo Browser, select the &#39;Window 1&#39; page and drag one of the windows.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5886</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2008-10-20 14:26:47 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>we need to check, whether we have the same issue in 0.8 as well.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5915</commentid>
            <who name="Rüdiger Herrmann">rherrmann</who>
            <bug_when>2008-10-21 10:53:11 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I Noticed that the target milestone was set to 0.8.1. Does that mean that this issue won&#39;t be fixed in the 0.7.x stream?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6093</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2008-11-03 13:58:58 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>no it just means that we want to check whether we have the same problem in 0.8 as well.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6224</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2008-11-11 00:10:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Zooming in IE7 is inherently broken, i.e. badly designed and implemented. :-( Other frameworks show similar effects, it&#39;s not qooxdoo specific (neither 0.7 or 0.8):
* Images get a black background (PNG alpha transparency?)
* Grid decorators deteriorate (maybe rounding errors)
* Offsets are wrong, e.g. for drag start
* Labels stay fixed horizontally while dragging internal windows

I doubt we can account for the badly-broken pagezoom feature of IE7, while other browsers like FF or Opera do a substantially better job (still showing some minor artifacts). 

From the IEBlog at http://blogs.msdn.com/ie/archive/2006/02/07/526805.aspx :
&quot;The way we zoom in IE7 is a little different than other products [!!!], so let me briefly explain how it works and our design goals. The primary goal of the page zoom feature is to maintain the intended design of the webpage (the user shouldn’t notice any change in the layout of the webpage) while improving the readability of the page. This means we do not re-layout the page after we zoom.&quot;

Apparently MS changed the pagezoom behavior for IE8, http://blogs.msdn.com/ie/archive/2008/03/25/internet-explorer-8-and-adaptive-zoom.aspx .
&quot;Internet Explorer 8 Adaptive Zoom is founded on the concept of scaling elements pre-layout. This is significantly different from Internet Explorer 7 Zoom behavior, which was analogous to “magnifying” the webpage – elements were scaled post layout and then re-drawn on screen.&quot;

Therefore, we won&#39;t (be able to) fix the IE7 issues (see also bug 1262).
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37967</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:23:18 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>