<bug>
          <bug_id>1539</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-11-06 09:28:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>There is no full control over bold, italic, etc.</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-02-28 10:46:55 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>contrib</product>
          <component>HtmlArea</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Petr Kobalíček">kobalicek.petr</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6138</commentid>
            <who name="Petr Kobalíček">kobalicek.petr</who>
            <bug_when>2008-11-06 09:28:44 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>There is no full control over bold, italic, etc. I can toggle them, but I can&#39;t set them for example to true or false that&#39;s bad.

I&#39;m reporting this, because bol, italic, underline and strike styles are usually implemented as checkboxes, so it&#39;s very good to send correct value to HtmlArea, because when I massive tested it, it&#39;s sometimes inversed (Bold is false, but typing is bold, etc...).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6141</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2008-11-06 14:28:28 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>to me</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6142</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2008-11-06 14:38:16 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>HtmlArea does not offer a toolbar, only the demo application provides one. 

But there is support for updating the state of a toolbar implementation by using the &quot;cursorContext&quot; event. This event is fired with any positioning (through left|right|up|down and pageUp|pageDown|Pos1|End keys) and with every mouse click. So you can gather at every position change the formatting at the current position and update your toolbar accordingly. 

This event offers a map with the following keys:
bold, italic, underline, strikethrough, fontSize, fontFamily,  insertUnorderedList, insertOrderedList, justifyLeft,justifyCenter, justifyRight and justifyFull

Either is has the values 1|0 or in case for fontSize and fontFamily the current value.

-&gt; INVALID</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6150</commentid>
            <who name="Petr Kobalíček">kobalicek.petr</who>
            <bug_when>2008-11-06 17:06:48 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Alex,

I&#39;m using this event, but values are sometimes not correct, so when I toggle bold from TRUE to FALSE, it&#39;s clear to send HtmlArea that bold is now false and not only to toggle bold.

I think that my idea is more bug free to the future</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6401</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2008-11-21 14:57:42 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Petr, you&#39;re right. 
As I re-thought this issue I realized that the existing methods (setBold, setItalic, etc.) are misleading and you need to have better control over the formatting of the content. 
&quot;setBold&quot; e.g. should set the selected content bold and not toggle it as it is now the case. There has to be a overhaul of the API in this case.

-&gt; REOPEN</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>7728</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-12 16:33:27 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Major refactoring needed -&gt; moving out of 0.3 release scope</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13265</commentid>
            <who name="Petr Kobalíček">kobalicek.petr</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-19 00:41:03 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Alex,

how much work needs to solve this issue? I looked at HtmlArea source, but I don&#39;t know if I can do it. Can be this bug been fixed in near future?

Thanks, Petr

</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13322</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-19 17:37:40 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #6)
&gt; how much work needs to solve this issue? I looked at HtmlArea source, but I
&gt; don&#39;t know if I can do it. Can be this bug been fixed in near future?
I don&#39;t know. This is a pretty big change to make.
This bug can be fixed in the future,  but I don&#39;t know in which time frame, sorry.

If you want to take it over and I can provide you some knowledge, let me know.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>15473</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2009-12-09 17:10:10 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move HtmlArea with no milestone to framework</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>17111</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2010-03-04 11:19:48 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>back to &#39;NEW&#39;</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35208</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2014-02-25 09:21:12 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Discontinued support for htmlarea in the framework, set all open issues to WONTFIX. Still available as a contribution acc. to bug #7918 .</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>