<bug>
          <bug_id>1591</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-11-14 17:06:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Library (e.g. qooxdoo-contrib) appearance theme assistance by generator</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 09:17:40 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>alexander.steitz</cc>
    
    <cc>matthew+qooxdoo</cc>
    
    <cc>mustafa.sak</cc>
    
    <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6299</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2008-11-14 17:06:25 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>See mailing list discussion &quot;[qooxdoo-devel] Help with contrib project and themes&quot; on 14 Nov 2008.

A library, for example, a qooxdoo-contrib project, may make use of appearances defined in its own local appearance theme.  Per the above discussion, the recommendation is for the library&#39;s theme to define only what it, itself needs (i.e. not to include any standard themes), and it is up to the application writer to include any library&#39;s themes via the application&#39;s own theme.

It seems to me that although this works, it&#39;s more work for the application writer than should be required.  This may, in many cases, even require that an application writer create an own theme for the sole purpose of including a library&#39;s theme (when the application itself doesn&#39;t otherwise require its own theme).  

I believe that an application writer should only need to point his config.json file to each required library&#39;s Manifest file, and all else should occur automagically if not otherwise overridden by the application writer.

When the generator sees a library being included, I propose that it automatically include that library&#39;s appearance theme if one is specified for the library [in the library&#39;s Manifest file?  in its config.json file?].)  For those rare cases that an application writer wants to redefine the theme used by the library, a new config.json tag, e.g. &quot;include-theme&quot; which would default to true, could state explicitly that a library&#39;s theme is not to be included.  For example:

  &quot;jobs&quot; :
  {
    &quot;include-contrib&quot; :
    {
      &quot;library&quot;: 
      [
        {
          &quot;manifest&quot; : &quot;../../../qooxdoo.git/qooxdoo-contrib/trunk/qooxdoo-contrib/TimeChooser/trunk/Manifest.json&quot;,
          &quot;include-theme&quot; : false
        }
      ]
    },
  ...</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10658</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-06-29 16:23:29 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Also see bug #2345 (contributio skeleton)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>11187</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-08-04 14:02:51 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&#39;ll take that into account when reworking the contrib infrastructure.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>11188</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-08-04 14:19:06 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>16055</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2010-01-07 12:43:23 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Marked as enhancement and assigned to Alex as it fits into similar tasks for further improving the contrib infrastructure.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19779</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-11 15:44:52 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Daniel, please review and check how it fits in the current infrastructure.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>