<bug>
          <bug_id>1596</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-11-18 12:44:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Implement a &quot;logical&quot; getParent() method in widgets</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:47:49 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>fabian.jakobs</cc>
    
    <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6327</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2008-11-18 12:44:04 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Devise a &quot;getParent()&quot; method that has to be implemented individually for existing widgets that will return the *logical* parent of a component widget.

The problem with the current &quot;getLayoutParent()&quot; is that it mixes logical and implementation-specific parent-child relations. For some widgets you can get to the &quot;logical&quot; parent eventually by recursing, e.g. for a widget nested into a Window widget getLayoutParent() takes you to something like the WindowPane first, and then to the Window widget itself. But this is not true for e.g. the SplitButton. If you start from a Label widget in the corresponding menu, getLayoutParent() takes you to the Menu widget, and then to Application, for implementation reasons. SplitButton should therefor implement a logical getParent() method that links the Label to the Menu, and the Menu to e.g. the SplitButton&#39;s triangle button, and this to the SplitButton widget itself. This would reflect the correct logical structure.

The Tree widget has already implemented that (a specific &quot;getParent()&quot;), and for good reason. Not having this facility makes it hard to traverse the logical structure of widgets and whole applications.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36039</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:47:49 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>