<bug>
          <bug_id>1662</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-12-03 14:12:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Default jobs: &#39;fix&#39;: add removal of utf-8 BOM from source files</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:25:34 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>0.8</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6617</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-03 14:12:08 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Currently, Chrome has issues with BOM in utf-8 source files (see bug#1389). The 
default job &#39;fix&#39; could remove the BOM from source files, as a further feature.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8090</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-26 18:32:38 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>In bug#1389 (which holds this issue for 0.7.x) I maintain the view that our 
build process *doesn&#39;t* insert BOM into output files. This seems not to be true 
for build versions. In some build scripts spurious &lt;feff&gt; BOMs are appearing 
throughout the code, like in this generated code snippet:

  qx.event.Pool.getInstance().poolObject(event);
  return !preventDefault;
  }}});
﻿  &lt;feff&gt;;
  qx.Bootstrap.define(&quot;qx.lang.Object&quot;,{statics:{empty:function(map){for(var 
key in map){if(map

They always seem to be between semi-colons.

Although obviously not disturbing in most contexts, this is non-sensical: BOM 
should be the first character in the file, if at all, and there is no need for 
multiple BOMs.

So, some part of generating the build version inserts spurious BOMs. My first 
guess was that this was in place where pruned code was in the AST, but that 
doesn&#39;t seem to hold.

NB: find ~/workspace/qooxdoo.trunk/framework/source/class/qx -name &quot;*.js&quot; \( 
-exec sed -n -e &#39;/\xef\xbb\xbf/q1&#39; {} \; -o -print \)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8091</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-26 19:01:53 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I have a fix *iff* the problem is due to parsing a source file that contains a 
BOM.

If a source file contains a BOM the BOM is read in straight away (no BOM 
stripping by the codecs module!). The parser parses this as an identifier which 
becomes then part of the AST. Through AST shuffling this might get swapped to 
the end of the class code on output generation.

The fix treats the BOM as white space in the tokenizer. (BOM is not white space 
in Unicode, but of category &#39;other, format&#39;).

Since I currently don&#39;t have a test case so I could reproduce the problem and 
then test that the fix solves it, this fix is sort of arbitrary but seems to 
make sense anyway. Let&#39;s see if the problem re-appears!

With r18174.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8101</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-27 11:17:25 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Other shell command to find BOM in .js files:

find ~/workspace/qooxdoo.trunk/framework/source/class/qx -name &quot;*.js&quot; \( -exec 
perl -ne &#39;/\xef\xbb\xbf/ and exit(1);&#39; {} \; -o -print \)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9512</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-23 10:50:00 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>to Thomas</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10065</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-20 16:50:25 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I observed this behaviour on Windows:

* Reading a file with a BOM at its beginning, the BOM is stipped by the reading 
(codecs) module, so the generator code doesn&#39;t see it. (This contradicts my 
earlier assumption that the reading module doesn&#39;t touch the BOM; but in the 
cases I looked at back then the BOM sequence was *within* the file, not at the 
beginning!).

* Therefore, it cannot strip it with &#39;fix&#39;!

* At least on Windows the BOM is again prepended when the buffer is written to 
a file, *without* explictly doing so. (This contradicts my assumption that you 
have to explicitly write the BOM, in order to have it in the file). Maybe this 
is a platform-specific behaviour, since I read that particularly Microsoft used 
the BOM in Utf-8 to signify this encoding.

So at least on Windows, a leading BOM is silently stripped on reads, and 
silently prepended on writes, so there is no immediate way for the &#39;fix&#39; job to 
remove it. It could re-read the file as binary, though, and then edit it. But 
maybe this should be done platform-dependent anyway (The described behaviour 
might be perfect for Windows, where the BOM should be left in).

This should be re-tested on other platforms.

This is all in the context of Utf-8 encoding.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>17670</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2010-04-09 11:38:29 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>&#39;fix&#39; job now also removes a leading BOM (EF BB BF) from files, if it finds one.

With r21865</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>38798</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:25:34 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>