<bug>
          <bug_id>1664</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-12-03 19:47:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Widgets are broken in Firefox 3.1 (and above) builds with JIT enabled</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:21:54 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop</component>
          <version>0.7</version>
          <rep_platform>Firefox 3.5</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>INVALID</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://demo.qooxdoo.org/0.7.3/showcase/index.html#Tooltip</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>major</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.7.5</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>rherrmann</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Firefox</cf_browser>
          <cf_browser_version>3.5</cf_browser_version>

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6631</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-03 19:47:21 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I have choosen to report this as an potential qooxdoo issue, although it only reproduces using Firefox&#39;s TraceMonkey [1]. But I&#39;d prefer this to be marked as &quot;invalid&quot; whenever this is properly isolated than to not report it and let (0.7.x) qooxdoo-based applications be haunted by this in a near future. :-)
Please help in reducing this issue in order to decide on whether is this a qooxdoo or a Firefox issue! ;-)

Steps to reproduce:
1. Open the report&#39;s URL using a recent Firefox version which has JIT enabled (this can checked using the &quot;about:config&quot; special page: the property is &quot;javascript.options.jit.content&quot; should be &quot;true&quot;);
2. Place the pointer over the buttons;
3. Disable &quot;JIT&quot; for content (set &quot;javascript.options.jit.content&quot; property to &quot;false&quot;);
4. Close and reopen Firefox;
5. Place the pointer over the buttons;

Expected result:
Tooltips are shown in both steps 2 and 5.

Actual result:
Tooltips are always shown in step 5. In step 2, they are sometimes displayed as a small rectangle without content.

Platform:
Firefox 3.1

Version details:
First seen in - Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; en-US; rv:1.9.1b1pre) Gecko/20081005 Minefield/3.1b1pre
Recently seen in - Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; en-US; rv:1.9.1b3pre) Gecko/20081203 Shiretoko/3.1b3pre

Additional information:
This symptoms were only found using the legacy branch. The trunk behaves as expected. Target milestone was set to 0.7.4 to call for attention - please change it whenever this is felt like acceptable for a future release.
Personally, I&#39;d label this as medium priority given that Firefox 3.1 is to be out in the wild in a near future - currently in beta 2 [2]).
I&#39;m not sure if this is easily fixable by analyzing the changes between the legacy and the trunk branches and (possible) porting some code.

[1] https://wiki.mozilla.org/JavaScript:TraceMonkey
[2] https://developer.mozilla.org/devnews/index.php/2008/12/02/aboutmozilla-add-on-con-tree-logistics-updating-add-ons-mozilla-manifesto-bugzilla-firefox-thunderbird-and-more/#addons</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6648</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-04 11:39:51 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks Helder, excellent bug report (as always).

Have you noticed other issues with this early version of FF 3.1? Hard to tell if those issues are qooxdoo, not browser related, a 2nd beta of FF 3.1 isn&#39;t even out yet (but expected soon). 

I added a Firefox 3.1 to account for issues potentially related to tracemonkey. If you&#39;ve got some more, please do report them. Closing them later during FF progress as invalid would just be fine. But I wouldn&#39;t advise to currently spend too much time (only a &quot;reasonable amount&quot;) with this early FF 3.1.

@Daniel, please have a look.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6665</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-04 12:14:15 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; Thanks Helder, excellent bug report (as always).

Thanks. :-) I guess I only forgot to mention in the &quot;Actual result:&quot; that, sometimes, tooltips with contain images display the image (alone, without the tooltip text), which makes me believe this may mostly have to do with some weird text handling and/or timer interaction.

 
&gt; Have you noticed other issues with this early version of FF 3.1? Hard to tell
&gt; if those issues are qooxdoo, not browser related, a 2nd beta of FF 3.1 isn&#39;t
&gt; even out yet (but expected soon). 

I did in older nightly builds, reason why I&#39;ve took so long to report it (first seen in October, as per comment 0): I was waiting to see how TraceMonkey evolved. Few know issues/crashes were solved with more TraceMonkey merges [1], this is is the only remaining one I&#39;m aware of.


&gt; I added a Firefox 3.1 to account for issues potentially related to tracemonkey.

Cool, it makes sense given the relevant differences (not limited to TraceMonkey). :-) Just updated the report&#39;s properties.


&gt; If you&#39;ve got some more, please do report them. Closing them later during FF
&gt; progress as invalid would just be fine. But I wouldn&#39;t advise to currently
&gt; spend too much time (only a &quot;reasonable amount&quot;) with this early FF 3.1.

Yeah, I&#39;ll be (as) aware as time permits. ;-)


[1] http://www.squarefree.com/burningedge/</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6708</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-04 17:14:10 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Bug is out-of-scope for 0.7.4. It makes sense to take another look once FF 3.1 is more stable (e.g. beta2 or beta3).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6947</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-16 11:27:43 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Issue confirmed in FF 3.1b2</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6948</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-16 11:43:38 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #4)
&gt; Issue confirmed in FF 3.1b2

Few more thoughts:
 * Confirmed using 3.2a1 [1] also:
   * Could &quot;Firefox 3.2&quot; be added to the &quot;Hardware&quot; list?
   * Could &quot;Hardware&quot; be changed to &quot;Platform&quot; or something more appropriate? ;-)
 * Qooxdoo version set to 0.7:
   * This issue was verified ranging from 0.7 [2] to 0.7.4 [3];
 * Target version set to 0.7.5 to call for attention.

[1] http://www.mozilla.org/developer/#builds
[2] http://demo.qooxdoo.org/0.7/showcase/index.html#Tooltip
[3] http://demo.qooxdoo.org/0.7.4/showcase/index.html#Tooltip</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8175</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-02 17:58:10 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Apparently also internal windows (which subclass from qx.ui.popup.Popup from which tooltips do also) and buttons seem to be affected, which makes me believe the root issue is in qx.ui.basic.Atom and/or around it.

To reproduce issue with internal windows:
1. Open http://demo.qooxdoo.org/0.7.4/showcase/index.html#Themes
2. Press the &quot;Open theming window&quot; button

An internal window containing several buttons for the available themes was expected, while a small box (6px by 6px is displayed, apparently the minimum) is displayed instead.

To reproduce issue with buttons:
1. Open http://demo.qooxdoo.org/0.7.4/showcase/index.html#Form
2. Open the &quot;Themes&quot; section

The &quot;Open theming window&quot; button was expected, but again a small box is displayed instead.

Firefox nightly (3.2 alpha) version details:
Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; en-US; rv:1.9.2a1pre) Gecko/20090302 Minefield/3.2a1pre

It would be good if someone could confirm this using the latest available 3.1 beta.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8220</commentid>
            <who name="Rüdiger Herrmann">rherrmann</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-03 15:13:53 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The steps outlined in comment #6 are also reproducible with 3.1 beta 2 (factory settings)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8334</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-05 18:24:10 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Changing report&#39;s title to reflect that this issue applies to much more that just tooltips.

Increasing severity also, as it causes parts of the layout not to be displayed, therefore potentially causing incoherent behavior, for example:
 * One opens a modal window but the window isn&#39;t shown -- user must reload the application (possibly losing session data), as the blocker element doesn&#39;t allow any other interaction... :-(
 * Parts of the application may not display as expected, inducing the user into wrong actions or giving a feeling of a broken application.

I&#39;ve noticed, by inspecting (with DOM inspector [1]) that there actually missing &quot;div&quot; elements for the missing portions of the application so I&#39;m not still sure how is this caused. Creating a reduced test case would be great so that this could be better looked at by the Mozilla folks. Help anyone?

Still confirmed that this only occurs with TraceMonkey enabled in a more recent nightly build [1]. Disabling JIT makes this (very) weird behavior to go away.

[1] https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/1806
[2] Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; en-US; rv:1.9.2a1pre) Gecko/20090305 Minefield/3.2a1pre
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8335</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-05 19:00:13 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #8)
&gt; Changing report&#39;s title to reflect that this issue applies to much more that
&gt; just tooltips.
&gt; 
&gt; Increasing severity also, as it causes parts of the layout not to be displayed,
&gt; therefore potentially causing incoherent behavior [...]

Component also changed to ui-core, as this seems to be a lot deeper then initially assumed.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8361</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-06 18:24:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>This was recently reported in Mozilla&#39;s Bugzilla [1]: please vote in the bug if you find it relevant (please don&#39;t just comment saying &quot;please fix it&quot; or &quot;I&#39;ve experienced this too&quot;).  Comments which are Firefox-centric should be posted there, although if someone is not certain but has details who would like to share, please comment here and someone (potentially me) will try to understand if it&#39;s related to Firefox or Qooxdoo.

[1] https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=481869</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8373</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-09 09:17:24 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I now see this problem in 0.8.2 as well. The demo browser doesn&#39;t even start up. http://demo.qooxdoo.org/current/demobrowser/

firefox-3.2a1pre.en-US.mac.dmg	08-Mar-2009</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8383</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-09 10:51:18 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #10)
&gt; This was recently reported in Mozilla&#39;s Bugzilla [1]: please vote in the bug if
&gt; you find it relevant (please don&#39;t just comment saying &quot;please fix it&quot; or &quot;I&#39;ve
&gt; experienced this too&quot;).

Naturally, one may use the &quot;Add me to CC list&quot; to get notifications on the issue... ;-)


(In reply to comment #11)
&gt; I now see this problem in 0.8.2 as well. The demo browser doesn&#39;t even start
&gt; up.

Yup, I had already reported it in the mailing list previously [1]... ;-)


[1] http://www.nabble.com/Release-0.8.2-ramp-down-td22293472.html#a22308966</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8643</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-17 10:15:00 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>In the current nightly version of FireFox the problem seems to be fixed.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8648</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-17 11:00:36 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #13)
&gt; In the current nightly version of FireFox the problem seems to be fixed.

Apparently not yet [1]...

[1] https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=481869#c15</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9244</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-13 14:49:54 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #14)
&gt; Apparently not yet [1]...
&gt; 
&gt; [1] https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=481869#c15

OK, apparently gone [2] for good. :-)

(Marking as invalid as the source of the behavior described in this bug report was due to a Firefox bug.)

[2] https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=481869#c20</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9249</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-13 16:28:19 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Changing (platform) property as of bug 2231 -- sorry for the mass mailing.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37470</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:21:54 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>