<bug>
          <bug_id>1724</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-12-16 11:12:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Make child control API public</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:23:44 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.8.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</assigned_to>
          <cc>info</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6946</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-16 11:12:11 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>We should parts of the child control API public and deprecate the protected methods:

_getChildControl
-hasChildControl
-showChildControl
-excludeChildControl</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6949</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-16 14:07:49 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>to me</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6950</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-16 14:34:43 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Why should they be public? The idea behind this was that they are explicit protected because nobody outside really should have access into these internals. Some arguments for this change would be nice. The cost is an increased public API which opens up deep internals of widgets to the outside. </thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6951</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-16 14:40:43 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I was not privy to the discussions on making them public, but I certainly appreciate it happening.  On a number of occasions I&#39;ve encountered the need to retrieve or manipulate a child control.  Although qooxdoo has improved greatly in 0.8 by making it possible to manipulate the internally-used widgets via methods to the &quot;top-level&quot; widget, there are still many unanticipated needs that require a deeper knowledge and the ability to easily access the child widgets.

Granted this change doesn&#39;t actually add any capability, but it does make it clear that there are times when it&#39;s perfectly reasonable to access the child controls.

Derrell
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6952</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-16 14:44:08 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>First of all this information is already part of by public API. Anyone who has to write a theme has to know, which child control IDs exist and which widget they represent. So they cannot be regarded as implementation detail. By being protected they are in fact accsessible in derived sub classes.

Recently there have been some very valid use cases on the mailing list, which require access to the child controls. In some of these use cases creating a sub class is definitively overkill. I would say in this it makes sense to make the API more open.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6953</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-16 14:54:37 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>@Fabian: To document a child control for theming and to allow full-blown access to it, is a huge difference.

@Derrell: We should find a solution for such edge cases. But open up a whole sub-system to every-day qooxdoo users is bad. It just offer to many options not officially supported by the widget author.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6954</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-16 15:17:17 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I made _getChildControl and _hasChildControl public (rev. 17037)

Documenting the child controls is out of scope of this bug but needs to be done anyway.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>7133</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-17 19:34:40 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>fixed.

See related bug #1789</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>38125</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:23:44 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>