<bug>
          <bug_id>1791</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-12-18 01:52:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Support accessibility via keyboard navigation and WAI-ARIA</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:48:10 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Aaron Leventhal">aaronleventhal</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>7136</commentid>
            <who name="Aaron Leventhal">aaronleventhal</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-18 01:52:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Adding support for keyboard navigation and WAI-ARIA would allow Qooxdoo to be usable by people with disabilities.

There is information on WAI-ARIA at http://codetalks.org 
Please see the resource page on that site: http://wiki.codetalks.org/wiki/index.php/ARIA_Resources (there&#39;s even an in-depth video now)
There are also plenty of examples: http://wiki.codetalks.org/wiki/index.php/Set_of_ARIA_Test_Cases
I also really suggest signing up to the mailing list for support: http://groups.google.com/group/free-aria

Other JS toolkits either already have support for WAI-ARIA or are currently planning it. Dojo currently has the most complete support, followed by YUI, then GWT, then JQuery.

On the browser side, Firefox 3 has very complete support. IE 8 betas have basic support, and both WebKit and Opera have added some support for ARIA.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>7148</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-18 10:25:06 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Aaron,

thanks for the detailed input. 

In fact, we have been considering to add ARIA support for a while now, also see http://qooxdoo.org/community/ideas#accessibility

BTW, keyboard support in qooxdoo is quite extensive. What could also be done very easily is creating a high-contrast theme. Some more work would (font) scaling imply, but in principle flexible layouts can also be realised easily in qooxdoo. Of course, those intermediate steps are far from screenreader enabled apps, ARIA.

On a technical level qooxdoo should be able to fulfill many of those requirements. But for implementing a real-life a11y solution, we certainly need to collaborate with people that are experienced in this topic, i.e. know all the concepts, relevant tools, screen readers, etc.

Given your interest in the ARIA, could you image to work with us on this topic? :-)
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>7149</commentid>
            <who name="Aaron Leventhal">aaronleventhal</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-18 10:31:30 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Great to see the interest.

&gt; Given your interest in the ARIA, could you image to work with us on this topic?

I&#39;m actually a little bit of a bottleneck, so it&#39;s better to put questions out to the whole community. But yes, I and others will help. There are a lot of helpful people on the free-aria mailing list. Some are even working on ARIA under grants. In particular, Mozilla has given grants to the ATRC from U Toronto to advise JS toolkits on the right approaches. Finally, you can find a lot of us at irc.mozilla.org #accessibility

Where are you in Germany? I&#39;m in the Stuttgart area. Perhaps we can meet to discuss ARIA if you are not far.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36157</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:48:10 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>