<bug>
          <bug_id>1874</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-01-28 23:43:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Can not set a column width lower then 40 pixels.</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:26:20 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.table</component>
          <version>0.8</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.0-beta1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Jim Hunter">Jim</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>7466</commentid>
            <who name="Jim Hunter">Jim</who>
            <bug_when>2009-01-28 23:43:39 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>If you set the column size lower then 40, the data column will get set to the new size, but the header will go no lower then 40. So setting a column size to 30 will give you a header 40 pixels wide and the data column will be 30 pixels wide. The vertical line between the columns will then be misaligned and the actual visible line in the header can not be used to resize the column. At that point you need to click above the column border in the data area to resize the column. And if you resize it larger then 40, then the alignment will be back to normal. And this can be done programmatically as well with setColumnWidth().</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>7515</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-02 08:42:59 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>This is because the min width of the table header cells is hard coded to 40px in the modern theme. The idea behind this min size was that the column with should at least allow the user to see the sorting indicator and the icon. However users didn&#39;t expect that and blamed the table to be broken.

I&#39;ve experienced two problems with very small column widths. The first is that below a width of 5px it becomes impossible or at least very hard to make the column wider again by using the resize handles. The second problem looks like a bug to me: If the column is smaller than ~13px the pane has rendering issues. The cells of the resized column overlap with the cell of the next column.

I&#39;ve set the min width in the appearance to 13px for now (rev.  17507). Once the pane bug is fixed we should lower this to 5px.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12536</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-22 15:20:21 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The table cells have a left/right padding of 6px and a right border of 1px width. This results in a minimal width of the cell DOM element of 13px. Making the minWidth smaller than 13px will result in rendering errors.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14446</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-24 20:14:38 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>mass renaming of 0.9 target to 1.0-beta1</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>39078</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:26:20 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>