<bug>
          <bug_id>1917</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-02-09 15:45:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>SingleValueBinding shouldn&#39;t verify the passed property name</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:22:46 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core</component>
          <version>0.8.2</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.8.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Wayne">w.si</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>7649</commentid>
            <who name="Wayne">w.si</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-09 15:45:43 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi,
I believe the bindeventtoproperty and bindpropertytoproperty should NOT verify the property definition even in debug mode, because some qooxdoo controls do not use property. For example, the only way to access the value of a TextField is getValue and setValue however value is not a property, and thus the assert in the binding functions will always fail.

I don&#39;t want to turn off the debug option, so please do NOT use assert but use this.log or this.error or this.warning instead.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>7650</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-09 16:02:59 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I do know that problem and its on my to do list. I plan a fallback solution that first checks if an property is there and after that, if there is an event with that name.
If you do have currently the problem of only having a data event, just use bindEvent instead of bind. But keep in mind that there will be changes in the code. Its still experimental.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>7651</commentid>
            <who name="Wayne">w.si</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-09 16:08:12 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; I do know that problem and its on my to do list. I plan a fallback solution
&gt; that first checks if an property is there and after that, if there is an event
&gt; with that name.
&gt; If you do have currently the problem of only having a data event, just use
&gt; bindEvent instead of bind. But keep in mind that there will be changes in the
&gt; code. Its still experimental.
&gt; 

Thanks for the reply. But the problem is I want to sync between two TextFields so naturally bindevent fails due to the same check but on the target instead. Then I was so desperated to raise the bug. :-)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13888</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-04 23:18:07 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>mass correction: set previously unspecified target milestone to 0.8.2</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37801</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:22:46 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>