<bug>
          <bug_id>1985</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-02-23 14:15:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Restructuring of top level namespaces for improved visibility of often used areas</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:20:36 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.0</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Sebastian Werner">info</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</assigned_to>
          <cc>fabian.jakobs</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>7979</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-23 14:15:23 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I would like to suggest some minor restructuring of the top-level namespaces to optimize the visibility of often used areas while hiding more internal stuff from the user:

qx.log =&gt; qx.core.log (most often used via this.debug, etc.)
qx.xml =&gt; qx.bom.xml (XML specific DOM manipulation)
qx.lang =&gt; qx.core.lang (language specific utilities which are used all over the framework)
qx.theme =&gt; qx.ui.theme (are as of today UI relevant)
qx.locale =&gt; qx.core.locale (most often used via this.tr, etc.)
qx.io.remote =&gt; qx.io.classic (
qx.io2 =&gt; qx.io (migration while keeping the classic classes)
qx.fx =&gt; qx.bom.fx (browser low-level specific, maybe used through Collection class in the future)
qx.application =&gt; qx.core.application (the application concept is a essential part of qooxdoo, but not really seen by the normal user with the new skeleton creation)

* Some of these changes would require further work on some classes to replace other stuff, especially in case of IO2/IO migration.
* Some of the changes may suggest to change things originally structured this way by me.
* Not sure about every idea yet - if it&#39;s practicable or better, but I thought it might still be a good idea to open a discussion here.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8874</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-24 18:52:39 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>There certainly are some valid suggestions (e.g. resolving qx.io2), others are questionable. Well, as usual. In general, though, those kind of API changes are to be seriously considered for releases 0.9 and particularly 1.0.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8897</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-25 09:47:47 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I would highly suggest to &quot;fix&quot; these things with 0.9 as qooxdoo should stabelize in these sections when nearing the 1.0 release.

As most of this stuff is automatically migrated through the migration support I also would not think that it is a huge problem to apply changes like these as early as time allows.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14741</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-24 20:26:02 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>mass renaming of 0.9 target to 1.0 (for issues with status &quot;NEW&quot;)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>15752</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-12-11 16:29:54 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Some of this has been addressed (i.e. resolving io2 namespace into existing io). The other suggestions won&#39;t be implemented in 1.0. 

The existing namespaces are often the original (or even refactored) ones, and are usually well-established now among users. They&#39;re not wrong per se, so it would rather hurt (users) to change them instead of keeping them as they are. Lets address useful namespace/renaming improvements again at a later point, when the framework has had significant progress, i.e in a 2.0 release.
 </thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36956</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:20:36 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>