<bug>
          <bug_id>1999</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-02-25 19:32:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>context menus require right and left click to generate &quot;execute&quot; event</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:26:16 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P1</priority>
          <bug_severity>major</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.8.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8069</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-25 19:32:35 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Some change has occurred recently to context menus. Previously, a right-click would display the context menu and the menu would remain visible when releasing the right-click. One could then move to the appropriate selection and left-click to make the selection.

Now, as soon as the right-click is released, the context menu disappears. In order to make a selection, one must hold down the right-click, move to the desired selection, and left-click while still holding the right-click.

This behavior can be seen in demobrowser, using the Menu option. Enable the firebug console so that execute events are displayed, right-click in the list box and then try to select an option.

There are two common operation methods for context menus: right-click, hold, release on the desired selection; or right-click and release, menu remains visible, left-click on the selection. I believe the operating system typically makes this choice, with Mac preferring the former, and Windows and Linux preferring the latter. The current behavior matches neither, of course.

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8070</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-25 19:55:07 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for reporting, this seems indeed to be broken. @Alex, please have a look at the issue.

Regarding the different behaviors (often OS-dependent), that might at sometime be solved by sorta abstract behavior layer (think of appearance). But that is still far, also involving the animation of qooxdoo widgets. In the meantime there should simply be a reasonable &quot;qooxdoo-style&quot; default behavior. </thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8089</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-26 18:29:37 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8102</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-27 11:22:40 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed with Revision #18182

Regression bug. A fix to prevent the menu from hiding when a disabled menu item was clicked caused this context menu disappear bug.

Modified the menu manager to support both correctly.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>39052</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:26:16 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>