<bug>
          <bug_id>201</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2006-10-25 11:05:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Line endings in frontend/demo/tool/layout.sh prevent make</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2008-06-05 14:28:56 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>INVALID</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>critical</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>hgibson</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>594</commentid>
            <who name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</who>
            <bug_when>2006-10-25 11:05:00 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>If you try and make in Windows with the default SVN checkout, you hit problems when the file frontend/demo/tool/layout.sh is executed. This is because the checkout in windows, using native eol style, puts in CRLF line endings. 

If these are modified to just LF endings it works. 

The fix is to change the SVN property eol-style to LF.

Hugh</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>595</commentid>
              <attachid>65</attachid>
            <who name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</who>
            <bug_when>2006-10-25 11:17:00 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Created attachment 65
Patch to fix this problem on trunk

I would check this in but my CVS write permission wasn&#39;t transferred to SVN...</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>598</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2006-10-25 12:20:10 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This is only true, if you configured your cygwin environment to work with unix line breaks while using another SVN client than the built in one e.g. TortoiseSVN.

The fix you suggest is not a fix, as it will break the users which use another configuration of cygwin/tortoisesvn. The bash script layout.sh always must use the line-breaks of the environment.

Maybe we can extend the documentation here and mention that if you use Tortoise SVN it is the best to configure cygwin to use DOS line breaks.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>602</commentid>
            <who name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</who>
            <bug_when>2006-10-25 14:48:48 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>&gt; This is only true, if you configured your cygwin environment to work 
&gt; with unix line breaks while using another SVN client than the built in one e.g.
&gt; TortoiseSVN.

I have not done this. In researching this reply, I found the nobinmode environment option for Cygwin, but I have not got that specified - in fact there are no Cygwin environment variables set.

I tried setting nobinmode, and issuing another &quot;make&quot; with layout.sh as checked out by Tortoise (i.e. with CRLF endings) and it failed at the same point as before.

&gt; The fix you suggest is not a fix, as it will break the users which 
&gt; use another configuration of cygwin/tortoisesvn. The bash script layout.sh 
&gt; always must use the line-breaks of the environment.

I don&#39;t see &quot;another configuration&quot; which will affect cygwin in this way. Have you tried this? At least two other people have hit the problem (check the mailing list).

Perhaps the make command, when loading layout.sh opens the shell script explicitly in binary mode, leading to problems.

&gt; Maybe we can extend the documentation here and mention that if you 
&gt; use TortoiseSVN it is the best to configure cygwin to use DOS line breaks.

I do, and it fails. So the bug is certainly not fixed.

What would be the problem in having layout.sh with just LF line endings? In that case Cygwin would perform no conversion when loading the file - either as part of Make or if executing it standalone. And it should just work.

Hugh</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>603</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2006-10-25 15:26:59 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The only way to change the setting is IMHO via the setup of cygwin. Just start it again and change the setting in one of the first dialogs.

I also have heard from many people that after changing this setting it simply works. So it&#39;s more or less a incompatibility between TortoiseSVN and Cygwin and no need for qooxdoo to modify the setting. Tortoise have no option to configure the &quot;native&quot; line ending. This would be another option.

The problem with LF line endings is, that a DOS configured Cygwin does not work anymore. In my opinion &quot;native&quot; line endings are just the best choice.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>607</commentid>
            <who name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</who>
            <bug_when>2006-10-30 14:45:00 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>That now works. I&#39;ve updated the documentation in the Wiki regarding installation of Cygwin and then what to do if you hit a bug during building.

Wonderful thing, documentation!

Hugh</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
          <attachment isobsolete="0" ispatch="1" isprivate="0" isurl="0">
            <attachid>65</attachid>
            <date>2006-10-25 11:17:00 +0200</date>
            <delta_ts>2006-10-25 11:17:00 +0200</delta_ts>
            <desc>Patch to fix this problem on trunk</desc>
            <filename>qxbug201.patch</filename>
            <type>text/plain</type>
            <size>181</size>
            <attacher>hgibson</attacher>
            
              <data encoding="base64">DQpQcm9wZXJ0eSBjaGFuZ2VzIG9uOiB0cnVua1xxb294ZG9vXGZyb250ZW5kXGRlbW9cdG9vbFxs
YXlvdXQuc2gNCl9fX19fX19fX19fX19fX19fX19fX19fX19fX19fX19fX19fX19fX19fX19fX19f
X19fX19fX19fX19fX19fX19fX18NCk5hbWU6IHN2bjplb2wtc3R5bGUNCiAgIC0gbmF0aXZlDQog
ICArIExGDQoNCg==
</data>

          </attachment>
      

    </bug>