<bug>
          <bug_id>2012</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-02-27 14:41:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>&quot;qx.event.Registration.getManager(null) was called!&quot;</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:22:46 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P1</priority>
          <bug_severity>blocker</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.8.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8109</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-27 14:41:59 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Sebastian made a change yesterday to qx.event.Registration that causes the build version of applications to fail now. I think his change was to figure out where the null element was coming from, but it also put the &#39;target = window&#39; inside of the qx.debug block, meaning that in the source version, the log message is displayed but in the build version it just fails.

Here&#39;s a backtrace from the source version in case this helps track it down:

5407ms qx.event.Registration.getManager(null) was called!Native.js (line 51)
5414ms
 qx.event.Registration: qx.log.Logger:224
 qx.event.Registration:67
 qx.bom.Element:242
 qx.html.Element:341
 qx.ui.core.queue.Manager:127
 qx.application.AbstractGui:render:97
 qx.application.AbstractGui:finalize:87
 qx.core.Init:86
 qx.event.dispatch.Direct:constructor:99
 qx.Interface:422
 qx.event.Manager:809
 qx.event.Registration:293
 qx.event.handler.Application:__fireReady:167
 qx.event.handler.Application:107</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8110</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-27 14:46:32 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>r18192 puts the target=window outside of the qx.debug so that build versions work again. This ticket is left open, however, as the source of the null element should probably be tracked down.

Derrell
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8111</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-27 14:57:13 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>-&gt; Sebastian</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8114</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-27 15:40:58 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report Derrell.

I just do not understand why no just fix the *real* error. I don&#39;t understand why you doing this, without letting me know about the problem *first*. 

There were some post-fixes already to make sure that there are no such calls in the framework anymore. I may have overlook some, but these should be fixed immetiately.

Please tell me where you got this error?

Seems that somewhere qx.bom.Element.focus() is called without an argument.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8118</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-27 16:25:24 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(08:49:41)  Andreas Ecker:  Hi, got a second? 
(08:49:54)  Derrell Lipman:  yup. stand by just a minute. 
(08:50:16)  Andreas Ecker:  Regarding your recent bug report 2012, are you up-to-date with SVN trunk? 
(08:50:35)  Andreas Ecker:  What apps do fail in the build version and where exactly. 
(08:51:15)  Derrell Lipman:  sorry. with you now. 
(08:51:41)  Derrell Lipman:  yes, i&#39;m completely up to date. my LifeLine-DVD gui app fails the build version and displays that error in the source version. 
(08:51:49)  Derrell Lipman:  i provided the stack backtrace. 
(08:52:07)  Derrell Lipman:  and it didn&#39;t have any errors with the version from yesterday. 
(08:52:19)  Andreas Ecker:  would you mind doing a distclean and try again? 
(08:52:25)  Derrell Lipman:  sure. hold on. 
(08:52:34)  Andreas Ecker:  I cannot reproduce the error here. 
(08:52:37)  Andreas Ecker:  :-( 
(08:53:03)  Derrell Lipman:  why was that log message put in? sebastian must have seen some problem...??? 
(08:53:11)  Derrell Lipman:  it was just changed yesterday. 
(08:54:00)  Derrell Lipman:  yes, error still occurs after distclean and generate source. 
(08:54:33)  Andreas Ecker:  At startup of your app before interaction? 
(08:54:37)  Derrell Lipman:  yes 
(08:57:32)  Andreas Ecker:  What about the built-in apps? 
(08:57:41)  Andreas Ecker:  Feedreader or Playground? 
(08:58:04)  Derrell Lipman:  don&#39;t know. i don&#39;t have them built. 
(08:58:06)  Andreas Ecker:  What&#39;s the browser your&#39;re using (I suppose FF 3.0.6 under Linux)? 
(08:58:22)  Derrell Lipman:  yes 
(08:58:23)  Andreas Ecker:  Would you mind generating playground? 
(08:58:32)  Andreas Ecker:  ... and give it a try. 
(08:58:34)  Derrell Lipman:  sure, but what do you want me to feed it? 
(08:59:14)  Derrell Lipman:  (i&#39;ve actually never used it; i just have my standard Application.js that i always play with.) 
(08:59:22)  Derrell Lipman:  for testing 
(08:59:40)  Andreas Ecker:  No, I&#39;d expect it to bark at start-up, just like your app. 
(08:59:51)  Andreas Ecker:  What&#39;s special about your app at startup? 
(09:00:00)  Derrell Lipman:  nothing that i know of. 
(09:00:31)  Derrell Lipman:  no, playground doesn&#39;t barf 
(09:00:41)  Andreas Ecker:  :-( 
(09:01:06)  Derrell Lipman:  playground gets an error in Focus.js though. 
(09:01:35)  Derrell Lipman:  actually it&#39;s a similar location. __fireReady() 
(09:01:38)  Derrell Lipman:  may be related. 
(09:03:09)  Derrell Lipman:  A parameter or an operation is not supported by the underlying object&quot; code: &quot;15
focus()(null)Focus.js (line 214)
focus()(null)Element.js (line 242)
flush()()Element.js (line 341)
flush()()Manager.js (line 127)
render()()AbstractGui.js (line 97)
finalize()()AbstractGui.js (line 87)
__ready()()Init.js (line 86)
dispatchEvent()(Window index.html, qx.event.type.Event[13] $$hash=13 _type=completed, &quot;ready&quot;)Direct.js (line 99)
wrappedFunction()Interface.js (line 422)
dispatchEvent()(Window index.html, qx.event.type.Event[13] $$hash=13 _type=completed)Manager.js (line 809)
fireEvent()(Window index.html, &quot;ready&quot;, undefined, undefined)Registration.js (line 293)
__fireReady()()Application.js (line 167)
onScriptLoaded()()Application.js (line 107)
(?)()()lifeline.js (line 79)
[Break on this error] element.focus(); 
(09:04:12)  Andreas Ecker:  Ok, what&#39;s special about your browser?  ;-) 
(09:04:18)  Derrell Lipman:  oops, bad copy. forget that &quot;lifeline&quot; entry 
(09:04:21)  Andreas Ecker:  FF extensions? 
(09:04:43)  Derrell Lipman:  hold on, i&#39;ll see what i have installed.  
(09:05:01)  Derrell Lipman:  Better Gmail 2 0.7.2 
(09:05:04)  Derrell Lipman:  Firebug 1.3.3 
(09:05:09)  Derrell Lipman:  JSView 2.0.5 
(09:05:14)  Derrell Lipman:  MP3Tunes Load2Mobile 1.9 
(09:05:18)  Derrell Lipman:  Nuke Image 0.3 
(09:05:23)  Derrell Lipman:  Ubuntu Firefox Modifications 0.5 
(09:05:27)  Derrell Lipman:  i don&#39;t know what the latter does. 
(09:07:50)  Andreas Ecker:  ;-) 
(09:08:01)  Andreas Ecker:  I bet you&#39;d like to know now. 
(09:08:07)  Derrell Lipman:  i&#39;ve just disabled all extensions except for firebug. i&#39;ll tell you what happens in a moment. 
(09:08:25)  Andreas Ecker:  Great, thanks for tracking this one down. 
(09:08:44)  Derrell Lipman:  sorry, bug still appears. 
(09:10:24)  Derrell Lipman:  let me spend a few minutes and see if i can track this down. i would really like to know what sebastian&#39;s change was about yesterday, though. 
(09:15:45)  Derrell Lipman:  ok, the problem seems to be that 
(09:16:02)  Derrell Lipman:  in qx.html.Element it is iterating the action list 
(09:16:03)  Andreas Ecker:  Hold on, Alex got an idea ... 
(09:16:20)  Derrell Lipman:  but action.element.__element is not defined for some actions. 
(09:17:26)  Derrell Lipman:  action.element is an object with lots of properties including a $$hash and a qxClass (qx.ui.form.RadioButton in my case); just no __element property 
(09:18:56)  Andreas Ecker:  Hmm, you think the qx.html.Element thing is causing this problem? 
(09:19:21)  Andreas Ecker:  Alex thought it&#39;s due to the recent consolidation of the loading phase. 
(09:20:18)  Derrell Lipman:  indirectly. it&#39;s in the stack trace so i just traced it down that far. the action itself, though, and the actions&#39;s element is more directly the problem due to the fact that there&#39;s no __element property in action.element. maybe it&#39;s not rendered yet, so __element hasn&#39;t been created yet? 
(09:21:00)  Derrell Lipman:  this is in the flush() method in qx.html.Element. 
(09:22:09)  Derrell Lipman:  what&#39;s the method to obtain info about an object given its hash? 
(09:22:21)  Derrell Lipman:  i can then see exactly what this thing is that&#39;s causing the problem 
(09:23:29)  Andreas Ecker:  qx.core.ObjectRegistry.fromHash(hash) 
(09:27:23)  Derrell Lipman:  well that was entirely useless. it just told me it is a qx.html.Element. sigh. 
(09:27:40)  Derrell Lipman:  trying again... 
(09:31:49)  Derrell Lipman:  that&#39;s not helping.  
(09:31:50)  Derrell Lipman:  here&#39;s a clue, though. i&#39;m getting this error six times, and i have six tabs... 
(09:45:11)  Andreas Ecker:  So it&#39;s in your LifeLine app, right? 
(09:45:38)  Andreas Ecker:  I thought you were looking for the Focus problems of playground... 
(09:45:47)  Derrell Lipman:  that&#39;s the app that&#39;s exhibiting the problem, yes.  
(09:45:58)  Andreas Ecker:  Or do both apps show the same problem underneath? 
(09:46:46)  Derrell Lipman:  i don&#39;t know if they both show the same problem, although they both occur during __fireReady 
(09:47:11)  Andreas Ecker:  What&#39;s your cache setting in FF. You don&#39;t seem to use special cache-controlling extensions. 
(09:47:29)  Andreas Ecker:  Yes, it&#39;s probably related to the loading phase stuff. 
(09:47:37)  Derrell Lipman:  no, there&#39;s nothing special. what cache setting do you mean? 
(09:47:51)  Andreas Ecker:  Always off and the likes. 
(09:48:27)  Andreas Ecker:  It&#39;s (almost) unreproducible here (only Alex saw it once).  
(09:48:53)  Derrell Lipman:  i don&#39;t even know where those cache settings are configured in FF. i haven&#39;t touched them (any time recently, anyway). 
(09:49:12)  Andreas Ecker:  There are a few paths that can be taken during the loading phase, so the cache setting may influence this. 
(09:49:29)  Andreas Ecker:  Ok. 
(09:49:42)  Andreas Ecker:  You&#39;re a Debian guy, right? 
(09:49:54)  Derrell Lipman:  formerly, now ubuntu which is based on debian. 
(09:50:17)  Andreas Ecker:  What does the About say in FF? 
(09:50:42)  Andreas Ecker:  (Sorry, cannot focus closely enough the hidden camera behind you) 
(09:50:51)  Derrell Lipman:  Mozilla/5.0 (X11; U; Linux i686; en-US; rv:1.9.0.6) Gecko/2009020911 Ubuntu/8.04 (hardy) Firefox/3.0.6 
(09:51:02)  Andreas Ecker:  thx 
(09:51:38)  Derrell Lipman:  every time i get up to go to the bathroom, i get a phone call. there MUST be a webcam here someplace... 
(09:52:07)  Andreas Ecker:  Oops, the famous &quot;potty break&quot;.  ;-) 
(09:52:11)  Derrell Lipman:  i&#39;m tracking down what element is causing this problem. i&#39;ll let you know shortly. 
(09:53:03)  Andreas Ecker:  Great, it probably doesn&#39;t hurt that Alex is also checking the loading phase... 
(10:09:05)  Derrell Lipman:  ok, the element causing the problem is the containerElement of the &quot;button&quot; child of qx.ui.tabview.Page. 
(10:20:00)  Derrell Lipman:  at start-up time, the referenced button is hidden. it&#39;s a button in tabview within a tabview, and that inner tabview is not visible because the outer tabview has a different tab selected. what&#39;s interesting, though, is that i seem to get the error only on the first, selected non-visible inner tab, not on the other tabs within that inner, not-visible tabview. 
(10:20:52)  Derrell Lipman:  when i select the outer tabview&#39;s tab to display these inner tabs, they all renders fine.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8121</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-27 16:59:17 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Ok, fine. A chat transscript. Next time it would be great if you could involve me and dissuss issues with my changes in first instance with me and not with someone else. Otherwise please add me to the discussion earlier. Maybe I could help to track these things down.

After a first investigation I think that the qx.html.Element stuff trying to focus some element which has not been yet created. Maybe this is related to the action changes Alex has made a few weeks ago.

Maybe you can publish an small example somewhere which shows the error (qooxdoo-contrib, maybe).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8122</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-27 17:59:49 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Here&#39;s a nice simple application that causes the problem.

/*
#require(qx.log.appender.Native)
#require(qx.log.appender.Console)

*/

qx.Class.define(&quot;custom.Application&quot;,
{
  extend : qx.application.Standalone,

  members :
  {
    main : function()
    {
      var i;
      var j;
      var page;
      var subTabs;
      var subPage;

      this.base(arguments);

      var mainTabs = new qx.ui.tabview.TabView();
      this.getRoot().add(mainTabs, { edge : 10 });

      for (i = 0; i &lt; 2; i++)
      {
        page = new qx.ui.tabview.Page(&quot;Page &quot; + i);
        page.setLayout(new qx.ui.layout.VBox(4));
        mainTabs.add(page);

        subTabs = new qx.ui.tabview.TabView();
        subTabs.setContentPadding(0);
        page.add(subTabs, { flex : 1 });

        for (j = 0; j &lt; 2; j++)
        {
          // Create a page
          subPage = new qx.ui.tabview.Page(&quot;Subpage &quot; + j);
          subPage.setLayout(new qx.ui.layout.VBox(4));
          subTabs.add(subPage, { flex : 1 });
        }
      }
    }
  }
});
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8126</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-28 19:02:20 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Derrell, may I ask to verify that this is fixed in SVN? Thanks.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8127</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2009-02-28 19:47:43 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Yup, it certainly seems to be fixed. The small example I provided now works perfectly with no stack backtraces displayed, and my own application works in its &quot;build&quot; version even if I move the target=window statement back inside of the qx.debug block.

Thanks!

Derrell

ps. I&#39;m leaving the bug open since the svn commit indicated that you&#39;re awaiting a response from Alex.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8152</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-02 14:18:20 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>@Alex, could you please double-check this and then close the bug?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8157</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-02 15:09:56 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Everything fine. Well done Sebastian!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8323</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-05 16:52:25 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>While this bug appeared to be fixed, it still showed up, nicely to be reproduced in Derrell&#39;s sample app in comment #6. Before and after the code changes of comment #7, though, it could show up when starting up the app or when switching the tabs within the app. Therefore even after the intended fixes it probably got unnoticed.

The whole issue is also related to bug #2040. In total this issue became critical right before shipping the 0.8.2 release. There seems not to be a definite generic solution to problems around widgets that certain actions are to be applied to (like focus, blur, etc.), but that are not yet visible. This needs more thoughts and testing. Hmm, maybe it is still the best solution to do such actions like focusing a widget in the appear handler explicitly?

We&#39;ll see what a generic solution could look like (well, if there is any), encouraging all interested people to discuss and contribute.

BTW, commit to restore the (possibly incomplete but hopefully uncritical) behavior of 0.8.1 was r18333.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37800</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:22:46 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>