<bug>
          <bug_id>2020</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-03-02 21:58:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Applications break in build version in Google Chrome</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:20:39 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>Chrome</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>DUPLICATE</resolution>
          <dup_id>2017</dup_id>
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P1</priority>
          <bug_severity>critical</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.8.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</assigned_to>
          <cc>helder.magalhaes</cc>
    
    <cc>mrh</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Chrome</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8182</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-02 21:58:09 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The following report is from a post of Mr. Hericus on the mailing list:

This has only happened within the past week or so.  I&#39;m working from the
qooxdoo trunk code, and have recently updated to the latest commits.
I&#39;ve been testing with IE 7, FF 3, and google Chrome 1.0.154.

When I work with a source version of my application, all 3 browsers work
fine.  When I compile a build version of the application, IE and FF are
fine, but chrome gives me this error when trying to load the
application:

Uncaught TypeError: Cannot ready property &#39;style&#39; of null
http://webserver/qd8/build/script/qd8.js (line 7307)

Line 7307 is inside qx.ui.root.Application, in the
_createContainerElement  on this line:

        var bstyle = doc.body.style;

I wondered if it was something I&#39;m doing in my application.  So i used
create_application.py to generate a brand new skeleton app.  I made no
changes to it, created both the source and build versions and pointed
all 3 browsers to it.  Same behaviour.  With IE and FF, both source and
build versions load just fine with no warnings or errors.  With chrome,
the source version loads fine with no warnings, but the build version
gives the above error and fails to load.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8183</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-02 22:02:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks Mr. Hericus for the bug report. 

This may be related to the consolidation of the apps&#39; loading phase. @Fabian, please take a look (might also affect other browsers like Safari?).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8188</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-03 09:09:47 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I had the same issue with Safari. Fabian fixed this issue yesterday see #2017. He added the &quot;body&quot; tag to the &quot;index.html&quot; file. 

With the current trunk (r18247), I have tried to test the issue with Chrome. But the new created application (with &quot;create-application.py&quot;) runs in the source and build version. If I remove the body tag, the script error occurs.

Thus, I set the bug report as duplicate of #2017

*** This bug has been marked as a duplicate of bug 2017 ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8236</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-03 19:42:39 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #2)
&gt; I had the same issue with Safari. Fabian fixed this issue yesterday see #2017.
&gt; He added the &quot;body&quot; tag to the &quot;index.html&quot; file. 

If this adding an empty body tag fixes the problem, then in my opinion:
 1. The legacy branch should be fixed as well (index.html scattered around), unless there&#39;s proof that the legacy branch is not affected, naturally;
 2. All qooxdoo users should be notified (maybe through the mailing list and by creating a qooxdoo news/blog [1] entry) stating that index.html files should be manually updated -- already deployed application&#39;s HTML file will only be fixed by manual user intervention, and this may save from many issues haunting the mailing list in a near future, given Chrome (and Safari?) user base likely increasing.

[1] http://news.qooxdoo.org/</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8240</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-04 09:30:56 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #3)
&gt; (In reply to comment #2)
&gt; &gt; I had the same issue with Safari. Fabian fixed this issue yesterday see #2017.
&gt; &gt; He added the &quot;body&quot; tag to the &quot;index.html&quot; file. 
&gt; 
&gt; If this adding an empty body tag fixes the problem, then in my opinion:
&gt;  1. The legacy branch should be fixed as well (index.html scattered around),
&gt; unless there&#39;s proof that the legacy branch is not affected, naturally;
&gt;  2. All qooxdoo users should be notified (maybe through the mailing list and by
&gt; creating a qooxdoo news/blog [1] entry) stating that index.html files should be
&gt; manually updated -- already deployed application&#39;s HTML file will only be fixed
&gt; by manual user intervention, and this may save from many issues haunting the
&gt; mailing list in a near future, given Chrome (and Safari?) user base likely
&gt; increasing.
&gt; 
&gt; [1] http://news.qooxdoo.org/
&gt; 

[1] The issue is since the new loader script is implemented for 0.8.2, so the legacy branch mustn&#39;t be fixed.

[2] Yes, we have to publish the issue to the qooxdoo community. I will worry about it.
 </thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8244</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-04 10:28:24 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #4)
&gt; [1] The issue is since the new loader script is implemented for 0.8.2, so the
&gt; legacy branch mustn&#39;t be fixed.

Thanks for clearing this up.


&gt; [2] Yes, we have to publish the issue to the qooxdoo community. I will worry
&gt; about it.

OK, great. ;-)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36975</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:20:39 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>