<bug>
          <bug_id>2033</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-03-03 17:12:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Qooxdoo doesn&#39;t work on Symbian S60 and Opera Mini browsers</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-05-16 10:25:04 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>0.8.2</version>
          <rep_platform>Other</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P5</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Jiri Peterka">peterka.jiri</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>info</cc>
    
    <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
    
    <cc>rherrmann</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Other</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8227</commentid>
            <who name="Jiri Peterka">peterka.jiri</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-03 17:12:28 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Qooxdoo doesn&#39;t work on Symbian S60 browsers. Same problem on latest J2ME Opera Mini (4.2) browser on any OS. Caused probably by missing Ajax implementation of the browsers. Only initial screen without widgets is painted. Some Qooxdoo workaround for these devices will be needed. Note: On Windows CE with MS Internet Explorer and Android standard browser, it works fine.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9411</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-21 09:27:15 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Jiri, any updates on this one? Do you have a chance to look into those problems for S60 or Opera Mini browsers? We don&#39;t have those platforms available, but maybe we could collaborate on debugging the issues?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9412</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-21 09:41:27 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Opera Mini uses a proxy to reproduce content for low-end devices. Ajax applications will never work for Opera Mini.

Opera Mobile is the Ajax-enabled client from the same company. This client should basically work. But if you see that even the by large extends faster Webkit needs some time to initialize a qooxdoo GUI application it will not be better in Opera Mini.

The greatest hope on mobiles is Webkit. It is already available on Nokia S60, Blackberry, iPhone, Android and Palm Pre. There are even Webkit-based Windows CE browsers available. All these clients should basically work - maybe we need to fix some issues here and there but finally all these engines use the same core technology.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9415</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-21 10:24:07 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Sebastian, thanks for the input. I added it to the following page, along with some additional links to mobile platforms:
http://qooxdoo.org/documentation/general/mobile_devices

Anybody that has some more mobile info and links, please feel free to add them to this wiki page.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9663</commentid>
            <who name="Jiri Peterka">peterka.jiri</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-26 15:30:25 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Andreas, I suppose Sebastian wrote everything important. There is article about Opera Mini JavaScript support - http://dev.opera.com/articles/view/javascript-support-in-opera-mini-4/. Unfortunately  I can&#39;t judge possibility of modifying qooxdoo to be able run on Opera Mini. For example Google GWT-ext has similar problems on it. I would leave that, nevertheless it would be nice to have better performance on device browsers where it already works (Webkit based) because loading and processing times are not currently comfortable.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9667</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-27 09:59:50 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks Jiri for the feedback. I added your link to Opera Mini to the wiki page. Please feel free to add to or update this wiki page for any new &quot;mobile&quot; findings of yours.

Now that Opera Mini is too limited to support Ajax apps, what about your initial statement that &quot;&quot;Qooxdoo doesn&#39;t work on Symbian S60 browsers&quot;? Since it is based on webkit, what was your test setup (versions, etc.) that didn&#39;t allow for qooxdoo apps on S60?
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9687</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-27 14:06:15 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>As far as I know not all models of S60 are using Webkit. It seems that Nokia uses it only for the newer more capable devices.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9695</commentid>
            <who name="Jiri Peterka">peterka.jiri</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-27 15:00:52 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Andreas. Actually it seems that all Symbian S60 browsers are based on Webkit/WebCore/KJS Java Script. But there are several version of this browsers depending on product line of Nokia mobile phones, res. Symbian. If we are talking about working or not-working Qooxdoo, rendering engine doesn&#39;t seem to be good aspect for this. Nokia has at least three generation of Webkit browsers and the latest one is still in development. Qooxdoo works neither on the 1st generation (E50,.. ) nor on the 2nd and current generation (E51,...). So Webkit isn&#39;t guarantee for working Qooxdoo. It seems it depends on used JavaScript engine underneath. Nokia uses KJS but who know how it is modified. Unfortunately I&#39;m  not familiar with these technologies so I can&#39;t provide any valuable information.  See documents related to  Nokia browser  (http://www.forum.nokia.com/info/sw.nokia.com/id/1e66bc62-0a3e-4e36-b8c9-4e20e8b8cdd8/Overview_of_AJAX_Support_in_Nokia_Web_Browser_v1_0_en.pdf.html and http://www.s60.com/file?id=550).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9709</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-28 09:31:24 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks Jiri for the information. It&#39;s interesting that the document regarding Ajax support is from 2006. I think we could easily ignore this document. Only recent webkit versions are capable of running well on mobile devices. So it seems that we should start to collect devices which are offered with more-up-to-date-webkit-versions. Anybody has found resources regarding this?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12233</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-14 10:41:21 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>marked as enhancement. If anybody has more info or is interested to work in this area, please let us know.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19992</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-26 13:24:47 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closing as won&#39;t fix. This bug is about legacy browsers that don&#39;t play a role in the mobile challenges nowadays.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>