<bug>
          <bug_id>2040</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-03-04 17:39:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Unhandled exception in qx.html.Element.flush()</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2009-09-09 11:36:14 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P1</priority>
          <bug_severity>critical</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.8.3</target_milestone>
          
          <blocked>2089</blocked>
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Will Pritchard">Will_Pritchard</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</assigned_to>
          <cc>info</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8278</commentid>
            <who name="Will Pritchard">Will_Pritchard</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-04 17:39:08 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>qx.html.Element lines 374 - 375:

          obj = actions[action];          
          elem = obj.__element;

actions[action] on line 374 can be undefined and then an error occurs when obj.__element is evaluated.

When this happens the value of action is &quot;focus&quot; and the actions map has no members.

It is very hard to recreate in an small example application as the low level DOM processing is rather a &quot;black art!!&quot;</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8282</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-04 19:09:48 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Will, thanks for bringing this up. AFAIK nobody saw this before.

Please provide more input (as much and as soon as you can): OS, browser, browser deviation from default (extensions, settings). Also the application you noticed this error in (would be great you could provide the source code), and how you managed to trigger this error. What version of qooxdoo where you using (pre-SDK or SVn trunk) and does it show up in the latest versions?

Thanks for your collaboration!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8300</commentid>
            <who name="Will Pritchard">Will_Pritchard</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-05 11:52:14 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>*** Bug 2049 has been marked as a duplicate of this bug. ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8309</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-05 13:16:00 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>It may happen when focus and blur an element in a single flush of the queue. The fix would be to add a &quot;if (obj)&quot; before trying to access the element. Still not sure why this happens as the modifications to the &quot;actions&quot; map in &quot;__performAction()&quot; look good so far.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8310</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-05 13:16:37 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>to me</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8311</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-05 13:16:55 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8312</commentid>
            <who name="Will Pritchard">Will_Pritchard</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-05 14:00:00 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>This fault is present in:

qooxdoo SVN trunk

Windows XP

IE 6
Firefox 3.0.6 (with only the Java Quick Start add-on)

Unfortunately the application is far too big and complex to share and I have not been able to isolate the problem into a smaller application I could submit.

I can confirm the same application does not suffer from this fault using qooxdoo 0.8.1
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8314</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-05 14:16:03 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Will, even if you couldn&#39;t isolate the problem yourself, what widgets or interaction is involved? Nobody ever saw such an issue here, and there was really an impressive amount of testing. Any prompt feedback appreciated.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8316</commentid>
            <who name="Will Pritchard">Will_Pritchard</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-05 15:08:32 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I do not want this to delay the release of 0.8.2 as it does seem like a corner case and I can live with making a local fix (as per comment #3) to get around the issue.

More information about when it happens:

The problem is triggered when a mouse move event occurs in a qx.ui.table.Table.
This begins a timer after which a qx.ui.basic.Image is displayed - if there is a further mouse over event on the image another timer begins after which a derivative of qx.ui.container.Composite (which also includes qx.ui.core.MPlacement and contains a qx.ui.form.List and some qx.ui.form.Button objects) is displayed and focused.

When a mouse out event occurs on the Composite, timers are initiated to hide both the Image and the Composite - the error occurs at this point.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8325</commentid>
            <who name="Will Pritchard">Will_Pritchard</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-05 16:59:15 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>More information (see comment #8):

The Composite object is explicitly focused in an appear event handler so that it can be hidden in a blur event handler if the user clicks somewhere else before the timer expires (which will hide the Composite anyway).

When focus is not called the problem does not happen (but there is no blur event to use for hiding the Composite on a click before the timer expires).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8326</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-05 17:18:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed so that it can ship with the 0.8.2 release. This was nasty, and the topic
of how-to apply certain actions (like focus, blur, etc.) to widgets that are
not visible yet, is non-trivial. It appears there&#39;s not even a generic solution
that would work best in all situations.

More information and comments can also be found in a related bug, in which also
a sample app is given that allows to reproduce the error:
http://bugzilla.qooxdoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=2012#c6

Information from the bug mentioned:

This needs more thoughts and testing. We&#39;ll see what a generic solution could
look like (well, if there is any),
encouraging all interested people to discuss and contribute.

BTW, commit to restore the (possibly incomplete but hopefully uncritical)
behavior of 0.8.1 was r18333. 

Thanks so far to all people involved, either for fixing, improving, reporting,
in general for collaborating on this issue! This one needs to be continued
after the 0.8.2 release, so deferred milestone to next release.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8539</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-11 20:01:29 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>fixed with rev. 18274. See bug #2089 for details</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12056</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-09 11:36:14 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>closed</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>