<bug>
          <bug_id>2052</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-03-05 15:24:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Packages: The first package has to contain the complete translation infos</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:24:47 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>app.feedreader</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.8.3</target_milestone>
          
          <blocked>2086</blocked>
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          <cc>alexander.steitz</cc>
    
    <cc>christian.schuff</cc>
    
    <cc>steffen.frey</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8319</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-05 15:24:12 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The language switch for the main view works, but for the other windows (preferences, add feed) the language is always English.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8549</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-12 13:03:28 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Accepted.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8560</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-12 14:47:21 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The problem is that the translations are uncompleted in the feedreader.js (qx.$$translations), though the po files are full translated.

It seems to me, that the qx.$$translations miss the translations from the parts (addfeed and settings).

I think the generator ignore the translations form existing parts. Thomas could you please check this?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8658</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-17 14:43:10 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Additionally comment:
The generator does recognize the several translation strings of each package, but only the translations of the boot (=first) package are provided at the &quot;qx.$$translation&quot; map.

It is better to pack the translations of every package together into the boot package, to streamline it with the resources.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8660</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-17 15:14:18 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Normally each package should *only* contain the strings used in the package. There should be some kind of merge handling to migrate all strings into the global qx.$$translations with every additional package. This should be the same for resources as well.

Yes, this is the optimal case, but it was always thought this way in the initial implementation of the generator (II) part handling as normally all kind of additionally loaded parts may have a lot of texts / resources which are not needed for the initial bootup. For example huge preferences dialogs as for GMX.com etc.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8710</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-18 14:41:27 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>@Sebastian
You&#39;re right. The infos of the resources and  the translations should belong to the package which make use of them.
But to solve this problem pragmatically I have filed a separate bug report for splitting the infos off when packages are used. The goal of this bug report should be to add all necessary translation infos into the boot package in order to get a fully functional application.
The split off of the infos is filed under the Bug #2129.

Sounds good enough?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8721</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-18 17:07:05 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed with r18490.

The localisaton data from *all* parts (not just the first) had to be used.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>38520</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:24:47 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>