<bug>
          <bug_id>2110</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-03-16 10:14:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Improve structure for manual.</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:26:34 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>website</product>
          <component>documentation</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P1</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</assigned_to>
          <cc>gene</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8621</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-16 10:14:23 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Some proposals for the manual has appeared in the mailing list:

Gene Amtower:
&quot;Just a suggestion, but for somebody just wanting to read through the online documentation, a link to the Next and Previous pages in the documentation would be convenient.  Right now, I have to keep jumping back to the documentation TOC just to go to the next section.  To be consistent with reading through a paper manual (shiver!), jumping forward page-by-page would be an easy way to get familiar with all the Qooxdoo concepts, which is probably more important for newer users than current users looking for a particular detail.

Of course, I don&#39;t see anything like an Index page, sorted alphabetically by keyword.  This would be helpful when you want to find a topic without remembering which &quot;chapter&quot; it&#39;s in, and might help to reduce the number of &quot;where do I find out how to...&quot; questions on this list.  I envision keywords like &quot;root&quot;, &quot;widget&quot;, &quot;dom&quot;, &quot;object-oriented&quot;, &quot;create-application.py&quot; etc. providing links to any chapters that touch on that particular keyword, which might be a topic, concept, language construct, or tool component.  It can start out simple and grow as contributors help add entries to the Index page.  Even existing users of the framework might find this really helpful in times of need.  This Index page link should show up on every page in the documentation, at the bottom or top (or both), to facilitate finding an answer to a question that comes to mind while reading.

Since I haven&#39;t really looked into the functional structure of the Qooxdoo documentation, I don&#39;t know how easy it would be to implement these types of features.  A good example of a Next/Previous feature in online docs is the PHP manual, which makes it really easy to just read through the PHP docs linearly.&quot;</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8852</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-24 16:26:07 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&#39;ll have a closer look at the possibilities to link the manual pages, but I expect it to be some (duh!) manual work of inserting the links.

An index page (aka sitemap) might also be a good idea. As an alternative the wiki&#39;s full-text search may also be used to bring up all relevant pages for a topic (see search field on the right-hand side of the page).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12082</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-09 14:47:54 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>move documentation enhancements up to 0.9</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14875</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-24 20:48:34 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>mass renaming of 0.9 target for documentation issues to 1.0</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>16124</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2010-01-12 11:11:24 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The manual and explicit inter-linking of related documents could be an improvement. While it should work ok within certain sections, it probably won&#39;t along the entire manual (it is to less a book).

Adding an index may be a useful addon, but seems hard to create and maintain manually. One should look at that again after the more straightforward rework of the manual overview/structure.
 </thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19991</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-26 13:16:23 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closing this rather unspecific bug, targeting 1.2, as for that release the manual has been reworked to a large extend, with much improved output (online/html, offline/pdf).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>39157</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:26:34 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>