<bug>
          <bug_id>2119</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-03-17 13:42:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>IE error &quot;The data necessary to complete this operation is not yet available&quot; reading the response text</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:21:08 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.io</component>
          <version>0.7.4</version>
          <rep_platform>IE</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.7.5</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Ivan Furnadjiev">ivan</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Ivan Furnadjiev">ivan</assigned_to>
          <cc>alexander.steitz</cc>
    
    <cc>derrell.lipman</cc>
    
    <cc>info</cc>
    
    <cc>rherrmann</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Internet Explorer</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8651</commentid>
            <who name="Ivan Furnadjiev">ivan</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-17 13:42:33 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>In rare cases we receive such an error on AJAX request in Internet Explorer 7 when we try to read the response. Unfortunately there is no reproducible scenario available. We read the response text when the &quot;complete&quot; event is fired. It seems that the &quot;complete&quot; event is fired before the readyState become 4 in IE. Looking at the Exchange#wasSuccessful there is one suspicious place where the method returns true if readyState is different than 4 - the case with status code -1.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8849</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-24 16:10:25 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Not being easily reproducible may make it hard to track down the issue. Ivan, any chance you come up with a scenario?

Do some of the &quot;transport/RPC guys&quot; (e.g. Derrell, Andreas, Alex) have observed such an issue or have an idea? It may be happening in 0.8.x as well, since the underlying code may not have changed?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8864</commentid>
            <who name="Ivan Furnadjiev">ivan</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-24 17:14:29 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>No reproducible scenario yet.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9110</commentid>
            <who name="Rüdiger Herrmann">rherrmann</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-03 09:57:44 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Could someone of the &quot;transport/RPC guys&quot; take a look at the code in Exchange#wasSuccessful()?	
What does a statusCode of -1 mean?
Why does statusCode == -1 and readyState &lt; 4 return true?
Could a request with statusCode -1 ever trigger a &#39;completed&#39; event?
The comment &quot;// Not Available (OK for readystates: MSXML&lt;4=1-3, MSXML&gt;3=1-2, Gecko=1)&quot; does not match the code below.
Would it help to know the MSXML version? If so, how can it be determined?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10049</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-20 10:22:14 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hm, this is still an open issue. Does anyone have an update or comments here (e.g. reproducible sample, Ivan?).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10634</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-06-29 15:13:52 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Unfortunately, there weren&#39;t any comments from the CC&#39;ed people. I&#39;ll assign it to you Ivan, because you might have a sample to reproduce the issue now? Or you might have investigated it further. Any updates?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10665</commentid>
            <who name="Ivan Furnadjiev">ivan</who>
            <bug_when>2009-06-29 17:17:42 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Maybe someone from the &quot;transport/RPC guys&quot; will answer the questions in comment #3.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10668</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Junghans">andreas.junghans</who>
            <bug_when>2009-06-29 18:29:05 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Removing myself from CC since I can&#39;t help here. The code in question is probably Sebastian&#39;s, and I have no idea why it looks the way it does.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12994</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-08 14:19:13 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>There haven&#39;t been any updates. I guess also not on your side, Ivan??</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12996</commentid>
            <who name="Ivan Furnadjiev">ivan</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-08 14:26:38 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>No... We are still waiting for &quot;transport/RPC guys&quot; to answer the questions in
comment #3.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13010</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-08 15:01:12 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This code is a bit bizarre, but Exchange#wasSuccessful() is given a status code of -1 if an attempt to retrieve the status from a request throws an error:

    getStatusCode : function()
    {
      var vStatusCode = -1;

      try {
        vStatusCode = this.getRequest().status;
      } catch(ex) {}

      return vStatusCode;
    },

This would indicate to me that either there&#39;s a bug (getRequest() returns null because there&#39;s no request in progress) or the request has no status member (very strange).

The comment in wasSuccessful should probably say, &quot;Status code was not available&quot;, but why that&#39;s OK for various MSXML versions I have no idea.

(A complete rewrite of qx.io.remote such that it&#39;s readable and better organized would be a really nice project for someone with good networking experience who&#39;s looking to contribute to qooxdoo!)

Derrell
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13034</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-08 19:33:06 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Just got the bug to my radar. Thanks Andreas.

It relatively easy to explain as nearly every Ajax lib has such a workaround.  The issue is that in IE under some conditions a few properties throw some kind of access errors while other browser do not have an issue. &quot;-1&quot; is this case basically means that the browser not yet allows to access the property, but is not related to being successful or failed. As long as a request is not explicitly failed it is regarded as successfully.

Derrell, I think qx.io2 is a bit better. Especially as all the cross-browser magic is already done in qx.bom.Request. It makes it more complex when a code mix cross-browser logic and class-logic in one file. This is not the case with qx.io2.HttpRequest. It still needs further fine-tuning and testing, but I think it&#39;s a good start.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18369</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2010-05-19 09:20:21 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Ivan, this is still marked as NEW. Any updates, otherwise you might want to close this issue.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18392</commentid>
            <who name="Ivan Furnadjiev">ivan</who>
            <bug_when>2010-05-19 09:29:11 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>No, nothing in addition.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35106</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2014-02-17 18:53:16 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed outdated issue as wontfix, as bug became stale without feedback from assignee.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37173</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:21:08 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>