<bug>
          <bug_id>2138</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-03-19 11:52:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Bugzilla: no visual feedback on fixed issues and obsolete attachments</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:26:34 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>website</product>
          <component>other</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>minor</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</assigned_to>
          <cc>helder.magalhaes</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8751</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-19 11:52:40 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>If an attachment is made obsolete, no visual indication of this fact is displayed in the attachment list. This may become deceiving and also would avoid wasted time looking at patches/attachments made obsolete. This is a minor though annoying issue...

To reproduce:
1. Go to a bug containing obsolete attachments (bug 2137, for example);

Expected result:
Obsolete attachment(s) would display different (usually with a strike out decoration) from current ones.

Actual result:
Obsolete attachment(s) appear just like the other ones.

Workaround:
Follow the &quot;details&quot; link (in &quot;Actions&quot; column) and see if the &quot;obsolete&quot; checkbox is marked. (This is pretty non-user friendly...)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8754</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-19 11:58:33 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The different display should also be used in comments when the attachment is made within the report (such as the one in the example [1]).

This different visual display is included with Bugzilla (strike out), I&#39;m not sure if this was meant to be in the qooxdoo Bugzilla installation or if this was caused by a mistake during a CSS simplification/cleanup operation.

[1] http://bugzilla.qooxdoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=2137#c1</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8756</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-19 12:55:09 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&#39;ll have a look.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9768</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-01 13:32:18 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Just noticed that this behavior is also seen in issues fixed: &quot;Summary&quot; edited with this in mind, and priority also raised as this is much more annoying and misleading that just affecting (obsolete) attachments.

Bugzilla also recognizes and creates links for bugs, which currently aren&#39;t being strike-out whenever fixed (one can take a look at a comment which contains a link to an issue within the tracker, for example [1]. Currently, one has to place the cursor over the link in order to have some feedback on the linked bug status (for the example in [1], one can then read &quot;RESOLVED INVALID - ...&quot;) -- of course one can also follow the link or open it in a new window/tab but this somehow degrades usability, increases bandwidth and holds a performance hit for just knowing the bug (fixed) status of a related issue.

This will likely be the same while checking for votes [2] (fixed issues striked-out) for which using Mozilla&#39;s Bugzilla [3] displays not only striked-out issues (for the ones already fixed) but also tooltips with the issue&#39;s status. This makes me wonder if this has something to do with the Bugzilla version currently being used (2.22.2 in qooxdoo -- seen in page bottom -- as current Bugzilla versions are 3.2.3 and 3.3.4 [4] -- which is a giant step forward!)...

[1] http://bugzilla.qooxdoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1728#c7
[2] http://bugzilla.qooxdoo.org/votes.cgi
[3] https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/
[4] http://www.bugzilla.org/</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12083</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-09 14:51:28 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>to 0.9</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14876</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-24 20:48:35 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>mass renaming of 0.9 target for documentation issues to 1.0</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>15738</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-12-11 13:30:42 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>to be addressed after 1.0</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>17370</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-03-19 09:57:59 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Johnny, please look at this in the new bugzilla installation</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>17631</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2010-04-02 15:11:29 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #7)
&gt; Johnny, please look at this in the new bugzilla installation

Not Johnny here but no, it has not fixed it. ;-p

Digging down the issue, the issue seems to be caused by missing CSS information: obsolete attachments use CSS class &quot;bz_obsolete&quot;, while closed bugs use &quot;bz_closed&quot;, none of these classes declared in qooxdoo&#39;s bugzilla CSS information [1]. By digging this down a bit, and comparing qooxdoo&#39;s bugzilla CSS information [1] with Mozilla bugzilla one [2], this is the relevant stuff missing, slightly optimized:

.bz_obsolete, .bz_inactive, .bz_closed, .bz_CLOSED td {
    text-decoration: line-through;
}

Adding these lines will both solve issues with obsolete attachments and fixed/closed bugs. :-)

I&#39;m not sure if you want to take the opportunity for a quick review of more CSS information which may be worth to port, but for now this is it! ;-)

It&#39;s great that Bugzilla install was updated, anyway. :-)

Cheers,
 Helder


[1] http://resources.qooxdoo.org/style/sites/bugzilla.css
[2] http://bugzilla.mozilla.org/skins/standard/global.css</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>17636</commentid>
            <who name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</who>
            <bug_when>2010-04-06 10:15:10 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thank you Helder for digging into the style sheet. I just fixed this bug by adding your code.

We hope that we can roll out the new Bugzilla on our new server soon...</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>39158</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:26:34 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>