<bug>
          <bug_id>2227</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-04-09 10:31:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Further improve tooltip support</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:45:58 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Sebastian Werner">info</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>fabian.jakobs</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9227</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-09 10:31:08 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>With bug #26 there where added two new properties tooltipText and tooltipIcon which are in conflict with the old &quot;tooltip&quot; property which still exists.

I thought in qooxdoo we have this issue with the previous releases. We have omitted these kind of conflicts two properties may have during 0.8 in various places. With this change, added to 0.8.2 we introduced a new section of pain.

This may be OK for a initial step but needs further fine-tuning in my opinion. It would be highly interesting here for example what other frameworks and toolkit support here. There where never any kind of evaluation before. So this might be a good thing to do before modifying the current API.

The best usage of a tooltip is using shared instances. This massively reduces the number of instances needed. The only thing we need to support is to make it possible to support different types of visual styles and maybe icons. Even different implementation may be useful where a tooltip is not built of an Atom widget but with something else.

The most flexible solution here would be to have an additional property &quot;tooltipClass&quot; and remove the current property &quot;tooltipIcon&quot;. This way it may be possible to have different appearances as well (Just extend the base class and override the appearance default value). It is even possible to have another layout etc. And the interesting part here is that there might be used a singleton for every tooltip class so that even customized tooltips are shared. This is a huge win when an application couldn&#39;t work with the default tooltip implementation of qooxdoo as it can benefit from the same sharing algorithm.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12250</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-14 11:39:10 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This proposal should be reviewed for a more generic solution in future releases.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35367</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:45:58 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>