<bug>
          <bug_id>2244</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-04-16 10:31:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Improve logging for test runs</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:23:43 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.test.automation</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.8.3</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9309</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-16 10:31:06 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Debugging failed test runs is frustrating because any errors, debug messages and all Selenium RC server log messages are dumped to STDOUT/STDERR. Writing log output to multiple files depending on its origin and differentiating between info/debug and warning/error messages would make things easier.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9428</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-21 14:19:42 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The log output of the test script itself can now be routed to a file specified in testConf[&#39;testLog&#39;].</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9821</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-06 15:23:03 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>* The test controller class now logs everything it does to a file. Its location is specified in testConf[&#39;testLogDir&#39;]. A new file is created for each test run with the run&#39;s start date in the file name.

* The actual test runs (Simulations) now log to a local file as well as to the Selenium RC server&#39;s log file. Test reports are generated from these files, with the server log as a fallback.

Additional logging for tests of a local qooxdoo checkout:

* Output from batbuild.py (errors during SVN update or application build) is logged to files saved in the directory configured in buildConf[&#39;buildLogDir&#39;]. A new file is created for each build target.

* The build status (the trunk&#39;s SVN revision number at the time generation was started and any build errors) is also saved as a JSON file in the local trunk checkout&#39;s qooxdoo root directory. Remote test runs read this file in order to determine whether the application they&#39;re about to test has been built correctly.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>38119</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:23:43 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>