<bug>
          <bug_id>2350</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-05-07 17:10:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>RFC: A New Format for JS Packages</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:19:13 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>0.8.2</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>2.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          <cc>fabian.jakobs</cc>
    
    <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9843</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-07 17:10:15 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This bug discusses a new package format for qooxdoo JS packages. It might be 
sensible to restrict the investigation to &quot;build&quot; packages, i.e. packages that 
include class code directly (as opposed to &quot;source&quot; packages that only contain 
uris). Further comments will provide more background, motivation, intended 
purpose, and sketch possible formats.

One general idea is to split a package up into a CODE part (think: class code), 
maybe a DATA part, and a HEADER part. The HEADER part could contain an index of 
the contained classes, information about variants and optimizations, and other 
interesting meta information. The DATA part is e.g. to contain localized and 
translated strings.

  +--------------------+
  |  HEADER            |
  +--------------------+
  |  DATA              |
  +--------------------+
  |  CODE              |
  |                    |
  .                    .
  .                    .
  .                    .
  +--------------------+

The idea is to have a more versatile and re-combinable format for processed JS 
code. It should cover our current packages, which are e.g. created when 
defining parts. A package should be optimally self-contained on demand (e.g. by 
including all necessary translated strings), so it can be used highly 
independently of other packages. The format should probably be such that it can 
accommodate loader code, as our current boot packages have, so that boot 
packages fall into the generic scheme. But it should also be easily usable in 
contexts were the package does not belong to a RIA application (like the 
current apsinth/qod efforts), and the package code is loaded and managed by 
external (non-qooxdoo) logic. Maybe it should have a section for arbitrary JS 
code, so we could include non-qooxdoo JS code as well.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12552</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-22 17:20:43 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>added &#39;RFC&#39; to summary</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30771</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2012-09-21 18:13:41 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The intent of this bug is still valid, though we have a achieved a format that 
already has the DATA and CODE parts. We can re-open this bug when the need 
arises to define and utilize the HEADER part.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35091</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2014-02-17 16:35:16 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>LATER --&gt; WONTFIX</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36398</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:19:13 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>