<bug>
          <bug_id>2361</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-05-08 15:18:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>TextArea#maxLength has no effect</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:25:42 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.form</component>
          <version>0.7.3</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.7.5</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Ivan Furnadjiev">ivan</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>info</cc>
    
    <cc>michael</cc>
    
    <cc>rherrmann</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9880</commentid>
            <who name="Ivan Furnadjiev">ivan</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-08 15:18:31 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Setting the maxLength of a TextArea has no effect. User can continue typing in the text area after the number of characters exceeded the maxLength.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9881</commentid>
            <who name="Ivan Furnadjiev">ivan</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-08 15:30:48 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The HTML textarea has no property maxLength. One possible solution is given here:
http://psacake.com/web/js.asp
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9884</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-09 20:08:38 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>0.8 needs this feature as well. We should fix it in both branches.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9898</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-11 12:14:46 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>At least in 0.8 &quot;max&quot; is not supported anymore for textareas for exactly the reason that it is not natively supported.

As this is mainly not just a fix I would suggest to keep it in 0.7.x as it is (without support) and just adding it to 0.8 as a new features for text areas.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10026</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-19 11:37:41 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>-&gt; To Johnny</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10039</commentid>
            <who name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-19 15:10:28 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Accepted.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10063</commentid>
            <who name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-20 16:26:31 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed in trunk (r19191).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10066</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-20 17:21:58 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Just a few comments to the new implemention:

* Replace the two events with &quot;input&quot; should be more efficient
* Shouldn&#39;t the property be named &quot;maxLength&quot; instead of &quot;maxlength&quot;?
* When setting a value larger than maxLength I get a temporary wrong value with the &quot;changeValue&quot; event which is fired. This should not happen at all. What is needed here is that the value is not accepted (throws and error). I think for the API interface this is the same like the range of a Slider which is also not allowed to be lower zero for example.
* The best would be maybe to lay out the &quot;check&quot; of the value property from the abstract property so that special formatters are possible as well (e.g. IP number, date field, etc.)
* The event listeners should only be attached when the maxLength property is not null.
* Before calling trim() the length should be checked IMHO. Especially in these quite often called methods it&#39;s important to reduce the overhead. When every keypress produces a set of additonal function calls - even when the limit is not reached - this means some useless overhead

Just my 2 cents :)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10130</commentid>
            <who name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-26 15:28:32 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Implemented in AbstractField. Done for 0.8.x, this needs still to be done for 
0.7.x.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10131</commentid>
            <who name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-26 15:29:53 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Corrected MS and version.
-&gt; Andreas</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10143</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-26 18:40:29 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Johnny won&#39;t be able to look into an implementation for 0.7.x soon, so this bug gets unassigned. It would be appreciated if someone could provide a patch, maybe along the lines of the recent implementation in 0.8.x?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10150</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-27 11:25:59 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The current version do not fire input events when a part of the field is changed which is not in the limited area. E.g. adding text to the beginning of the field. Also it is questionable if &quot;input&quot; events should be really limited in a way. An input event do not mean that the value has changed - so all input is qualified to be fired as an event. Even if the value is not changed.

Why was the implementation modified in a way that properties are not used anymore? I would suggest to go back to properties and implement a check which protects the field for values which are to long (respecting max length). Then I would add a function maybe named &quot;parseValue()&quot; (like parseFloat() etc.) which is used during the &quot;blur&quot; event to process the current value of the field (applying limitations/formatting etc.). This method then calls the setter with an allowed value and results into the &quot;changeValue&quot; event being fired. This implementation would somewhat comparable to the other widgets having comparable features e.g. Slider. The aspect of implementing comparable things using the same established approach is IMHO quite important for a framework.

Found an issue in the implementation for the &quot;setValue&quot; method. Currently when any limitiations are applied the &quot;changeValue&quot; event is not fired. This is not correct as even if the new value is too large the shrinked value might have changed!

BTW: What was the reason for not using the native &quot;maxLength&quot; attribute on standard text fields anymore?

Re-assign to Jonny for further investigation.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10220</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-29 12:51:49 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>*** Bug 2181 has been marked as a duplicate of this bug. ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>17422</commentid>
            <who name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</who>
            <bug_when>2010-03-22 12:09:16 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Exclusive 0.7.x</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>17764</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-04-14 14:10:13 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Removed all core developers as assignee from 0.7 only bugs.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18381</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2010-05-19 09:29:05 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Set all open 0.7.x-only issues that have no assignee to WONTFIX. This is in accordance with 0.7.x users like the RAP team. If you want to work on such an 0.7.x issue, feel free to reopen it and assign it to you. The issues should only exist in the legacy 0.7.x versions and be already resolved in qooxdoo 0.8 or above.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>38844</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:25:42 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>