<bug>
          <bug_id>239</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2006-11-28 08:16:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Missing name for param in function comment crashes API builder</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2008-06-05 14:27:16 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.apidata</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>711</commentid>
            <who name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</who>
            <bug_when>2006-11-28 08:16:40 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>If you have a function header with an @param entry but a missing name e.g.

* @param {var} TODO

then the API builder crashes.

I can&#39;t copy from cygwin, but here is the gist:

api.py, line 350, in handleFunction
   paramName = attrib[&quot;name&quot;]
Exception: Create documentation failed: &#39;name&#39;

Hugh</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>737</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2006-11-29 14:50:51 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>IMHO params without names make no sense so it&#39;s OK that this does not work. The author should correct the class in this case.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>753</commentid>
            <who name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</who>
            <bug_when>2006-11-29 22:46:45 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The point is that the API builder crashes, with no information about where the problem is in your JavaScript. Other faults in the JavaScript give an exception with information about the location of the problem including file, line number and column number. In this case the python app just crashes with no information.

For example, put an extra comma after the last entry in a set of constants in a class. You get a traceback, but at the bottom it says &quot;treegenerator.SyntaxException: Expected map key (identifier, string or number) but found token/RC: &#39;}&#39;. file:blah.blah, line:39, column:4.

All syntax errors should be handled in a consistent way. In fact, they should probably omit the traceback which would be very confusing for someone not familiar with Python.

Hugh</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>760</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2006-11-30 15:24:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>OK, Hugh. I see your point. I have improved both, the output of the script. I have also added an additional check to handle this missing parameter name.

But in general it&#39;s not possible to handle each error with a nice message, because there could be more internal stuff like missing attributes etc. In these cases the script throws the exception - in all other cases it will try to print out something more informative.

Revision: 5004.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>