<bug>
          <bug_id>2411</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-05-25 11:19:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Report e-mails are too large</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2009-05-25 12:17:54 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>contrib</product>
          <component>Simulator</component>
          <version>1.0</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10089</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-25 11:19:14 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>smtp.1und1.de seems to have a limit of 500 lines per message. Currently, one of the Playground samples logs a deprecation warning with a large stack trace, preventing the Playground test report e-mail from being sent since there are between five and seven test runs per report and each lists the full log output. This could probably be fixed easily by only logging warnings and errors, ignoring info messages such as the stack trace,

However, other test reports could also exceed the 500 line limit so a more general approach is necessary. logFormatter could check the length of the report file and send it as an attachment if it&#39;s too long. The problem here is that the SMTP server seems to insert line breaks after a set amount of characters in addition to the regular mail headers, so the sent file has more lines than the generated report.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10091</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-25 11:55:50 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Info messages (i.e. the stack trace) are now excluded from the Playground report.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10092</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-25 12:17:54 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Drastically reduced the amount of lines in the report by optimizing the CSS and removing line breaks in logFormatter.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>