<bug>
          <bug_id>2424</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-05-26 18:38:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>table column visibility menu is partially obscured; rendered in wrong place</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:23:11 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.table</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.0-beta1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</assigned_to>
          <cc>qooxdoo-bugs</cc>
    
    <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10142</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-26 18:38:33 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The first time the table column visibility menu (top-right button) is requested, it renders partially off the right side of the table, so only the checkmarks are visible, not the column names. Closing that menu and re-opening it renders the menu in the correct location.

This problem began with r19241 but I&#39;m not currently seeing how that change would affect the rendering location.

To see the bug in action, try this in a post-r19241 playground:

var tableModel= new qx.ui.table.model.Simple();
tableModel.setColumns([ &quot;ID&quot;, &quot;A number&quot;, &quot;A date&quot;, &quot;Boolean&quot; ]);
var table =  this._table = new qx.ui.table.Table();
table.setTableModel(tableModel);
this.getRoot().add(table, { edge : 10 } );

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10145</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2009-05-26 19:01:37 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>All right, it makes a bit of sense. The menu isn&#39;t being created until the &quot;appear&quot; event, so it requires re-rendering. Such a thing has worked consistently in the past, so it seems something&#39;s changed. I tried, however, replacing this:
        menu.addListener(&quot;appear&quot;, this._initColumnMenu, this);

with this, to hopefully generate the menu before actually rendering it:
        control.addListener(&quot;activate&quot;, this._initColumnMenu, this);

but got the same results.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12104</commentid>
            <who name="Dave Baggett">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-09 23:40:07 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I can add some fuel to the fire. Using r20075 and earlier (not sure how far back -- at least a month), my column visibility menus have been missing entirely. I&#39;ve traced this to code in Table.js, in _createChildControlImpl. Under the &quot;column-button&quot; case, it adds the &quot;appear&quot; listener Darrell mentions below. Except that for me, it doesn&#39;t: I can put an alert(...) in that callback and it never shows up! Very strangely, however, if I go into columnmenu/Button.js and add code to hook the listener there (and have it call table._initColumnMenu, which is all that Table is adding the &quot;appear&quot; listener to do), it works!

So something is happening to prevent the addListener call in Table.js from having any effect.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12105</commentid>
            <who name="Dave Baggett">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-09 23:46:57 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>BTW, now that I&#39;ve gotten the &quot;appear&quot; callback to actually fire via my little hack, I get the same offsetting behavior Darrell reports here -- only checkboxes the first time the menu is created. So I suppose my problem may be only vaguely related.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13003</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-08 14:40:59 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>My recent work on menu placement and scrolling has fixed this issue. Now it is possible to modify a visible menu. The menu will be moved into view if this causes parts of the menu to be rendered outside of the viewport.

fixed in r20302</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14506</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-24 20:15:07 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>mass renaming of 0.9 target to 1.0-beta1</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>15788</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-12-14 10:12:33 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>*** Bug 3160 has been marked as a duplicate of this bug. ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37919</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:23:11 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>