<bug>
          <bug_id>2448</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-06-02 16:41:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>per-user configuration file for create-application</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:46:26 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool</component>
          <version>0.8.2</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P5</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10256</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2009-06-02 16:41:56 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>In conjunction with the additions to create-application mentioned in bug #2354, it would be really nice to have a per-user configuration file for create-application. The *nix convention would be to have a file called ~/.qooxdoorc or ~/.qooxdoo/config. This file would provide defaults, if so desired by the user, for use by each invocation of create-application. Entries in this configuration file could include the default cache directory, the default setting of the &quot;quiet&quot; flag (-q), a new &quot;silent&quot; flag meaning don&#39;t go into interactive mode as described in #2354 but rather take all defaults from this configuration file with fallback to base.json, etc. The file could likely be in config.json format, and include any data typically found there that is not application-specific.

It would be nice to find a &quot;standard&quot; place to put this file under Windows as well. Windows doesn&#39;t have the concept of &#39;~&#39; for a home directory, but it does have per-user directories. An option for the location of this file on Windows is &quot;%User\My Documents\qooxdoo\config&quot;. An other option, of course, is the registry, but that&#39;s playing in the dark arts and is thus often considered evil.

create-application should read the configuration file described herein before generating any output, to handle the &quot;quiet&quot; and &quot;silent&quot; options. 

Command line options to create-application should take precedence over those in the configuration file, so would typically be parsed after reading the configuration file. The only caveat is that the new command line option &quot;--config-file=/path/to/file&quot; should be parsed early and the specified file used instead of the default one if that option is provided on the command line. This new command line option may in fact be the reliable method of using the configuration file on Windows if no appropriate default location for the configuration file can be found.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10257</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2009-06-02 17:09:59 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>to me. removed dependency to bug#2354. although there might be some information 
in there that is interesting for this bug, i think they are solvable 
independently.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35529</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:46:26 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>