<bug>
          <bug_id>2449</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-06-02 18:30:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Add Location and Filename to Examples in qooxdoo Documentation</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-02-17 18:53:17 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>documentation.manual</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://qooxdoo.org/documentation/0.8/ui_custom_themes</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Gene Amtower">gene</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Gene Amtower">gene</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10258</commentid>
            <who name="Gene Amtower">gene</who>
            <bug_when>2009-06-02 18:30:28 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The embedded example code within the online docs could be more helpful if it described a typical folder location and filename that would include the example code.  This way, readers of the documentation would understand where in their project folders or qooxdoo application folders that particular example file would be added or modified.  This could apply to the config files, theme files, image files, and code files throughout the documentation.

It appears that you&#39;ve already adopted a consistent example project name &#39;myApplication&#39; in these examples.  As an example, this would suggest adding a notation for the filename in the example on &quot;Extending Themes&quot; in &quot;Custom Themes&quot; [URL provided above] as &quot;/myApplication/source/class/myApplication/theme/Appearance.js&quot;, so that the reader would have a better understanding on how to start implementing custom themes in their own projects.

Other examples throughout the documentation would benefit from this same approach, directing the user to the appropriate location and filename for that example.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10299</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-06-08 11:51:46 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Gene, I absolutely agree with you. Are you willing to take this task?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10306</commentid>
            <who name="Gene Amtower">gene</who>
            <bug_when>2009-06-08 13:44:50 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Oh, boy!  From the frying pan into the fire!  

Sounds like a great way for me to study the examples in much greater detail, giving me some much needed education in Qooxdoo.

Since I&#39;m new to the documentation, do you have a format you think I should use for this new documentation feature?  Maybe if you mark one up the way you want it to look, I can expand that to all of the examples throughout the documentation.  Or, if you have another piece of documentation that you think will look appropriate for this, I could base it on something else in the current wiki docs.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10313</commentid>
            <who name="Gene Amtower">gene</who>
            <bug_when>2009-06-08 17:07:12 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thought &quot;Accepting&quot; the bug would automagically add my email to the &quot;Assigned To&quot; field - not so, so I&#39;m adding it now.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35111</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2014-02-17 18:53:17 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed outdated issue as wontfix, as bug became stale without feedback from assignee.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>