<bug>
          <bug_id>2582</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-07-13 14:52:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Creating AppCache compatible manifest file during build</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:47:43 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Sebastian Werner">info</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10870</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-07-13 14:52:30 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>It would be nice if the generator could create HTML5 AppCache compatible manifest files for using in applications. This dramatically improves performance of mobile applications and may also help to realize desktop widgets.

I opened this bug to have a brain dump of my current ideas archived on the net :) Sorry, when this is too detailed for your preference.

The idea is to list files which may be cached in a file which is send with mimetype &quot;text/cache-manifest&quot;. The file will be referenced in the HTML file via a attribute in the HTML tag e.g.:

&lt;html xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot; xml:lang=&quot;en&quot; manifest=&quot;/mobile.manifest&quot;&gt;

The paths may be relative. The file could contain all files from the resource folder of the &quot;build&quot; directory including the top level HTML file(s).

One neat trick published by Google adds a comment line with a time stamp on every change of the resource folder. This might also be supported by the qooxdoo generator. This however needs some understanding of the status of the files. The idea is to update the time stamp and manifest everytime the contents of the original folders have changed (newer modification date) etc. It is highly important to not change the files contents or timestamp when there were no files modified. Otherwise the client reloads all files at the next time.

Though one issue might problematic in qooxdoo as the JS files changes all the day... so it might not make sense to spend to much time to the resource folder logic.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36002</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:47:43 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>