<bug>
          <bug_id>26</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2006-06-07 14:55:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Add support for tooltiptext</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:24:56 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.8.3</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Sebastian Werner">info</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</assigned_to>
          <cc>daniel.titze</cc>
    
    <cc>mngo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2006-06-07 14:55:32 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Add a new property tooltiptext (could be HTML or text) which will be used, if configured, for a shared tooltip between all widgets. This would reduce the amount of tooltips needed to create.

Maybe this is also possible for icons inside tooltips? Or other complex things.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1124</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2007-03-28 17:05:55 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>fixed in TRUNK with revision #7063</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1125</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2007-03-28 17:06:46 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>sorry, wrong bug report</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>3818</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-07-11 14:57:17 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Moved enhancement out of 0.8</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5138</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-03 20:17:43 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Long grown priorities normalized to P5 to increase a few of them afterwards.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8393</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-09 11:41:00 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>to 0.9. Also see bug #1876 for tooltip related improvements.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8423</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-09 14:32:44 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>to me</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8441</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-09 16:26:01 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>fixed in rev. 18374</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8457</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-10 09:37:42 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Is is really needed to have tooltipicon as well? It may be done with appearance already and this can be easily modified in the theme of the application.

I also think that the original &quot;tooltip&quot; property should maybe made &quot;deprecated&quot; as the preferred way is to use tooltiptext now instead.

In normal applications all tooltips looks the same, so it might be also OK, to just offer exactly one tooltip property which is always text only and always uses a shared tooltip instance.

Would be interested what other GUI related frameworks do here.

Reopened as this is an issue with the new API (we now support 3 types of properties instead of only one which is quite confusing)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8465</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-10 10:47:57 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>We now support toe ways of working with tooltips:

1. The simple way. Just set the tooltip text and/or icon. This will use a shared tooltip instance. If we want to enable the user to specify a tooltip icon we absolutely need this property. This is something, which needs to be set on a per widget basis and thus cannot be specified in a theme.
2. The customizable way. Set your own custom tooltip instance e.g. with a different open/close interval or use a different tooltip class using the &quot;tooltip&quot; property.

I think we need to support both that&#39;s why we have both APIs. </thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8467</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-10 11:18:14 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Maybe we can still talk about the thing as it is far from perfect in my opinion. I would say that we are thinking the same, in that the best usage pattern is that every tooltip in a application is shared. So the best way to use tooltips is through the usage of &quot;tooltipText&quot; regarding efficiency and code readability. I hope you are with me on this.

Other than that one would like to offer options to control the styling of a tooltip and I would say that the icon displayed is part of the styling - the same like the colors or the decoration of the tooltip which is also not propagated to the widget.

In my opinion it would be best to

* add a new &quot;tooltipAppearance&quot; property
* remove the newly introduced &quot;tooltipIcon&quot; property
* deprecate the old &quot;tooltip&quot; property

With these changes it is possible to always use shared instances even with different styles and behavior (timeouts are theme-controlable as well!). You will have infact a tooltip instane for each &quot;tooltipAppearance&quot; value you use in the application. This is quite efficient and not that easy possible with the current implementation.

This way one could have simple text tooltips as well as big rounded corner info bubbles with a nice &quot;info&quot; icon in them.

Sorry for reopen it again.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8496</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-11 10:20:26 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>You are right, I think we can agree that most of the time only a toolTipText is required and that we should reduce the number of instances where possible.

My rationale for the toolTipIcon is that it depends on the context just as much as the text. In the messenger demo the tooltip icon may be the online status or in the test runner an icon, which indicates whether a test was successful. This cannot be done with an appearance theme.

Regarding the toolTip property, I don&#39;t think that we should remove it. The new properties can&#39;t entirely replace the functionality of this property even with the added &quot;tooltipAppearance&quot; appearance property. 

Your idea with the toolTipAppearance however is interesting. But in my approach we would then have four tooltip properties.

</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>8546</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-03-12 11:26:04 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>What would also be great is something like tooltipClass to use custom classes (which may be derivates of the original class) for tooltips. There may be cases where a tooltip pattern is used to show more information than displayable in a single line of simple text.

With &quot;tooltipClass&quot; in place there wouldn&#39;t be any need anymore for the &quot;tooltipAppearance&quot; property as this could be solved through inheritance in this case.

All other things configurable at the tooltip instance may also be done in the constructor of a custom class. This way &quot;tooltipClass&quot; may also be used to deprecate &quot;tooltip&quot;. Even previously there were only some edge cases where &quot;tooltipAppearance&quot; wasn&#39;t yet enough, but with tooltipClass in place I think that the legacy &quot;tooltip&quot; property can finally be removed.

Not sure if one really needs to support tooltipIcon in this case as it might be possible to control the icon through another property when dealing with a custom tooltip class e.g. a userStatus property instead of the hard-core icon property makes more sense in cases of a available/online/away icon for IMs.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9218</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-09 09:46:11 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closing this bug since the issue is fixed and I&#39;m happy with the current solution. If you still want to change the API please raise it as a new bug.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9228</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-09 10:31:27 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Done: Bug #2227</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>38572</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:24:56 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>