<bug>
          <bug_id>2602</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-07-17 17:19:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Textfield keypress events stop firing after all characters selected by &#39;swiping&#39; across them.</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:26:53 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.form</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>IE</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P1</priority>
          <bug_severity>major</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.8.3</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Raymond Cote">rgacote</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</assigned_to>
          <cc>carsten.lergenmueller</cc>
    
    <cc>rgacote</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Internet Explorer</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10960</commentid>
            <who name="Raymond Cote">rgacote</who>
            <bug_when>2009-07-17 17:19:24 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This is with 0.8.2 trunk:

See http://bugzilla.qooxdoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=2600 for additional odd selection behavior.

Create a text field with some data:
      this.quantifyText = new qx.ui.form.TextField();
      this.quantifyText.setValue(&quot;abcdefg&quot;);

Add a keypress listener:
(note, original code that triggered problem was filtering the key presses, so I know the act of popping up an alert is not part of this problem. Alert provided only for code sample.)

      this.quantifyText.addListener(&quot;keypress&quot;, function(e)
      {
          alert(&#39;keypress&#39;);
      }, this);

With IE8, the keypress listener is not being triggered when the text in the field is selected by clicking and swiping across the text. 

Example:
Set focus outside text field before each of the following tests:
 - Click inside text field; type a character--keypress fires.
 - Double-click inside text field to select everything; type a character--keypress fires.

In following, &#39;swipe&#39; means to move the mouse to select characters to left or right of insertion point and then mouse-up.
 - Mouse-down to right of all text in field, swipe to the left to select all characters; type a character -- keypress _does not_ fire.
 - Mouse-down to left of all text in field, swipe to the right to select all characters; type a character -- keypress _does not_ fire.
 - After either of the above two events, just click in the middle of the text string you&#39;ve entered and keypress begins firing again. 

Repeat the above test, but this time do not select all the characters, keypress will filre.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10961</commentid>
            <who name="Raymond Cote">rgacote</who>
            <bug_when>2009-07-17 17:22:40 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>----
Further testing indicates how we select the first character also affects keypress event.
 - Have several characters in the field. 
 - Click to the right of the first character. 
 - Swipe to the left to select just the first character. 
 - mouse up.
 - Type a character -- keypress does not fire. 

However, if you repeat the above by clicking to the left of the first character, swiping to the right, and then typing a character, the keypress event does fire. 
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>10984</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-07-21 12:10:56 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>to Chris (please talk to Fabian and Alex as they might have some valuable input here)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>11921</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-07 14:13:10 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Accepted.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>11923</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-07 15:16:21 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>All IE has this issue -&gt; increased severity

It seems to me that the &quot;keypress&quot; events doesn&#39;t occur if the mouse up event doesn&#39;t occur on the TextField. I mean, if I select the text and the mouse pointer is in the TextField -&gt; the &quot;keypress&quot; events occur. But if I select the text and the mouse pointer is out of the TextField -&gt; no &quot;keypress&quot; events occur!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>11929</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-07 17:16:01 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed in trunk with r20011.

Raymond Cote, could you please verify, that the fix is also working for you and set the sate to &quot;verified&quot; when it works. Thanks! </thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12429</commentid>
            <who name="Raymond Cote">rgacote</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-18 23:48:25 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Confirmed.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12435</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-21 09:13:02 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Close.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14058</commentid>
            <who name="Carsten Lergenmüller">carsten.lergenmueller</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-11 17:37:13 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Reopen, this is not completely fixed yet.

1) The same problem occurs in TextAreas, not only TextFields. The fix in qx.event.handler.Focus.__onNativeMouseUp only works for textfield elements, not text areas.

2) The same problem occurs in Safari 4 Win, but the fix only deals with IE.

3) Why does mouse UP change the focus at all? This is different to all UI systems I know. The fix for this bug is specific to text fields and soon maybe text areas, but what about the other widgets? Tables can have selections..., trees support drags.... is it possible that whenever the selecting / dragging ends outside of the widget the keyboard focus is lost?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14062</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-11 18:27:55 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed for TextFields and TextAreas (IE/Safari).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14064</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-11 18:45:37 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Addition to last comment: Fixed on trunk with rev. 20606.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14156</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-17 15:40:59 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fabian, could you please have a look at comment #8 3). Perhaps this is a general issue on the focus implementation.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>15065</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-30 11:36:42 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>&gt; 3) Why does mouse UP change the focus at all? This is different to all UI
&gt; systems I know. The fix for this bug is specific to text fields and soon maybe
&gt; text areas, but what about the other widgets? Tables can have selections...,
&gt; trees support drags.... is it possible that whenever the selecting / dragging
&gt; ends outside of the widget the keyboard focus is lost?

Mouseup does not change the focus. The focus is changed on mouse down. On mouse up the target element is activated (i.e. it becomes the new target for key events). IMHO this should not be a problem for other widgets.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>39270</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:26:53 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>