<bug>
          <bug_id>2689</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-08-17 15:27:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>HTML5: use native &quot;datagrid&quot; implementations whenever available to enhance widget implementations</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-04-25 10:52:56 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.layout</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>INVALID</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://www.w3.org/TR/html5/interactive-elements.html#datagrid</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P5</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>11369</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2009-08-17 15:27:10 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>«The datagrid element represents an interactive representation of tree, list, or tabular data.» (bug&#39;s URL)

I haven&#39;t yet checked if there are already any native implementation of this HTML5 element, but whenever this element is native in some implementations it would be great using it to improve the implementations of existing widgets (somehow like bug 1400 to use native JSON support whenever available).

This issue was created in the sense of tracking this element&#39;s support across implementations and/or to serve as a placeholder for patches whenever it is ready.

I&#39;ve created it using the &quot;ui-misc&quot; as there was no way to attach this issue to the &quot;ui-tree&quot;, &quot;ui-list&quot; and &quot;ui-table&quot; components. I&#39;ve set it to the &quot;trunk&quot; in the sense that, whenever available, this will probably never be back-ported (as it would involve a tremendous effort).

Finally, I&#39;ve seen bug 2582 which is also HTML5-centric. Should an &quot;HTML5 tracking bug&quot; be created in order to set dependencies for what will likely be a new set of issues like this one? ;-)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29268</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2012-04-25 10:52:56 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>While reviewing the status for this, my suspicions were confirmed: &quot;The datagrid element was removed from HTML5 a long time ago.&quot; [1], which in turn makes a reference to the original WHATWG blog [2] to support the statement.

Closing as invalid in the sense that no support from specifications means no support from browser vendors therefore it doesn&#39;t make sense for a framework to keep holding for broad support to make use of it. (Maybe &quot;resolved later&quot; would be appropriate in the sense that, maybe, one day a native implementation will be proposed again.)

[1] http://stackoverflow.com/questions/9967043/how-to-use-datagrid-in-html5
[2] http://blog.whatwg.org/tag/datagrid#gone</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>