<bug>
          <bug_id>2775</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-09-10 11:28:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Add support for build-system date flags for caching</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:45:46 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P5</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Sebastian Werner">info</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12124</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-10 11:28:03 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>One common pattern when hosting rich internet applications is to store the files in a specific date-dependend directory e.g. 2008-12-03_08-00-03. It might be useful to directly offer such a storing mode in the generator of qooxdoo. Currently all scripts are generated to &quot;script&quot; and all resources to &quot;resource&quot;. When finally putting this stuff on a server one needs to manually manage this stuff.

This might to work well in conjunction with other enhancements of the generator:
* better load script with supports for variants, languages, etc. (which can then support these date stuff, too)
* generation of a HTML5 manifest file in the date-specific folder

GWT&#39;s loading idea might be helpful here to adapt.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12129</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-09-10 12:40:50 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Marked as enhancement. It might be quite a task (to offer that generically in the framework), since different strategies have to be considered (think of MD5 checksums often being superior to time stamps), and adoption to existing deployment systems via config should be possible.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35287</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:45:46 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>