<bug>
          <bug_id>279</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2007-02-01 09:33:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>FontObject isn&#39;t implemented correctly.</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2007-05-04 10:26:41 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>0.6.5</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>862</commentid>
            <who name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</who>
            <bug_when>2007-02-01 09:33:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I tried using a FontObject. Setting a new size for it didn&#39;t change the size of the label, even though I had called addListenerWidget.

Looking at the code shows that _modifySize etc methods are needed, to call the _sync method.

The _sync method itself has been copied from Border and retains the &quot;vEdge&quot; parameter from there, even though it is meaningless.

Another thing: I applied the font object to the label through a customised theme. I would have hoped that addListenerWidget would be called automatically so that I didn&#39;t have do it manually. You can see this in the BorderObject and Border classes - widget._modifyBorder calls addListenerWidget() even though the object might be a Border. Border defines a stub for this function.

I note that BorderObject is broken in that if the widget is removed, a reference to it is left in the listener widget (the only place that removeListenerWidget is called is when changing the border).

You could de-register the widget automatically by adding a call removeListenerWidget in Widget.dispose(). You would have to do that for any object that might be a *Object e.g. Borders, Fonts.

See also issue 38.

Hugh</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1226</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2007-05-04 10:26:41 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>font themes and changing fonts on the fly is now supported in the 0.7 branch</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>