<bug>
          <bug_id>288</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2007-02-12 17:54:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Setting resizeable false on a window prevents maximization</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-05-16 09:43:01 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop</component>
          <version>0.6.5</version>
          <rep_platform>Firefox 2.0</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>INVALID</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Ralf Sternberg">rsternberg</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Firefox</cf_browser>
          <cf_browser_version>2</cf_browser_version>

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>881</commentid>
            <who name="Ralf Sternberg">rsternberg</who>
            <bug_when>2007-02-12 17:54:49 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>When the property &quot;resizable&quot; is set to false on a qx.ui.window.Window, the maximize button is grayed out and the window cannot be maximized --- even though &quot;allowMaximize&quot; is true.
I consider this behavior a bug, not a feature, firstly because it differs from common window managers, and secondly because a seperate property &quot;allowMaximize&quot; exists to control permission to maximize a window.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>883</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2007-02-13 09:45:22 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>This was meant as a feature, because it generally make no sense to maximize a unresizable window. Windows(TM) does not allow this, too (e.g. modal dialogs)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>915</commentid>
            <who name="Ralf Sternberg">rsternberg</who>
            <bug_when>2007-02-18 11:30:29 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I agree that it does make some sense to prevent the maximization of an unresizable window. In fact, the KDE window manager does not allow this. But with regard to Windows, you&#39;re wrong:

On Windows, a window can be maximizable without being resizable. The Windows API (at least XP, not sure about other versions) does not prevent maximization when a window is not resizable. Using SWT on Win32, a window can be created that shows exactly this behavior (wit only the style flag MAX).

The &quot;modal dialogs&quot; example does not proof your point, because dialog windows (modal or not) are usually neither resizable nor maximizable - this does not mean that every window that is not resizable is automatically not maximizable.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>