<bug>
          <bug_id>289</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2007-02-13 09:41:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>TreeFolder of TreeFullControl expands when clicked in any part</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:19:48 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.tree</component>
          <version>0.6.5</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WORKSFORME</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>minor</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.7.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Rüdiger Herrmann">rherrmann</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>882</commentid>
            <who name="Rüdiger Herrmann">rherrmann</who>
            <bug_when>2007-02-13 09:41:17 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Clicking on any part of a TreeFolder expands it, even if it were a check box.
A TreeFolder should only expand when its plus-sign was clicked.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>892</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2007-02-13 19:29:06 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>There are no plans, as far as I know, to modify Tree and TreeFullControl with this feature.  If you&#39;re willing to use a yet experimental class, TreeVirtual already supports this feature.  Note that TreeVirtual is still undergoing some development, so it&#39;s possible you may have to deal with some interface changes if you do choose to use it at this time.  It&#39;s becoming quite stable, however, and you&#39;re certainly welcome to use it.  (If you have many items in your tree, it&#39;s also a VERY lot faster to render them.)

I&#39;ll leave this ticket open, but I&#39;m changing it to an Enhancement Request.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>897</commentid>
            <who name="Rüdiger Herrmann">rherrmann</who>
            <bug_when>2007-02-14 17:38:22 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I still wouldn&#39;t consider this a feature.
All major widget toolkits like Qt, GTK, Win32, Swing, ... behave as mentioned in the bug report (don&#39;t expand except when plus is clicked).
As I understand qooxdoo strives to bring the comfort of a desktop application to the web browser. In this sense I consider it a bug if qooxdoo doesn&#39;t allow the programmer to build UI&#39;s that behave like desktop applications as close as possible.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>898</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2007-02-14 22:25:25 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>You should be able to prevent a TreeFolder from expanding upon a single click other than on the open/close button and indentation area, by setting tree.useDoubleClick(true).  This should give you the &quot;major widget&quot;-style effect.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1867</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2007-07-06 17:17:02 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Seems to be cleard in the discussion.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36635</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:19:48 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>