<bug>
          <bug_id>2892</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-10-06 07:15:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Mouse cursor changing needs too much CPU and sometimes it&#39;s inaccurate for splitpanes</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2010-11-08 09:09:32 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.panes</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          <keywords>Performance</keywords>
          <priority>P1</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.3</target_milestone>
          <dependson>3990</dependson>
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Petr Kobalíček">kobalicek.petr</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12876</commentid>
            <who name="Petr Kobalíček">kobalicek.petr</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-06 07:15:09 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Reproducing:

Open demobrowser, open all items in left treebox then go to the center of split pane (between tree and demos). There is noticeable time between mouse cursor is changed to &quot;horizontal-split&quot; one (cpu=100%) and when you go out of this pane (go in left direction to near scrollbar) there is also noticeable time (see cpu meter) and mouse cursor is not changed back, you must do another move. Noticeable delay is for me 2 seconds (I&#39;m have CQuad 2.4GHz). I think that there is something very inefficient in mouse cursor handling or mouse handling. The slowdown is increased when more DOM nodes are created, so I think that the algorithm used traverses entire document (or container).

This is always reproducible, on slower computers the time is bigger.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12883</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-06 13:26:18 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>It is indeed not trivial to determine the correct cursor in a (complex) UI. AFAIK it also depends on the browsers and OS used. What combinations did you try? And were the browsers affected differently?
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12889</commentid>
            <who name="Petr Kobalíček">kobalicek.petr</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-06 14:52:10 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I think that this is not browser specific. I can reproduce this in Firefox 3.5 (under both, Windows and Linux) and just tried this with Chromium (under Linux). I can try it in Opera and IE under Windows, but I think that it will be the same.

Can you reproduce this issue in Firefox?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12890</commentid>
            <who name="Petr Kobalíček">kobalicek.petr</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-06 14:57:50 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Andreas, just small note.

I know that it&#39;s not trivial, but I&#39;m talking about too much time and in this time the browser hangs. This issue I&#39;m talking about is here from first qooxdoo 0.8 version and I though that it&#39;s known (but probably it&#39;s not). Because it&#39;s still here I decided to report it.

If my description is not clear, please tell me. I can write better reproducing manual (or maybe I could make screencast, but I never did something like that:) )
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12894</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-06 16:46:12 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This certainly is something that needs to be addressed, so thanks for bringing up this issue (again?). It might not have been resolved sufficiently in the past, but it should now.

@Fabian, to you after our brief discussion.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12895</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-06 16:47:19 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Some related bugs: bug #487, bug #1300, bug #938</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12896</commentid>
            <who name="Petr Kobalíček">kobalicek.petr</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-06 16:56:45 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Many thanks for checking this:) This is for me most important bug I filled today:)

If this won&#39;t be fixable it&#39;d like to see some property to disable cursor handling at all, because it&#39;s noticable in my dev-machine and customers have more old ones than me.

Best regards
- Petr</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>12934</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-07 15:33:15 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>We have already disabled global cursor support for IE because this wasn&#39;t acceptable. We should grep over the framework code base and replace all uses of global cursor with better alternatives. For windows and splitter we could e.g. overlay the screen temporarily with a blocker with the corresponding cursor. That&#39;s not an easy change but it should be fixed before 1.0.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>16497</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2010-01-27 16:30:48 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>moved to target 1.0.2</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>17276</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-03-17 11:28:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>to Martin</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>17893</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-04-21 10:44:57 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Sadly, I can&#39;t get that done before 1.1 --&gt; moved to 1.2.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19424</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-07-26 17:22:03 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I think thats a big topic we should take care of in a whole and rethinking the mouse cursor handling. This takes some time --&gt; 1.3</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20471</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-04 15:54:55 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>As I took some time to check out the general cursor handling, this seems to be a problem of the split pane in general because it checks if the mouse is near to change the cursor. Seems like this &quot;checking&quot; takes up all the time! Will investigate here a bit more.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20502</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-06 08:50:40 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Completely reimplemented the cursor handling of the split-pane based on a blocker upon the splitter / slider of the split-pane. This way, the cursor handling can be done bye CSS and we don&#39;t need to do massive distance calculation anymore. I hope I included all the features were in before!

trunk: r23452, r23453</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>