<bug>
          <bug_id>2924</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-10-13 12:40:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Logging problem causes test run to abort</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:24:40 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.test.automation</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>major</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.0-beta1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13157</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-13 12:40:51 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>In the r20337 Playground, the &quot;Dialog&quot; sample causes an alert box with an error message to pop up. In German versions of Internet Explorer, this message contains an umlaut character. Simulation.log() is supposed to filter out any special characters, but in this case the umlaut slips through and ends up in the simulation log file.
While compiling the HTML test report, logFormatter.py tries to write the message to a file handled opened (using codecs.open()) as UTF-8, causing an exception which aborts the entire test run.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13158</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-13 12:41:28 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Set target milestone to 0.9</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13165</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-13 14:48:01 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Even though Simulation.sanitize() filters very aggressively, removing any characters that aren&#39;t alphanumeric or on a short list of allowed special characters, it has no effect on the umlaut. Logging the message to the console shows it as a ³ character, but explicitly checking for that in sanitize() has no effect. This particular string passes several boundaries: IE throws the exception,  the Playground application catches it and calls alert() with it, Selenium captures it (by redefining window.alert) and returns it to the Selenium Java Client Driver, which runs in Rhino. This makes it very hard to debug, so for now converting the simulation log entries to unicode and removing illegal characters before they are written to the report file will have to suffice (r20343).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14637</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-24 20:16:15 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>mass renaming of 0.9 target to 1.0-beta1</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>38471</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:24:40 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>