<bug>
          <bug_id>2954</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-10-19 16:42:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>HtmlArea should never set bold/italic/... styles to P element, instead SPAN should be used</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2009-12-09 17:15:56 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>contrib</product>
          <component>HtmlArea</component>
          <version>trunk</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>INVALID</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Petr Kobalíček">kobalicek.petr</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13313</commentid>
            <who name="Petr Kobalíček">kobalicek.petr</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-19 16:42:00 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>HtmlArea should never set bold/italic/... styles to P element, instead SPAN should be used.

Deproduce:

Create HtmlArea widget, write some text, select all the text using mouse, turn text to bold. Html output will be something like this:

&lt;p style=&quot;font-weight:bold;&quot;&gt;aa&lt;/p&gt;

it should be:

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight:bold;&quot;&gt;aa&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13319</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-19 17:32:17 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This is not under control of the HtmlArea component. When executing e.g. the &quot;bold&quot; command the control is handed over to the browser.

The generated output is the current content produced by the browser. There is no possibility to fix this.

-&gt; INVALID</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13323</commentid>
            <who name="Petr Kobalíček">kobalicek.petr</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-19 17:41:55 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>But other editors (tinymce, fckeditor) handles this nicely. There is problem that if styles gets into &lt;p&gt; tag then toggling this style inside this paragraph causes troubles. Try to play with it one minute and you should see all problems connected to this behavior (invalid formats, html output you never want, etc).

I think that introducing some methods that can correct these mistakes created by the browser isn&#39;t bad idea. Google chrome for example creates DIVs instead of P elements (this was just example), so how the output can be unified without some correction methods? (other editors can do that).

I know that html editing is complex and I understand why this component is in contrib :)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13325</commentid>
            <who name="Petr Kobalíček">kobalicek.petr</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-19 17:52:49 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Alex,

I will try to figure this myself, I send mail into mailing list and maybe some person here can also help:)

Don&#39;t worry about your time, I know that it&#39;s problem to work on contribs.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13328</commentid>
            <who name="Petr Kobalíček">kobalicek.petr</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-19 18:30:25 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Alex,

When you get some free time, can you provide me some help with fixing this issue ? For example I don&#39;t need how is the proper way to get information that style was set to bold and how elements were affected by it.

I think that if there will be some pluggable mechanism of postprocessing browser changes then there will not be problem. I can catch everything by this.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13485</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-23 18:23:08 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The most issues should be solvable with Bug #2976 and Bug #2977.
And if the HTML output should be transformed in any way I think it&#39;s better to offer a post-processing interface (as you already mentioned at the mailinglist) to be able to transform the output this way.
Offering such a possibility has two benefits: 

 * Clean way for application developers to post-process
 * HtmlArea is not blown up with code which tries to transform HTML code in the right manner

Especially the second point can&#39;t be achieved by a basic component like HtmlArea is. There are several approaches to transform HTML code afterwards and there are many opinions how clean HTML code look like and many other requirements. 

So creating ONE post-processing mechanism which rules them all is not realistic in my opinion.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>15552</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2009-12-09 17:14:16 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>mark all fixed bugs as VERIFIED</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>15615</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2009-12-09 17:15:56 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Close all verified bugs</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>