<bug>
          <bug_id>2974</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-10-23 15:29:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>It is not posible to enter &lt;tab&gt; into a TextArea</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:46:34 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.form</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P5</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13461</commentid>
            <who name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-23 15:29:15 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Should we allow this (via property) or a key combination? alt/crtl + tab?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13463</commentid>
            <who name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-23 15:32:55 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>There is an extra bug for the HtmlArea, since it might be important to have this feature there: bug #2973.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13466</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-23 16:04:05 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>gmail recently made some changes. It used to be that a tab would always move you from the &quot;compose a message&quot; area to the Send button. As mentioned, this is the common usage, where tab moves focus from field to field. I had some issues with it, and apparently others did as well. When creating a bullet list in a message, for example, being able to use keyboard commands to increase or decrease the list indentation level was not possible.

The solution that gmail came up with, which I&#39;m not fully comfortable with yet and don&#39;t fully understand the algorithm, is that if the text insertion point is in the left-most position (I think), tab increases the indentation level, and if you&#39;re elsewhere, it moves you to the next field (the Send button). I say I&#39;m not yet comfortable with it because there seem to be some other rules that apply. Sometimes it inserts a tab (or multiple spaces, I&#39;m not sure which), while other times it changes the focus.

Once I learn the algorithm, I expect to quite like having the additional keyboard capability. Since this is a brand new (in the past few days) feature, it&#39;s also possible that it&#39;s still a bit buggy. When it stabalizes, or if documentation can be found for how it works, that would be an interesting data point as far as what to implement here.

Derrell
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35583</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:46:34 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>