<bug>
          <bug_id>2993</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-10-27 11:03:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Implement a remote data store</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:48:04 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.databinding</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          <dependson>1897</dependson>
    
    <dependson>3975</dependson>
          <blocked>1527</blocked>
          <votes>1</votes>
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          <cc>b.collignon</cc>
    
    <cc>gradinf</cc>
    
    <cc>simonwhite</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13563</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-27 11:03:57 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>In cases of huge date set like big lists of countries or names, it is necessary that we can load only parts of the data as they were needed. Especially for such scenarios, a remote data store and fitting data types are needed.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19715</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-09 14:50:30 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>We should include</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19723</commentid>
            <who name="Guilherme Krycek">gradinf</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-09 15:37:36 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Do you have any idea how to do it?

I&#39;m curious because the model object is accessed directly by the widgets. And in this case, the model is not complete.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19740</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-09 17:08:13 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I have no detailed picture of it yet but I think we have to make the widget and the data array (most likely a subclass of it) aware of such async accesses like a remote access.

As you might have seen, I plan to take a look at the RPC layer first so could still be some time until we have more details on that.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19741</commentid>
            <who name="Guilherme Krycek">gradinf</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-09 18:32:30 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>&gt; As you might have seen, I plan to take a look at the RPC layer first so could
&gt; still be some time until we have more details on that.

I saw that it depends on the RPC layer but I don&#39;t understand why since it should be independent of such things. Won&#39;t I be able to use that w/o RPC?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19742</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-10 08:01:07 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Well, you need a way to query a subset of data from the server and for that, you need some method call on the server which takes the parameter what is needed and returns the data. So there has to be some kind of call and why not RPC?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19752</commentid>
            <who name="Guilherme Krycek">gradinf</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-10 14:58:20 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #5)
&gt; Well, you need a way to query a subset of data from the server and for that,
&gt; you need some method call on the server which takes the parameter what is
&gt; needed and returns the data. So there has to be some kind of call and why not
&gt; RPC?

Yes, that&#39;s an option and it&#39;s ok to do that. I&#39;m just wanna know if I will be able to use that with simple ajax requests.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19771</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-11 08:27:43 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I try to keep the dependencies as low as possible. But as I said, don&#39;t have any details on that.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26887</commentid>
            <who name="">simonwhite</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-22 17:12:47 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>My thought was that this should not be fully automatic.  I prefer the idea of being able to call a method which triggers the changed items to be sent back to the server.  So if the store is a JSON store I would expect to supply a URL for saving data.  The data would be sent in JSON format in a form POST.

My typical usage scenario would be a master/detail where a list or table would be used to navigate the data.  I would then trigger the save function when changing the selection in the list.  It should also be possible to supply a delegate so that I could build a custom version for saving data.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36126</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:48:04 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>