<bug>
          <bug_id>3007</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-10-29 16:10:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Better loadtime/runtime debug infos / Application Interface Methods</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:46:11 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.application</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Sebastian Werner">info</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13705</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-10-29 16:10:28 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I am currently developing a mobile application based on qooxdoo and I found that the infos of the loadtime etc. are a bit misleading or missing.

* qx.Bootstrap.LOADSTART should be infact better named qx.Bootstrap.EXECSTART as it is the moment the script engines processing the content. It does not include both, the loading time and the parsing time.

* It would be nice to have some info about these two times. Even if combined. To support this one needs a separate info in every HTML. This could automatically be used if available e.g. if (window.HTMLSTART) { qx.Bootstrap.LOADTIME = qx.Bootstrap.EXECSTART - window.HTMLSTART; }

* It would be useful to store the main/finalize runtime infos somewhere in qooxdoo.

* The &quot;finalize&quot; method is still a bit useless. For loading data it&#39;s not appropriate as it blocks other GUI relevant code from loading e.g. sending AJAX requests to load data here is probably a bad idea. So it&#39;s mainly an internal thing of a GUI application to control the rendering but has no usage for the native application developer. I would suggest to remove this method from the interface and from the native application classes.

* One thing one might add instead is a &quot;load&quot; method which might be executed with a timeout so it does not block the other stuff. We use such a method in our application to load data using AJAX with a 200ms offset. The effect is dramatically better than compared to putting that stuff into the &quot;finalize&quot; method. This might also help the API viewer etc. where the tree sometimes is rendered before the images are loaded.

* Not sure if main() is still a good name then, though. It would be more easy to communicate to have something like &quot;setup&quot; -&gt; &quot;ui&quot; -&gt; &quot;load&quot; which means &quot;setup environment&quot; =&gt; &quot;building gui&quot; =&gt; &quot;loading data&quot;. This would perfectly match our requirements here. We have a setup phase which manipulates META-Tags, loads CSS styles etc., a main phase which restores the last state (e.g. parsing history data, cookies, etc.) and a load time where we send AJAX requests to the backend.

If there is interested I can cooperate these changes back into qooxdoo and providing a patch. We need to make sure that it do not break existing code, but with some deprecation things in place this might not be an issue.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35445</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:46:11 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>