<bug>
          <bug_id>3031</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-11-05 11:27:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>create-application.py error substituting the hyphen with underscore</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:19:26 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Linux</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.0-beta1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Riccardo Bianchi">rbianchi</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>13951</commentid>
            <who name="Riccardo Bianchi">rbianchi</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-05 11:27:56 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>When you launch create-application.py with an application name with an hyphen within, the script substitute this hyphen &quot;-&quot; with an underscore &quot;_&quot;, but only for the &quot;application&quot; name field, not for the &quot;name&quot;, for the directory name, and for &lt;title&gt; html tag in index.html.

So for example, if you use &quot;my-app&quot; as application name, you still will get a directory called &quot;my-app&quot; (hyphen) with a &quot;name&quot; field &quot;my-app) (hyphen) in config.json and Manifest.json files and with the same &quot;my-app&quot; string in the generated index.html file. While the &quot;application&quot; name in config.json and Manifest will be set as &quot;my_app&quot; (uderscore).

So you end up with a not-clean installation.

Maybe it would be better to substitute the hyphen with an underscore at the beginning and to use the corrected string for everything: folder, &quot;name&quot;, &lt;title&gt;, &quot;application&quot;.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14025</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-10 14:08:20 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>to Daniel. Is there an inconsistency that causes problems, or is it supposed to be a feature only to rename the problematic names?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14030</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-10 17:24:17 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thomas and I discussed this briefly and came up with the following conclusions:
The application name (used for the root folder, &quot;name&quot; in Manifest.json and &lt;title&gt; in index.html) can differ from the application namespace. Only the namespace needs to be a valid JavaScript identifier. That&#39;s a feature we don&#39;t want to lose. If create-application.py is called with the -n and -s options, it should behave as it does now and only clean up the namespace if necessary, leaving the name alone.
But if the user only specifies the name (-n) and create-application.py uses that to create the namespace identifier, then both could be cleaned up so that everything would be consistently named as suggested in the bug report.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14031</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-10 17:38:27 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed as proposed in my previous comment in r20595.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14676</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-24 20:16:32 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>mass renaming of 0.9 target to 1.0-beta1</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36485</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:19:26 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>