<bug>
          <bug_id>3117</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-11-25 21:42:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>./generate.py build changes permissions</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:19:41 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Linux</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P1</priority>
          <bug_severity>major</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.0</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Fritz Zaucker">fritz.zaucker</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14941</commentid>
            <who name="Fritz Zaucker">fritz.zaucker</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-25 21:42:46 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Running

  generate.py build

from trunk changes the permissions of the build directory to 777 (ugo+rwx). Apart from being annoying (depending on the webserver configuration the webserver will not serve contents from such a directory, fortunately, just a bit difficult to figure out why), this can create a HUGE security hole, depending on what kind of info is stored below the build directory (and it is not unlikely that DB-access code is living there).

Therefore I took the liberty to assign this bug a high priority and severity (if bugzilla will actually allow me to do so upon saving ...).

Cheers,
Fritz

P.S.: Nobody seemed to notice my posting on the mailing list about this topic, at least I didn&#39;t see a reply.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14953</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-25 22:53:26 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>to Thomas

(BTW, are there specific permissions one would expect the build directory to get? Or isn&#39;t this aspect of security/deployment in responsibility of a final deployment manager in a post-generator procedure?)
 </thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14955</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-26 09:24:27 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>&gt; P.S.: Nobody seemed to notice my posting on the mailing list about this 
topic, at least I didn&#39;t see a reply.

This one, dear Fritz, relates to the fact that you habitually post new topics 
as replies to old ones; which then get burried in the old thread; which is then 
easily overlooked, as many follow specific *threads*; as I repeatedly stated on 
the ML :).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14983</commentid>
            <who name="Fritz Zaucker">fritz.zaucker</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-26 18:10:25 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Oh my, Thomas, finally I think I realize what the problem is with my posts. I use old mailing list mails to reply (to get the address) and as my mail client orders threads by subject and not my mail headers as apparently the mailing list server does, I never realized that this creates a problem. Thanks for pointing me into this direction, I&#39;ll try to remember.

Cheers,
Fritz</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14984</commentid>
            <who name="Fritz Zaucker">fritz.zaucker</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-26 18:16:15 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>In reply to Comment #1 by Andreas: I think the generator should NOT make any assumptions about the &#39;proper&#39; permissions of the build directory or any other files/directories it produces. It should be left to the user to setup the permissions (s)he seems fit. If a file/directory already exists, the generator should just leave the permissions alone. If it has to create a file or directory, it should just create it and leave it to the OS to choose the permissions. In Linux/Unix the user&#39;s umask setting will take care of the proper defaults.

At most the generator could point out &#39;mistakes&#39; it thinks the user made. I am not sure what assumptions I could make about other user&#39;s setups, though.

Cheers,
Fritz</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14985</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-26 18:32:52 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #3)
&gt; Oh my, Thomas, finally I think I realize what the problem is with my posts. I 
use old mailing list mails to reply (to get 
&gt; the address) and as my mail client orders threads by subject and not my mail 
headers as apparently the mailing list 
&gt; server does, I never realized that this creates a problem. Thanks for 
pointing me into this direction, I&#39;ll try to remember.

Great. I actually think the list server is completely neutral in this regard, 
it&#39;s really the client that does the ordering. Thunderbird, which I use, and 
maybe others use the &#39;References:&#39; and &#39;In-Reply-To:&#39; headers which track 
message id&#39;s. But then, Thunderbird also inserts the the list address when I 
just type &#39;qo&lt;TAB&gt;&#39;  in the address field, so it&#39;s easy for me to post a new 
message ;-).  Cheers, Thomas</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14986</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-26 18:34:08 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>This bug might be related to bug#2220.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14991</commentid>
            <who name="Fritz Zaucker">fritz.zaucker</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-26 20:49:28 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #5)

&gt; Great. I actually think the list server is completely neutral in this regard, 
&gt; it&#39;s really the client that does the ordering. Thunderbird, which I use, and 
&gt; maybe others use the &#39;References:&#39; and &#39;In-Reply-To:&#39; headers which track 
&gt; message id&#39;s. 

Ah, you used thread-ordering in your mail reader ... and I order my mails by arrival date. And then I also just delete my own mails arriving from the mailing list, after all, I know what I wrote and also have it in the send folder. Thus I never had a chance to see this effect.

&gt; But then, Thunderbird also inserts the the list address when I 
&gt; just type &#39;qo&lt;TAB&gt;&#39;  in the address field, so it&#39;s easy for me to post a new 
&gt; message ;-).  Cheers, Thomas

alpine does too, now that I have bothered to create an alias for the qooxdoo-list ...

Cheers,
Fritz

</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>14992</commentid>
            <who name="Fritz Zaucker">fritz.zaucker</who>
            <bug_when>2009-11-26 20:51:23 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #6)
&gt; This bug might be related to bug#2220.

Ah, I see the source of the problem ... not obivous, what the right solution is (except that chmod 777 certainly isn&#39;t). Perhaps create the target file first (thus using the OS defaults) and then &quot;append&quot; the new file?

Cheers,
Fritz
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>15367</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2009-12-07 14:50:51 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I reverted the -f option used when invoking the robocopy module, but added a 
work-around  to robocopy for copying read-only files in non-force mode. It is 
now still possible to re-copy read-only files (which was the issue of 
bug#2220), but directory perms need not be changed for this.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36588</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:19:41 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>