<bug>
          <bug_id>3156</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-12-02 12:47:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Add mechanism to prefetch images after startup</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:46:27 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          <keywords>Performance</keywords>
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>info</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>15179</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2009-12-02 12:47:07 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>With the use of e.g. decorators for button widgets the images necessary for the hover effect are loaded dynamically. 

If the images are not yet loaded and the browser need to send a request. If the images are not loaded fast enough this can result in an ugly effect showing only e.g. the half of the button decorator completely.

An image prefetching after startup (maybe pending for some seconds) should get all necessary images so the decorators can be switched without any negative effect.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>15322</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-12-05 02:00:36 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Are you think this really is useful? Wouldn&#39;t it be easier to encode all the images to an internal CSS with base64? This still does not work in IE, but would be really cool, for all other browsers.

Over a 3G network we have made some experiments with prefetching and most of it has a negative effect as it is quite hard to manage it right to not produce conflicts with other data which is being loaded.

It should be made sure that this really improves the situation and not add a bunch of negative side-effects. On initial load data is a lot more important than hover images.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>15406</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2009-12-08 11:19:00 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; Are you think this really is useful? Wouldn&#39;t it be easier to encode all the
&gt; images to an internal CSS with base64? This still does not work in IE, but
&gt; would be really cool, for all other browsers.
Thanks for this hint. If we try to implement it like this we need some toolchain support first, but worth a thought. Maybe a special solution for IE is then necessary here.

&gt; Over a 3G network we have made some experiments with prefetching and most of it
&gt; has a negative effect as it is quite hard to manage it right to not produce
&gt; conflicts with other data which is being loaded.
Making prefetching configurable would solve this problem here.

 &gt; It should be made sure that this really improves the situation and not add a
&gt; bunch of negative side-effects. On initial load data is a lot more important
&gt; than hover images.
Adding negative side-effects need to be avoided, yes. 
On the other hand it is really important for the &quot;feel&quot; of a big app. If you hover over a button and some images are not shown correctly because they are still not loaded, this is definetely a thing which need an improvement.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35537</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:46:27 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>