<bug>
          <bug_id>3282</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2009-12-29 14:37:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Implement optional startup method to poll browser security options</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:45:47 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Gene Amtower">gene</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>gene</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>15992</commentid>
            <who name="Gene Amtower">gene</who>
            <bug_when>2009-12-29 14:37:22 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>When a user-initiated action in a Qooxdoo application causes the browser to prompt the user to allow this action, the browser will often reload the application page once the user accepts the action.  This can occur, for instance, when a user initiates a file download that is blocked by a default browser security setting.  In an RIA environment, this can force the entire RIA page to reload, causing the loss of any particular state of the application.  

To avoid this condition, it would be helpful if there was a method available for the developer to &quot;poll&quot; the browser at RIA startup and allow the user to gracefully enable the option and reload the RIA at the very start instead of later when it is disruptive to the user experience.

I&#39;m not sure where this would logically fall in the Qooxdoo framework, but it probably would be a &quot;root&quot; method in qx.ui.root to be called at the start of the application class, before all of the widget creation and UI layout is completed.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35292</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:45:47 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>