<bug>
          <bug_id>3438</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-02-15 10:37:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Class Dependencies are violated by Part Collapsing</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:22:11 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>1.0.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P1</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.0.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>16812</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2010-02-15 10:37:52 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>When merging packages during part collapsing, class dependencies are not 
sufficiently honored. As a result, a package which is loaded earlier for a part 
might contain classes that have a load-dependency on classes in a later 
package. If you cut down merging to a minimum (no size restrictions, no 
expected-load-order), this does not happen in the given case, but happens if 
stronger merge policies are in place. So it&#39;s an issue of the merge process.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>16813</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2010-02-15 10:39:14 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>working on it</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>16854</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2010-02-17 12:56:42 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I said, I&#39;m working on it.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>16935</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2010-02-23 17:56:41 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I implemented two new constraints for merging packages:
- one that prevents a package merge if it would result in a cyclic dependency 
(the receiving package would have a dependency on another package, and this has 
a dependency on the receiving package)
- one that prevents a package merge if the receiving package is available in 
parts where prerequisite packages are not

As these conditions might change with ongoing merging (e.g. a prerequisite 
class might itself be merged into a larger package and its classes are 
therefore available in more parts than before; then the dependent package can 
also be merged), merge runs over a given list of packages are repeated until 
the list stabilizes, i.e. no more merges can be done.

These additional constraints can be toggled by a config key, 
&#39;packages/additional-merge-constraints&#39; (on by default).

The verifier has been enhanced and now checks the following conditions:
- for each class its load dependencies are also in the part
- for each load dependency it is loaded earlier than the class
- all defining classes for that part, as given in the 
&#39;packages/parts/&lt;part_name&gt;/include setting (glob expanded), are in the part 
(sanity check)

I also made the part verifier raise an exception if it finds violations of 
these rules. This behaviour can be toggled with 
&#39;packages/verifier-bombs-on-errors&#39;.

With r21627.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37582</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:22:11 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>