<bug>
          <bug_id>3663</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-04-29 16:19:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Solve mailing list / nabble issues</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-04-03 17:33:25 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>website</product>
          <component>other</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18108</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-04-29 16:19:09 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>We are using the qooxdoo mailing list for long time and we have experienced some issues with it:

1. Sometimes mails do have long delays on delivery. This delay can be up to a couple of hours.

2. Some mails are just lost, they never appear.

3. A couple of users ask new questions attached to old threads which makes it hard to track new questions and / or threads.

4. Nabble allows users to post without being registered on the list. This leads to a mail which is visible on nabble but not on the list itself. But if someone registered writes a reply to that question via nabble, the reply is visible on both sides which leads in most cases to answers without a question! 

5. Some users use a not registered (maybe a second) mail account to post which leads to additional maintenance effort. 

6. If a user has trouble getting the mails from the mailing list (maybe no more space in the inbox) he will be automatically banned. We have to take care of those banned users and check if the problem was temporarily.

7. Nabble does not support a &quot;read&quot; state for threads, answers which makes it hard to track new posts.


To get rid of those issues, we should write a requirement list which contains all the things we want to have for a new system, no matter what it is.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18846</commentid>
            <who name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-21 14:48:33 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>-&gt; Chris</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19718</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-09 15:12:57 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Andreas, is this still an issue we should take care of and waste some time for it?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29048</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2012-04-03 17:33:25 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Seems we gotta live with the current status albeit deficiencies.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>