<bug>
          <bug_id>3670</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-05-03 13:13:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Method insertHtml ignores default font settings in FF 3.6</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-02-28 10:46:56 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>contrib</product>
          <component>HtmlArea</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>Firefox 3.6</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://tinyurl.com/36bj4rq</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Norbert Schröder">qunibert</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</assigned_to>
          <cc>qunibert</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Firefox</cf_browser>
          <cf_browser_version>3.6</cf_browser_version>

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18125</commentid>
            <who name="Norbert Schröder">qunibert</who>
            <bug_when>2010-05-03 13:13:20 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>To reproduce this issue, please open playground application http://tinyurl.com/36bj4rq and try the following steps:

1. Select any sequence of characters in the demo text and press the [insertHtml] button. The selected characters will be set to bold, the default font family and size are preserved ==&gt; everything is ok. Selecting the [HTML source] button reveals that the complete HTML source text is enclosed by a &quot;span&quot; and a &quot;font&quot; tag containing the chosen font settings while the bold selection is enclosed by a &quot;span&quot; with the corresponding CSS style information (&quot;font-weight: bold&quot;).

2. Press the [resetHtml] Button and type some text. You will notice that the default font family and size are reset to some &quot;default&quot; which is definitely not the default having been set on instatiation of the widget ==&gt; maybe ok, maybe not (I&#39;m not quite sure how the &quot;resetHtml&quot; method is supposed to behave). Hitting [HTML source] shows that the enclosing &quot;span&quot; and &quot;font&quot; tags containing the default font settings have disappeared.

3. a) Pressing the [setValue] button results in some different demo content which will be displayed in the originally defined default font family and size ==&gt; looks ok, so far. [HTML source] shows that the enclosing &quot;span&quot; and &quot;font&quot; tags are back again.

3. b) Now select any sequence of characters (as in 1. above) and again press [insertHtml]. While the unselected parts of the text are still displayed in the original default font, the selected sequence turns into the same &quot;pre-default&quot; as above ==&gt; not ok. Press [HTML source] and you will find that the &quot;span&quot; and &quot;font&quot; tags are present, however, they don&#39;t enclose the entire HTML source but only those text sequences which had NOT been selected. It looks as if the insertHtml method &quot;breaks&quot; the default font settings.

4. You might also select the complete text content of the editor and hit the [DEL] key. This results in an empty editor window just as if you had used [resetHtml]. However, if you now type in some text it&#39;s still displayed with the chosen default font settings, just like in step 3. a). Selecting an arbitrary sequence of characters and hitting [insertHtml] again shows the same behaviour as in 3. b).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18130</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-05-03 15:15:16 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>HTML Area --&gt; Johnny</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18816</commentid>
            <who name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-21 14:41:56 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Assigning all HTMLArea bugs to Alex.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35212</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2014-02-25 09:21:12 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Discontinued support for htmlarea in the framework, set all open issues to WONTFIX. Still available as a contribution acc. to bug #7918 .</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>