<bug>
          <bug_id>3690</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-05-07 12:07:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Special events for mouse left and right clicks</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2010-09-20 08:25:34 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.event</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>DUPLICATE</resolution>
          <dup_id>3353</dup_id>
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.3</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Matthias Braun">matthias.braun</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18259</commentid>
            <who name="Matthias Braun">matthias.braun</who>
            <bug_when>2010-05-07 12:07:27 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Currently the &quot;click&quot; event is dispatched for left and right clicking.
If you check the qx.event.type.Mouse.getButton method, you&#39;ll see that for &quot;click&quot; and &quot;dblclick&quot; event the button is always &quot;left&quot;, for &quot;contextmenu&quot;  it is always &quot;right&quot;.

Other mouse events return the &quot;real&quot; button.

My suggestion is to dispatch click and dblclick events only for left clicks, contextmenu only for right clicks (as it already is)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19911</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-19 10:50:53 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Matthias, could you perhaps explain in more details where the problem is? Whats the expected behavior and should we split up the click event?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19915</commentid>
            <who name="Matthias Braun">matthias.braun</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-19 11:10:59 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Sure.

My current problem is, that I want to have several widgets that only react on clicking with the left mouse button and NOT on the right mouse button.

As I described in my first comment, if I use the &quot;click&quot; event, it is dispatched for left AND right mouse button, and the getButton() Method returns always &quot;left&quot;, even if I clicked with the right mouse button.

For the right button, there is a special event &quot;contextmenu&quot;. 

It would be very nice to have an event, that is only dispatched on clicking with the left mouse button (similar to &quot;contextmenu&quot;). If you want to have the &quot;click&quot; event for both buttons, left and right, it would be ok if you invent a new event.

So there could be three events:

&quot;click&quot; for clicking with left OR right mouse button
&quot;contextmenu&quot; for clicking with the right button
&quot;toBeDefined&quot; for clicking the left mouse button

This would result in two events for each mouse click (&quot;click&quot; and the corresponding other event).

Additonally, I would like to have the real mouse button when I call getButton().</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19916</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-19 12:48:55 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>So at first place, it would be ok to get bug #3353 fixed and you can distinguish which button has been clicked?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19917</commentid>
            <who name="Matthias Braun">matthias.braun</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-19 12:56:58 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Yes, that would be great. So I can do a working check in every click handler.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19920</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-19 14:54:38 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>After some investigation, I understand your problem! But its only firefox which
also fires a click event on right clicks which was mapped to a left click by
qooxdoo. 

I mark this but as duplicate of #3353 which is already fixed. Matthias, could
you pleas check if that solution is ok for you?

*** This bug has been marked as a duplicate of bug 3353 ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>