<bug>
          <bug_id>3736</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-05-27 18:52:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Accessibility of resources and configuration for AUT in testrunner</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:24:19 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.dev.testing</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>2.0</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="saaj">id</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18515</commentid>
            <who name="saaj">id</who>
            <bug_when>2010-05-27 18:52:52 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>There&#39;re major flows as i can see:

1) No settings are assigned from config.json to AUT, neither from &quot;common&quot; job, nor from build specific jobs. When i add job &quot;test&quot; with &quot;settings&quot; section to app&#39;s config.json, testrunner breaks by alerting &quot;The selected test file is invalid.&quot; by timeout. I can workaround it by defining these settings in case&#39;s constructor. 

I&#39;ve urls of rpc services my app uses. In &quot;source&quot; version they&#39;re absolute, in build - relative. Also config has cross-domain build specific key. So config.json is good place for it.

2) ${qx.icontheme} is not resolved for my app&#39;s classes so i&#39;ve bunch of lines

  &quot;Empty replacement of macro &#39;qx.icontheme&#39; in asset spec.&quot;

by generator in TEST::TESTRUNNER::BUILD-TESTS section. Its not critical but, in fact, unpleasant because testrunner&#39;s log is also filled with ImageLoader warnings. 

3) Also because of ignorance of application config, some other hard-to-track errors might happen. For example I have had 3 hours of headache trying to find out a reason of error which could be easily be reproduced by

 new qx.ui.treevirtual.TreeVirtual(qx.locale.Manager.tr(&quot;Tree&quot;));   

At the very beginning of project i&#39;m working on testing of, i&#39;ve found out the dynlocale is error prone because qx.locale.LocalizedString is not always correctly treated as string in string-expecting context (e.g. case above), so i&#39;ve had it off in config. But because of ignorance of app config in testrunner i&#39;ve faced this error again.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18522</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-05-28 09:40:34 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Testing issue --&gt; Daniel</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29749</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2012-06-13 16:50:37 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The &quot;tests-common&quot; job now inherits from &quot;common&quot;, meaning that any settings defined for &quot;common&quot; will be applied to the AUT build, including the &quot;qx.icontheme&quot; asset macro.

Fixed with a795b7ba on master.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29828</commentid>
            <who name="saaj">id</who>
            <bug_when>2012-06-17 21:57:27 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&#39;ve made a quick test-source test with 1.6 app and master branch app where I just call main() of application in testcase. I checked for appearance of library icon, environment value from config, generator warnings and application log entries. So 1.6 app fails with both icon and environment value, shows generator warnings and log entries of unmanaged icon. Whereas master branch app is correct against all these criteria.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29836</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2012-06-18 08:59:06 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I consider this an enhancement since no code is broken, which is why I didn&#39;t commit into branch. A simple workaround for 1.6 is to extend &quot;tests-common&quot; locally in the application config:

    &quot;testrunner::tests-common&quot; :
    {
      &quot;extend&quot; : [&quot;common&quot;],
      
      &quot;environment&quot; :
      {
        &quot;qx.application&quot; : &quot;testrunner.TestLoader&quot;
      }
    }</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29838</commentid>
            <who name="saaj">id</who>
            <bug_when>2012-06-18 10:01:55 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>It&#39;s clear about enhancement state. And everything is fine on 1.6 with configuration addition you provided. Thanks.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>38340</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:24:19 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>