<bug>
          <bug_id>3741</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-06-01 13:23:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Testrunner switches to AutoReload mode after first test executed</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2010-08-06 10:54:15 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>app.testrunner</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="saaj">id</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18540</commentid>
            <who name="saaj">id</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-01 13:23:38 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Having a complex application which takes a lot of time to load, its annoying to forget to uncheck this radiobutton, manually, for second test and have an application reloaded.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18562</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-07 09:42:45 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Currently, thats a feature. Daniel, should we rethink / remove this feature?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18574</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-07 15:50:08 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The idea is to make sure the following tests aren&#39;t affected by any undisposed objects from the previous test. But I agree, it&#39;s annoying and I usually turn it off, myself. Chris suggests we could store the checkbox value in a cookie. Thoughts?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18577</commentid>
            <who name="saaj">id</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-07 16:11:24 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I have changed it to false, also, when it has become annoying.

It&#39;s actually unclear because as far as I can see this &quot;reload option&quot; is about AUT iframe reload, while outer app, the runner is not affected by this option, not forced to reload. Of course until you have to reload the testrunner because of changed source dependency. So if radiobutton is off AUT is not reloaded, otherwise if its reloaded. I mean I don&#39;t see the reason to explicitly change user-defined setting after first time.

Obviously, a persistent setting could be a convenience I opt for, but its only related to this issue.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18578</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-07 17:24:58 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>We can&#39;t activate auto reload from the very start (right after the testrunner GUI is loaded) because by then the AUT is already loaded so of course it would be unnecessary to load it again when &quot;run&quot; is clicked. So for the first run, auto reload is always implicitly off, but for any following runs we&#39;d let the cookie decide. 
To avoid confusion we could deactivate/&quot;grey out&quot; the checkbox until after the first test run.

Martin liked the cookie solution as well, so I&#39;ll implement it some time this week.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18579</commentid>
            <who name="saaj">id</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-07 18:05:12 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Yes, this will work out, but when a simple thing, as this switch looks at the first glance, causes complex handling, the question comes whether initial requirements are strict enough... maybe not a question but the feeling.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18580</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-07 19:28:46 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>You&#39;re absolutely right, the entire auto reload mechanism is a kludge. The real solution would be to automagically make sure that all objects created by a test function are disposed after it&#39;s finished. This would prevent &quot;false negatives&quot; and speed up test execution. Unfortunately, this isn&#39;t as easy as it sounds. Martin already spent quite a bit of time on this problem but couldn&#39;t come up with a viable solution.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18593</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-08 15:53:31 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed as described in comment #4 in 22369.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>