<bug>
          <bug_id>375</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2007-04-19 15:18:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Menu needs to be hidden in disposer</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2007-05-24 12:06:35 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>0.6.6</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>INVALID</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1198</commentid>
            <who name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</who>
            <bug_when>2007-04-19 15:18:23 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I had a situation on IE7 where a context menu could be left hanging around after destruction. That then caused problems if Esc was pressed, in the Menu Manager.

The situation arose when I had a layout consisting of two panels. On the left is a tree, and on the right there is another panel. Changing the selection in the tree causes the class handling the right panel to be disposed and a new one created.

In the situation where the right panel had created a context menu, then the tree selection was changed, the context menu remained visible and wouldn&#39;t go away. Obviously the qooxdoo menu object associated with the menu had been disposed, but the div was still present.

The workaround was to place a call to Menu.hide() in the disposer for our menu class. However, this should really be in the disposer for the qooxdoo menu class, qx.ui.menu.Menu.

Hugh</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1383</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2007-05-24 12:06:35 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>It is not a good idea to add hide() to the disposer because this would add tasks to the layout queue, which is a problem on application disposal.

What is possible is an explicit &quot;destroy&quot; method like the tree already has, which does what you need.

Fabian</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>