<bug>
          <bug_id>3764</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-06-11 23:47:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Get QOOXDOO_PATH (or other &quot;let&quot; variables) from the environment</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:22:17 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>DUPLICATE</resolution>
          <dup_id>5632</dup_id>
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.6</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18654</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-11 23:47:17 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I work regularly with contrib projects which have QOOXDOO_PATH defined to point to where the author of the contrib has his framework directory. I can change that path in config.json to point to my framework, but then it becomes a modification as far as source control is concerned, making review of changes and commits more difficult.

I propose that environment variables be usable to override variables in the &quot;let&quot; section. There are a few ways to implement this:

1. An environment variable always overrides a variable of the same name in the &quot;let&quot; section. For example, if I define QOOXDOO_PATH in the environment, it will always override whatever is specified in the &quot;let&quot; section. (I would then provide a full path to my framework directory in that variable in the envrionment.)

2. Provide a method to specify that an environment variable can be used, if it is defined, and to use a default value otherwise. The parallel to this is with the bash shell, when one can say: ${varname:=word} which means if varname exists and isn&#39;t null, return its value; otherwise set it to word and then return its value. In our case, this would mean to look in the environment for varname and if not found, word would be the default value to use instead. Specifically, then, an entry in the &quot;let&quot; section might say:

  &quot;QOOXDOO_PATH&quot; : ${QOOXDOO_PATH:../../../trunk/qooxdoo}</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18671</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-14 10:30:12 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>--&gt; Thomas</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30124</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2012-07-13 11:51:29 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Proposition 1. has been implemented for QOOXDOO_PATH.

*** This bug has been marked as a duplicate of bug 5632 ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37619</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:22:17 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>