<bug>
          <bug_id>4002</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-08-16 15:55:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>getRowData and getRowDataAsMap don&#39;t get the same data after editing the table</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2010-11-08 09:07:56 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.table</component>
          <version>1.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://tinyurl.com/24fkafo</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>minor</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.2.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Mustafa Sak">mustafa.sak</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19856</commentid>
            <who name="Mustafa Sak">mustafa.sak</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-16 15:55:04 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>After editing a simple table model, I try to get the row data with meta data. In case of using getRowDataAsMap() I will get the current data as map but no meta data. So i try to get the map with .getRowData() and it seems to work, but after editing the table you will just get the initial data, not the current one. Look at Playground, pls.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19865</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-17 08:10:01 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report and the example!
--&gt; Martin</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20266</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-09-21 12:12:31 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The first thing i need to do is to find out why we have two different methods for basically doing the same thing. After some investigation, I tend to believe that the getRowDataAsMap should only return the data really visible. I added a comment to the API doc to make that clear.

The second thing is, why does the getRowData method return the old stuff? This method seems to be just implemented not correct. I reimplemented it to return the desired data.

trunk: r23351
1.2.x: r23352</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20468</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-04 15:30:40 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Seems like the getRowData method did not always return a map which breaks the Table Edit Cell demo as seen in bug #4108. Therefore I reopen this bug and change the implementation of getRowData back as it was and return the meta data in getRowDataAsMap instead.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20470</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-04 15:44:11 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>As already said, moved the implementation of getRowData to its old implementation as it seems to really rely on it and i don&#39;t really know why it returns different things sometimes.
Therefore, the getRowDataAsMap now includes the meta data as well which should be as fine as it was before.

trunk: r23434
1.2.x: r23435</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20625</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-13 07:54:13 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>mass retargeting to 1.2.2 due to intermediate 1.2.1 release</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>