<bug>
          <bug_id>4011</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-08-20 08:43:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>RPC Server Writer Guide is incorrect in places, incomplete otherwise</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-02-17 18:35:59 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>documentation.manual</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://manual.qooxdoo.org/1.2.x/pages/communication/rpc_server_writer_guide.html</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="aj h.">aj+qooxdoo</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Christian Boulanger">info</assigned_to>
          <cc>derrell.lipman</cc>
    
    <cc>info</cc>
    
    <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19931</commentid>
            <who name="aj h.">aj+qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-20 08:43:21 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Regarding the RPC Server Writer Guide, the &#39;Transport&#39; section is ambiguous on HTTP request methods for the various transport methods, incorrect about HTTP Request Content-Types, and silent on the need to wrap cross-domain responses in an undocumented function call.

# Ambiguous HTTP request methods #

The guide states that &#39;XmlHTTPTransport&#39; is one available transport method for RPC client requests. I could not find precisely what the term &#39;XmlHTTPTransport&#39; means, though I believe it means the use of an XMLHttpRequest object (i.e. Ajax ... please correct me if I am wrong). However, I&#39;m not sure which HTTP request method is used (GET, POST, etc.) for which configurations.

For example, in my tests, when a cross-domain request is made to my server (using either absolute or relative URL), the method is GET and the Content-Type is &quot;text/javascript&quot;. The documentation does not list &quot;text/javascript&quot; among the valid Content-Types, and makes no mention of the GET method anywhere.

When I make a same-domain request (using either absolute or relative URL), the method is POST and the Content-Type is &quot;application/json&quot;.

I wonder if there are other ways in which a server might be called. The documentation about RPC Server Writing should make this explicit.

# Undocumented Requirement for Cross-Domain requests #

Apparently cross-domain requests require a specific JSONP-formatted response. The JSON response must be wrapped in a call to `qx.io.remote.transport.Script._requestFinished($ScriptId, $JSON);`. This is not mentioned in the RPC Server Writer Guide. After much searching, I found it as a *suggestion* in the qx.io.transport API. Cross-domain requests do not appear to work without this callback.

# Questions #

Is qooxdoo&#39;s RPC feature set still supported? Is there an up-to-date reference implementation that should serve as the basis for documentation?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19937</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-20 14:45:13 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>to me</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>19939</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-20 16:25:29 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This documentation has become a bit stale. I&#39;ve committed (r23123) an attempt to update the Transport section to better reflect current reality. Christian, it would be useful if you&#39;d look at this document and update it based on all of your recent RPC Server work. (I added you to the CC list and assigned the bug to you.)

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26343</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Boulanger">info</who>
            <bug_when>2011-08-01 13:45:25 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #2)
&gt; This documentation has become a bit stale. I&#39;ve committed (r23123) an attempt
&gt; to update the Transport section to better reflect current reality. Christian,
&gt; it would be useful if you&#39;d look at this document and update it based on all of
&gt; your recent RPC Server work. (I added you to the CC list and assigned the bug
&gt; to you.)
&gt; 
&gt; Derrell

Noticing that this bug is targeted for 1.6: I don&#39;t see any sense in updating the docs until the new rpc layer is finished. After that, we can update the servers (backwards-compatible or not) and the documentation.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27146</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Boulanger">info</who>
            <bug_when>2011-10-07 22:11:31 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #3)
&gt; (In reply to comment #2)
&gt; &gt; This documentation has become a bit stale. I&#39;ve committed (r23123) an attempt
&gt; &gt; to update the Transport section to better reflect current reality. Christian,
&gt; &gt; it would be useful if you&#39;d look at this document and update it based on all of
&gt; &gt; your recent RPC Server work. (I added you to the CC list and assigned the bug
&gt; &gt; to you.)
&gt; &gt; 
&gt; &gt; Derrell
&gt; 
&gt; Noticing that this bug is targeted for 1.6: I don&#39;t see any sense in updating
&gt; the docs until the new rpc layer is finished. After that, we can update the
&gt; servers (backwards-compatible or not) and the documentation.

Actually, I think we shouldn&#39;t write our own servers anymore, but use standard-conformant, well-maintained third-party json-rpc servers instead. why reinvent the wheel and waste energy?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27182</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-10-12 10:20:48 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #4)
&gt; (In reply to comment #3)
&gt; &gt; (In reply to comment #2)
&gt; &gt; &gt; This documentation has become a bit stale. I&#39;ve committed (r23123) an attempt
&gt; &gt; &gt; to update the Transport section to better reflect current reality. Christian,
&gt; &gt; &gt; it would be useful if you&#39;d look at this document and update it based on all of
&gt; &gt; &gt; your recent RPC Server work. (I added you to the CC list and assigned the bug
&gt; &gt; &gt; to you.)
&gt; &gt; &gt; 
&gt; &gt; &gt; Derrell
&gt; &gt; 
&gt; &gt; Noticing that this bug is targeted for 1.6: I don&#39;t see any sense in updating
&gt; &gt; the docs until the new rpc layer is finished. After that, we can update the
&gt; &gt; servers (backwards-compatible or not) and the documentation.
&gt; 
&gt; Actually, I think we shouldn&#39;t write our own servers anymore, but use
&gt; standard-conformant, well-maintained third-party json-rpc servers instead. why
&gt; reinvent the wheel and waste energy?

I would agree.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27747</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-12-01 16:08:25 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Moved from the 1.6 release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>