<bug>
          <bug_id>4030</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-08-26 18:35:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Add JSON support to the Selenium extensions</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-08-30 11:37:32 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>contrib</product>
          <component>Simulator</component>
          <version>trunk</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20004</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-26 18:35:28 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Several methods of the qooxdoo user extensions for Selenium execute JavaScript code in the AUT&#39;s context and return the result, which is then converted to a string to be transferred over HTTP from the browser-side part of Selenium to the client driver. This means that test scripts need to a lot of string parsing/type conversion, e.g. &quot;true&quot; and &quot;false&quot; to booleans. This could be simplified by serializing the return values as JSON using either the browser&#39;s native capabilities or qooxdoo&#39;s JSON support. This would make common testing tasks like  checking the properties of qooxdoo objects significantly easier.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20053</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2010-09-01 17:28:24 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Added toJson method in 20678. Also added a new method getQxTableSelectedRowData that uses toJson to return a table&#39;s selected row data array.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26621</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2011-08-30 11:37:32 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>getRunInContext already uses toJson. The only other candidate is getQxObjectFunction, but the intended use case for that is to call functions that return primitives or have no return value. getRunInContext can and should be used for everything else.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>