<bug>
          <bug_id>4033</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-08-27 10:32:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>You have to tab twice on the ipad</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-04-19 13:37:21 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.popups</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.3</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Tino Butz">tinobutz</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20013</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-27 10:32:24 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Here is the report from the mailing list:

The thing is that there&#39;s no real mouseover effect on an iPad since there&#39;s
no cursor so you have to click once to trigger the mouseover effect and a
second time to trigger the mousedown effect. So I have to click twice in my
menus, once for focusing an item and a 2nd time to actually click the item. 

This is not really a problems since I can do everything I want on the
mouseover event in iPads instead of the mousedown event.

http://qooxdoo.678.n2.nabble.com/Closing-the-menu-on-a-menu-button-on-deman-td5411683.html#a5411683</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20089</commentid>
            <who name="Tino Butz">tinobutz</who>
            <bug_when>2010-09-06 13:34:59 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The problem is described in the apple docu:

http://developer.apple.com/safari/library/documentation/appleapplications/reference/safariwebcontent/HandlingEvents/HandlingEvents.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40006511-SW7

&quot;If the user taps a clickable element, events arrive in this order: mouseover, mousemove, mousedown, mouseup, and click. The mouseout event occurs only if the user taps on another clickable item. Also, if the contents of the page changes on the mousemove event, no subsequent events in the sequence are sent. This behavior allows the user to tap in the new content.&quot;

As the DOM gets changed when the user clicks on a button (press effect / tooltip), the event chain is interrupted and no mousout event arrives at the button.

Possible solutions:

 * No Tooltips on touch devices
 * and simulate mouse events on touchstart / touchend (tap)
 * or (but not preferred) postpone flush of layout queues until the mouse event sequence is finished</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20248</commentid>
            <who name="Tino Butz">tinobutz</who>
            <bug_when>2010-09-17 16:10:17 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed in Revision r23324:

Martin and I did a couple of things to get a RIA working on an iOS device:

1. Introduced a new target check to the event handler: TARGET_DOCUMENT
2. Handler can now support more than one targest - just add the targets together, e.g. TARGET_CHECK : qx.event.IEventHandler.TARGET_DOMNODE + qx.event.IEventHandler.TARGET_DOCUMENT
3. Fixed initialization of the touch event handler
4. Paused the queue manager right after the touchend (see bug report for more details)
5. Stop hiding menus on blur of the window on touch devices.

Sorry for the huge commit, everything needs to work together...</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>