<bug>
          <bug_id>4041</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-08-30 15:23:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>keypress is not a keySequence event but rather a textInput event</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2010-12-13 08:46:50 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.event</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.3</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Adrian Olaru">adrian.olaru</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20031</commentid>
            <who name="Adrian Olaru">adrian.olaru</who>
            <bug_when>2010-08-30 15:23:13 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Some description first (not related to qooxdoo).

We have 4 keyboard events: keydown, keypress,textInput,keyup.

The keydown event occurs when the key is pressed, followed immediately by the keypress event, and possibly the textInput event. Then the keyup event is generated when the key is released. 

the keydown and keyup events represent keys being pressed or released, while the keypress event represents a character being typed. textInput is a replacement and generalization of keypress.

in qooxdoo, the keydown/keypress/keyup fire a keysequence event which is used to identify the key being pressed and textInput event fire a textinput event to check which character was actually pressed.

As you see we have a keypress event that is used for something and a textInput that is used for something else. This two should be the same, and used for exactly the same purpose: checking which character was pressed.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20710</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-14 16:29:58 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Martin, please review.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21363</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-17 13:10:29 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Do you have some references for your facts? I mean changing something in that level of the event layer is not done easily and without thinking about the consequences and deprecation strategies.

I just checked the spec which says that keydown [1], keypress [2] and keyup [3] all implement the same interface, KeyboardEvent. The textInput event even implements a different interface: TextEvent [4]. 

So I don&#39;t see a reason why we should change keypress to textinput.


[1] http://www.w3.org/TR/DOM-Level-3-Events/#event-type-keydown
[2] http://www.w3.org/TR/DOM-Level-3-Events/#event-type-keypress
[3] http://www.w3.org/TR/DOM-Level-3-Events/#event-type-keyup

[4] http://www.w3.org/TR/DOM-Level-3-Events/#event-type-textInput</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>