<bug>
          <bug_id>405</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2007-05-14 10:06:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Table: columnVisibilitybutton menu DOM nodes are not removed after menu close</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:20:03 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.table</component>
          <version>0.6.6</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.7.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Daniel Haferkorn">daniel.haferkorn</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1280</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Haferkorn">daniel.haferkorn</who>
            <bug_when>2007-05-14 10:06:56 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Everytime one clicks on the columnVisibilitybutton widget, a new DOM node for the menu will be created, and it won&#39;t be deleted again once a menu item is selected or another part of the screen is clicked on, the DOM node stays there.
Tested with Firefox 2.0.0.3 Portable + Firebug under Windows, most likely also present in other browser/OS combinations.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1309</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2007-05-15 18:44:06 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I reviewed the code and enabled debug for object disposal, and all looks like it&#39;s getting properly disposed.

I&#39;m not seeing what you&#39;re seeing.  Can you point me to exactly where you&#39;re looking in firebug to ascertain that the dom node remains? 

Thanks,

Derrell
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1427</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Haferkorn">daniel.haferkorn</who>
            <bug_when>2007-05-29 11:23:11 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; I reviewed the code and enabled debug for object disposal, and all looks like
&gt; it&#39;s getting properly disposed.
&gt; 
&gt; I&#39;m not seeing what you&#39;re seeing.  Can you point me to exactly where you&#39;re
&gt; looking in firebug to ascertain that the dom node remains? 
&gt; 

This picture shows the HTML node tree in Firebug before clicking on the menu button:
http://img261.imageshack.us/img261/814/dombeforern6.png

This picture shows the node tree after clicking on the menu button three times and then selecting an entry or clicking on an empty space:
http://img502.imageshack.us/img502/4664/domafterss2.png

As you can see, there are three greyed out DIV nodes now. Everytime I click on the menu button of the table, a new DIV node will be created.

If I click on a normal button that creates a menu, for instance the language menu button in one of the qooxdoo examples, there will only be one greyed out DIV node created for the menu and it will be used again if I click on the button again.

The same problem with the table menu button happens when using the table example
http://demo.qooxdoo.org/current/sample/html/example/Table_1.html

Regards,
Daniel Haferkorn</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2135</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2007-08-17 16:58:06 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>fixed in trunk and legacy_0_7</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36736</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:20:03 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>