<bug>
          <bug_id>4071</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-09-10 17:36:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Add data: URL Support for Images</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:26:45 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator.compiler</component>
          <version>1.2</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.4</target_milestone>
          <dependson>4555</dependson>
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          <cc>carsten.lergenmueller</cc>
    
    <cc>daniel.wagner</cc>
    
    <cc>info</cc>
    
    <cc>martin.wittemann</cc>
    
    <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20135</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2010-09-10 17:36:27 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Add support for &quot;data:&quot; URLs.

Many browser are now supporting data: URLs which allow to represent an image as 
a base64 hex string. For example:

  &lt;img src=&quot;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAA...&lt;base64 string&gt;&quot; 
width=&quot;32&quot; height=&quot;32&quot;&gt;

includes a png image on a web site, giving its base64 encoded contents. It has 
to be evaluated what other use cases besides &lt;img&gt; tags allow data: encoded 
images (e.g. background images, ...).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20161</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2010-09-14 14:43:49 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Here is an outline for an implementation:

1) Generate base64 versions of existing images
2) Generate a representation for them usable for the qooxdoo run time
3) Use them in the qooxdoo run time

conc. 1)
Converting individual images to base64 with the generator is trivial. But 
simply having an image like &quot;up.png&quot; with its base64 variant &quot;up.b64&quot; would 
provide little advantage. The qooxdoo client would still have to load one or 
the other to get at the image data, and then base64 encoded data is about 
double the original size, so loading up.b64 rather than up.png has no apparent 
advantage.
Which brings us to the next point.

conc. 2)
data: encoded images only bring advantage when many of them are combined in a 
single file, so you save on net requests. The format of such a file could be a 
special Json:
{
  &quot;combined.json&quot; :   // the resource id of the containing file
  {
    &quot;embedded.png&quot; :  // the resource id of the embedded file
    {
      &quot;type&quot;     : &quot;png&quot;,
      &quot;width&quot;    : 32,
      &quot;height&quot;   : 32,
      &quot;encoding&quot; : &quot;base64&quot;,
      &quot;data&quot;     : &quot;iVBORw0KGgoAAAANS...&lt;base64 string&gt;&quot;
    },
    ...
  }  
}
The file extension should be .json, to comply with qooxdoo conventions. The 
generator could generate that with a variant of the &quot;combine-images&quot; config key.

A Json file like that could be treated pretty much like other combined images, 
as it serves essentially the same purpose. You could have a corresponding .meta 
file which lists the contained images (which would duplicate some of the meta 
information from the .json file, but just for the sake of common processing in 
the generator). The resource infos (as passed to the generated application) 
would mirror that of other combined images. The embedded images are listed as 
being part of the combined image, and the combined image has its own entry:
{
  &quot;embedded.png&quot; : [32, 32, &quot;png&quot;, &quot;mylib&quot;, [&quot;combined.json&quot;, -1, -1]], // as 
offsets are not used here
  ...
  &quot;combined.json&quot; : [-1, -1, &quot;json&quot;]  // as image dimensions are not used here
}

conc. 3)
The qooxdoo run time would look up individual images as usual (like 
&quot;embedded.png&quot; in the example). It would find it is part of a combined image. 
It would look up the combined image, and find that it is a json file with 
base64 encoded images (maybe the resource entry would need an &quot;encoding&quot; 
attribute for that). If it finds it can use this combined image, it would load 
it, extract the image attributes from the Json including the data string, and 
use it for the DOM, e.g. in the form of an &lt;img&gt; element as indicated in the 
bug summary.


Todo&#39;s:
* Create Json structures as described in 2), and see what the size penality (w/ 
and w/o gzip) would be.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20176</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-09-15 10:14:09 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the details explantation of this, thomas. Would be interesting to know what the size differences we are talking about after using gzip.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21299</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-15 14:37:00 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>*** Bug 2363 has been marked as a duplicate of this bug. ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23109</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-07 15:04:30 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>There is a first draft implementation in trunk. 

For one thing you can now create (pseudo-) combined images in a base64 
encoding. Use the standard &quot;combine-image&quot; action key, with 
&#39;combine-image/&lt;output_file&gt;.b64/type&#39; set to &quot;base64&quot;. Running such a job will 
create a Json output file. a map with the embedded images as key, and a set of 
information for each, like width, height, original image format, and a &#39;data&#39; 
entry that holds the base64-encoded representation of the image. Remember not 
to combine an input image in both a normal and a base64 combined image (only 
one can be registered with the app).

As known from literature 
(http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data:_URL#Disadvantages), combined images created 
in this way are approx. 35% larger than the corresponding binary combined 
image, which reduces to +2-3% under gzip.

I&#39;ve also add support for base64 data urls on the framework side, modifying the 
ResourceManager and the qx.bom.element.Decoration classes. Biggest change is 
the preloading of the base64 combined images, so the data is there when the 
Decoration class needs it. Base64 images are now used if they are provided by a 
base64 combined image, and if the client supports clipped images at all.

With r25333.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23173</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-09 12:51:31 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The approach with XHR-loading the combined base64 images did not work out. 
While it worked in the source version, in the build version the timing was not 
getting right, to have the combined images loaded before the ResourceManager 
tries to answer the first request. As a consequence, the whole primary 
Feedreader GUI was rendered using the fall-back, namely the individual images.

So I changed the strategy from pre-loading files to incorporating the combined 
images directly in the loader/package data (qx.$$resources, qx.$$packageData). 
This works nicely as far as timing is concerned. As a cost, the script files 
have to carry the additional payload. This is especially crucial if an 
application uses parts, as resource information is duplicated with every part 
that needs it, so now the base64 combined data is duplicated as well.

But I think we can use the current state as a start, and gain some feedback, as 
to what the experiences with this approach will be. Optimizations can then be 
addressed later. The Feedreader has completely be migrated to use base64 
combined images, and all tests look good.

Hence, I&#39;m closing this bug. If major issues arise this bug can be re-opened 
or, even better, dedicated new bugs can be created.

With r25429.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>39219</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:26:45 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>