<bug>
          <bug_id>4086</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-09-16 15:31:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Addition to new manual for i18n localization</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-02-17 16:11:46 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.locale</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Stefan Andersson">dev</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Stefan Andersson">dev</assigned_to>
          <cc>martin.wittemann</cc>
    
    <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20211</commentid>
            <who name="Stefan Andersson">dev</who>
            <bug_when>2010-09-16 15:31:33 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Partial-/Multi-localization
---------------------------

Qooxdoo does not support partial localization, such as for example one window or dialog or part of an application. It can be useful for non-natives of a language and in multi-lingual environments.

Solution: You have to rewrite and override localisation functions alternatively make a local implementation for the part.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20232</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-09-17 09:19:02 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report Stefan. 
Its not that easy to to write that into the manual how you would get that done because it highly depends on the widgets used in that single translation part. It requires a lot of insider knowledge and maybe some changes in the core to get it done at all. So adding a part to the manual is currently not a good idea because it would be huge to mention all the stuff which you have to take care of. All in all, this is just currently not supported and thats why we should not write documentation for it.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20237</commentid>
            <who name="Stefan Andersson">dev</who>
            <bug_when>2010-09-17 09:57:34 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I understand your view partwise.
My solution:
In the manual write this

___________________________________
Partial-/Multi-localization
---------------------------

Qooxdoo doses not support partial-/multi-localization at the moment. &lt;solution page reference link&gt;

__________________________________

Then create a solution page where people can find solutions and links to the playground code if any.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20240</commentid>
            <who name="Stefan Andersson">dev</who>
            <bug_when>2010-09-17 10:11:27 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Important to show that it is not supported then so people know when they are searching for it, because they will... We did!

you could also easily setup a knowlewledgebase and here is a very good one whichi is easy to implement:

kbpublisher

a knowledgebase is really good for that you do not want to put in the manual!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20244</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2010-09-17 11:33:33 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Stefan, could you share pointers to other frameworks that support exactly such a &quot;partial-/multi-localization&quot;, thanks. It doesn&#39;t seem to be a commonly requested or available feature elsewhere? Assigning to you to provide more input.

Regarding knowledgebase: the existing mailing list (incl. archives), stackoverflow, manual, user snippets or issue tracking should cover that sufficiently. Otherwise, such requests would be handled on the ML (that people hit no matter how well maintained any kind of &quot;knowledgebase&quot; is).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35085</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2014-02-17 16:11:46 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed this stale issue, as documenting unsupported, uncommon features unnecessarily bloats the manual.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>