<bug>
          <bug_id>4186</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-10-14 16:53:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Editing in playground no longer functions properly</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2010-12-13 08:37:47 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>app.playground</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.3</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20713</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-14 16:53:25 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>1. The standard keyboard commands have stopped working in the playground. Pressing ctrl-left to move backwards a word instead moves to the beginning of the line. Similarly, ctrl-right moves to the end of the line instead of forward one word. This applies when trying to highlight a word with ctrl-shift-left and ctrl-shift-right, which now highlight from current position to beginning and end of line, respectively.

2. Automatic indentation does not work most of the time, any longer. Closing braces usually indent properly (although not always), but most presses of new-line cause the cursor to move to the beginning of the next line, not indented according to the normal conventions.

Something very bad has happened to the code editing window.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20714</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-14 17:18:43 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>In trunk we have been working on integrating a different editing component. I&#39;ll assign this report to Martin, who&#39;ll surely have a look and come back to you (in about 2 weeks after his return from vacation).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21114</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-05 11:54:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Martin. Welcome back.

Now that you&#39;re working on this, I need to ask... Code Mirror was AWESOME. It worked perfectly for me. What problem are you trying to solve that requires replacing Code Mirror?

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21140</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-08 08:23:46 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hey Derrell,
I guess you are using Firefox vor development, right? In firefox, the code mirror worked like a charm. But on webkit based browsers not. So thats the main problem I had with the former implementation, it freaked me out working with it. Additionally, I was able to remove a hack used for the splitter due to the iFrame code mirror uses. Next thing is, that the new editor is virtual. There is no problem putting 10.000 lines of code in it (nice to have but not really that important for the playground, I know). One of the last and most important things is, that Fabian has written the editor for ajax.org which means we have a good relationship to the developer and can get in touch with him easily.
Best,
Martin</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21153</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-08 11:57:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Added a fixed editor with new key bindings.
Fabian also said that he worked on some indentation problems. Derrell, could you please recheck the indentation and reopen the bug if its still a problem? Maybe you can send me some details on how to reproduce it so that I can forward this bug to fabian.

trunk: r23690, r23689</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21268</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-13 20:25:31 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>In the latest devel playground, the indentation problems appear to be fixed, but the ctrl-left/right and shift-ctrl-left/right incorrect action still occurs. Those commands should move (or move and select) one word, but instead move to the beginning/end of the line. (&quot;Beginning of line&quot; seems to have changed since my original report. It now moves to the first non-white character on the line instead of the absolute beginning of line, but this is still incorrect for the command.)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21269</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-13 20:30:02 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Correction and more detail...

ctrl-left moves left one word. It also incorrectly (according to common usage) considers white space a word, so it requires twice as many word-left commands as it should to move a given number of words left.

ctrl-right works similarly, requiring twice as many commands as should be necessary.

shift-ctrl-left still incorrectly selects all the way to the beginning of the line instead of selecting only from current position to beginning of current word.

shift-ctrl-right similarly incorrectly selects all the way to the end of the line.

I&#39;ve tested in both Chrome and Firefox on Linux. The results are the same in each.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21275</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-15 09:38:23 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&#39;ll check that.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21532</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-24 14:26:05 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Those are two issues:

1. Spaces are not ignored on word move
Opened up a bug report for the editor:
https://github.com/ajaxorg/ace/issues#issue/10

2. Word select does not work.
Fixed with r23956 and send a pull request to the editor team:
https://github.com/ajaxorg/ace/issues#issue/11

I close the bug because I opened up a follow up reminder for the 1.4 release that we keep on checking the issue: http://bugzilla.qooxdoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=4365</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>