<bug>
          <bug_id>4203</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-10-19 14:22:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Re-Think Privates Optimization</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:47:48 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator.compiler</component>
          <version>1.2.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</assigned_to>
          <cc>martin.wittemann</cc>
    
    <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20768</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-19 14:22:52 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The current private optimization of the generator which relies on variable 
renaming has several issues.

- Scope: It is *not* a class-local operation. No class can be private-optimized 
on its own. This defeats any kind of atomicity, of operating on individual 
classes independent of the greater scope of an application.

- Rather, the current private optimization requires *perfect knowledge*: The 
privates mapping of all classes that go into any particular build have to be 
known at optimization time, either through calculating them immediately, or 
memoizing them from previous builds. In short: Private optimization currently 
works only on *entire applications*.

- Size optimization: It is also only partly an optimization. It gains some 
transfer size by using short replacements for private identifiers, but the 
question is how relevant this gain is in the face of gzipping transfered files.

- Quality assurance: The other, and maybe more prominent, aspect of private 
optimization is that of an assertion. By turning private optimization on the 
users gains a run-time assertion that no private members are used outside the 
defining class. This goes more in the direction of other run-time assertions in 
the framework that are actually turned off for the build version. The question 
is if it should not be advertised as this, a quality assurance measure that is 
turned off in the final version.

- Usage: Big projects deliberately turn off privates optimization for their 
production builds. For a code service that dynamically delivers pre-compiled 
code to various clients, the current private optimization is not usable at all.

- Bug#4148: The private optimization in its current form also defeats bug#4148, 
which tries to make compile results string-identical (given identical code 
input), which is a major requirement for effective change management in the 
application life cycle (e.g. w.r.t. checksums, server updating, etc.). The 
current implementation enumerates private identifiers over all classes, and 
this enumeration depends on the state of the memoized mappings (i.e. the 
private replacements in the previously compiled classes in the current 
environment). Currently, bug#4148 can only be achieved when compiling with an 
empty cache, or with private optimization turned off.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22950</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-24 17:12:00 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I couldn&#39;t find a good alternative to our current enumeration algorithm, if we 
don&#39;t want to accept much longer replacement strings (see also 
http://stackoverflow.com/questions/5094760/algorithm-to-map-strings-to-short-replacements). 
 The current solution allows to encode around 140,000 strings with replacements 
of at most 3 chars.

So for the time being we have to deal with a global privates map that holds the 
mappings of all classes&#39; privates to their replacement strings. This global 
resource is shared by all tasks that do private optimization, within a process 
and across multiple processes, be they concurrent or sequential in time. They 
need to lookup existing mappings (so re-compiling an already optimized class 
will re-use previously assigned keys; without the lookup you would always add 
new entries with each compile); and they need to add new mappings for privates 
that haven&#39;t been assigned yet.

This global resource has to be used accordingly. Only one task can ever update 
it, and all other tasks need to get the update with their next read. There are 
various ways to achieve that. An elegant, but expensive way, would be a server 
process that is reachable over a TCP socket. It keeps the privates map in 
memory, and returns requests for a key with either the existing or a newly 
created mapping. It needs to process requests sequenctially and would thus 
function as a serializing lock for the privates map.

A less elegant but more approachable solution is to have the privates map on 
the file system, and using a file lock for synchronization. This is how it is 
implemented now (in the context of bug#2008), using the compile cache. A task 
needing a privates mapping has to lock the file, read it, make the lookup, 
create a new mapping if needed, and writes the potentially modified map back to 
disk, then releasing the lock.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36031</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:47:48 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>