<bug>
          <bug_id>4238</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-10-26 14:27:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>generate.py should Follow the Value of the &#39;-c&#39; Option when looking for QOOXDOO_PATH</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-06-05 13:55:47 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>1.2.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>DUPLICATE</resolution>
          <dup_id>3795</dup_id>
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>derrell.lipman</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20871</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-26 14:27:06 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Currently, generate.py tries to infer the path to the qooxdoo SDK by looking 
into config.json. But &#39;config.json&#39; is hard-coded. generate.py should look into 
whatever config file is passed with the -c command line option.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20873</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-26 14:37:57 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I find generate.py sufficiently difficult to deal with, particularly for contribs, that I use the following alias, which works always, even for contribs that use a different relative path than I do to the SDK. I really wonder whether creating a shell script or batch file to run, that depends on having previously set QOOXDOO_PATH in the environment, mightn&#39;t be a better alternative to generate.py as the default way of doing it...???

This is qxgen:

/home/derrell/ME/qooxdoo.git/trunk/qooxdoo/tool/bin/generator.py \
  -m QOOXDOO_PATH:/home/derrell/ME/qooxdoo.git/trunk/qooxdoo !*

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20876</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-26 15:39:41 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; I find generate.py sufficiently difficult to deal with, particularly for
&gt; contribs, that I use the following alias, which works always, even for contribs
&gt; that use a different relative path than I do to the SDK. I really wonder
&gt; whether creating a shell script or batch file to run, that depends on having
&gt; previously set QOOXDOO_PATH in the environment, mightn&#39;t be a better
&gt; alternative to generate.py as the default way of doing it...???
&gt; 
&gt; This is qxgen:
&gt; 
&gt; /home/derrell/ME/qooxdoo.git/trunk/qooxdoo/tool/bin/generator.py \
&gt;   -m QOOXDOO_PATH:/home/derrell/ME/qooxdoo.git/trunk/qooxdoo !*

Derrell,

I use an alias to tool/bin/generator.py all the time. Actually, I&#39;ve put tool/bin in my shell&#39;s PATH. But your use of the -m QOOXDOO_PATH:... option is a nice hack, especially when working with foreign configs like in contribs, as you said.

generate.py is really for casual users, or users with little shell experience. As such, I think it serves its purpose. For those I don&#39;t think it is difficult to deal with, if you follow this single rule, to adapt QOOXDOO_PATH when you move libs around (or download them). But to that end, generate.py should honor the -c switch, which is what this bug is about. Again, generate.py is just a little helper which you can (and should) happily skip as soon as you know how to do that :).

I&#39;m not sure about the environment variable, though. If pressed I would use it, but it makes automatic installation and setup so much more tedious, especially cross-platform, that I am very happy to delay it as long as possible. The current qooxdoo &quot;installation&quot; that leaves zero traces when you just remove the files (no env settings to remove, no registry, nothing), is very much to my liking.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29674</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2012-06-05 13:55:47 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>

*** This bug has been marked as a duplicate of bug 3795 ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>