<bug>
          <bug_id>4249</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-10-27 15:06:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Errors in Test Runner</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2010-10-29 10:27:38 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>app.testrunner</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>DUPLICATE</resolution>
          <dup_id>4257</dup_id>
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P1</priority>
          <bug_severity>major</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter>marcomarchi89</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          <cc>oliverst</cc>
    
    <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20904</commentid>
            <who name="">marcomarchi89</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-27 15:06:34 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I tried to use the Test Runner in the Demo section of the site and i saw that it fails a lot of times. I tried with different browsers (on Windows XP) and the result is:

Firefox 3.6.3 -&gt; 404 failed tests
Chrome 7 -&gt; 40 failed tests
Safari 5.0.2 -&gt; 40 failed tests
Opera 10.60 -&gt; 38 failed tests
IE 7 -&gt; 409 failed tests

I don&#39;t know if those are known bugs, i just want to let you know that there are failed tests in every browser i&#39;ve tested.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20935</commentid>
            <who name="">oliverst</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-28 12:44:09 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Funnily I did the same yesterday just out of curiosity and was wondering, that no browser was completely the test with no issues. So as follow-up I got

IE8 -&gt; 404 failed
IE 9 beta -&gt; 410 failed

These tests were both conducted on a Windows 7 x64.

Both browser are going totally bonkers several times in the test with a batch of these messages:

&quot;Fatal Error: Flush terminated &lt;n&gt; times in a row due to exceptions in user code. The application has to be reloaded!&quot;</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20957</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-29 09:05:36 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>No indeed, those test runs should all be fine. Unfortunately, you didn&#39;t mention if you ran the testrunner of trunk of of one of the previous releases.

Anyway, automated testing in 30+ browser/OS combinations is supposed to address that for the framework continuously, and AFAIK there are no issues currently. Daniel, please have a look.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20976</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-29 10:27:38 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>These failing tests are almost certainly caused by a known issue with the Test Runner itself. Just created a report for it, #4257.

Marco and Oliver, if you want to take the time you can try running each namespace under qx.test individually, clicking the Reload button after each package finishes. This should get rid of the false positives and (hopefully) leave you with 0 failures.

*** This bug has been marked as a duplicate of bug 4257 ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>