<bug>
          <bug_id>4250</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-10-27 16:47:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Using HTML-Link in HTML-CellRenderer does not work(regression)</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2010-12-13 08:44:36 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.table</component>
          <version>1.2.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.2.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Oliver Hauger">oliver.hauger</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          <cc>christian.hagendorn</cc>
    
    <cc>derrell.lipman</cc>
    
    <cc>julian.ivanica.external</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20909</commentid>
            <who name="Oliver Hauger">oliver.hauger</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-27 16:47:40 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>With the previous(1.0.1) qooxdoo version the following was possible: if a table cell(rendered with HTML-CellRenderer) contained a html link the referenced URL was opened onclick. With version 1.2.1 this does not work anymore. 
See example: http://tinyurl.com/32gdfos</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20910</commentid>
            <who name="julez">julian.ivanica.external</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-27 17:01:02 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Is there already a workaround for this?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20912</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-27 17:17:45 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>to me.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20913</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-27 17:18:47 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>At the moment there is no workaround, I will have a look.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20921</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-27 19:30:27 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The example http://tinyurl.com/32gdfos doesn&#39;t work in all qx versions

See (qx 1.0):
http://tinyurl.com/34fwn9f

So I can&#39;t find out what occurred the regression. Could any one post a example to get a working version for qx 1.0??</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20925</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-28 09:26:23 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Now I can find a working version with qx 1.0. Just set the property &quot;showCellFocusIndicator&quot; to &quot;false&quot;.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20928</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-28 10:37:42 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Commit 22275 to fix bug #2866 and bug #1822 has caused the regression.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20937</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-28 13:20:05 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&#39;m not a expert for the table, so I don&#39;t know if using a link tag is general possible. 

But you can use a workaround:
http://tinyurl.com/22nknbk

The workaround is to open the URL in a new window. I used a own renderer to get an easy access to the raw data.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>20938</commentid>
            <who name="julez">julian.ivanica.external</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-28 13:28:37 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>It seems that the browser don&#39;t get the click. Unfortunately the workaround is not suiteable if there are more than one link in one cell. I tried to find a solution to get the clicked HTML (see http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4024055/get-html-below-mouseclick-via-qooxdoo) but i think that passing the click to the browser will be the best solution for this problem.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21003</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2010-10-29 16:19:37 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Martin, could you please have a look. I&#39;m not sure if this issue can be solved. 

I saw that the &quot;qx.ui.table.pane.Scroller&quot; moves the focus indicator on mouse down to the actual focused cell (_updateFocusIndicator). And it seems to me that the mouse up event is dispatched on a other target, which is the reason why the link tag is not executed.

Maybe you should also involve Derrell.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21167</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-08 17:36:21 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I did some research on that issue. But first, that never worked with the focus indicator on. The changes made with r22275 removed the exclude of the focus indicator which then, of course, broke this feature. The reason for this is simple, the focus indicator instead of the link is clicked. Bad luck, the focus indicator is no child of the cell which means that the click will never reach the link:

                       &lt;--Focusindicator  &lt;-- (editor)
paneClipper
                       &lt;-- Pane  &lt;-- row  &lt;-- cell  &lt;-- link

I currently have no idea how to fix this expect a complete reorganization of the focus indicator or a move back to the old code.

@Derrell, could you maybe explain what you did with the changes in r22275? Maybe its easier to find another solution for that problem.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21171</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-08 20:16:16 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext> 
&gt; I currently have no idea how to fix this expect a complete reorganization of
&gt; the focus indicator or a move back to the old code.
&gt; 
&gt; @Derrell, could you maybe explain what you did with the changes in r22275?
&gt; Maybe its easier to find another solution for that problem.

The problem, IIRC, was that it wasn&#39;t possible to edit a cell if the focus indicator so excluded, so I kept the focus indicator there but hid it rather than excluding it. The only really defined way of interacting with table cells is via the cell editor. Having active links in table cells may have worked by accident, but I don&#39;t think it ever worked as a consequence of a design decision.

I don&#39;t know whether it&#39;s possible to have both bugs fixed at the same time with this current code. My suggestion is for those users who need to have links in cells to exclude the focus indicator manually. Maybe we should add a property to exclude the focus indicator, and document that property as also as disabling cell editing. In fact, maybe the property is &#39;enableCellEditing&#39; with default true, and document that property as allowing setting it to false to enable the possibility of live links in an HTML cell renderer.

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21176</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-09 08:42:43 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #11)
&gt; The problem, IIRC, was that it wasn&#39;t possible to edit a cell if the focus
&gt; indicator so excluded, so I kept the focus indicator there but hid it rather
&gt; than excluding it. The only really defined way of interacting with table cells
&gt; is via the cell editor. Having active links in table cells may have worked by
&gt; accident, but I don&#39;t think it ever worked as a consequence of a design
&gt; decision.
Thats why i am not a big fan of the tabel from a design perspective.

&gt; I don&#39;t know whether it&#39;s possible to have both bugs fixed at the same time
&gt; with this current code.
I think it would need a major restructuring of the table, especially the focus indicator.

&gt; My suggestion is for those users who need to have links
&gt; in cells to exclude the focus indicator manually. Maybe we should add a
&gt; property to exclude the focus indicator, and document that property as also as
&gt; disabling cell editing. In fact, maybe the property is &#39;enableCellEditing&#39; with
&gt; default true, and document that property as allowing setting it to false to
&gt; enable the possibility of live links in an HTML cell renderer.
Sounds like a really good idea to fix this. I think I go with that, thank you very much Derrell!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21182</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-09 09:40:19 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>After some coding I got the idea how to fix this without the need of a new property. I let the focus indicator check on every move if the column is editable and if the indicator should be shown. That way, I can exclude the indicator if the column is not editable and the focus indicator should not be shown. So the feature is back to the original state which is, you can click links if the indicator is disabled.

trunk: r23712
1.2.x: r23713</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21191</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-09 14:44:41 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #12)
&gt;(In reply to comment #11)
&gt;&gt; Having active links in table cells may have worked by
&gt;&gt; accident, but I don&#39;t think it ever worked as a consequence of a design
&gt;&gt; decision.

&gt; Thats why i am not a big fan of the tabel from a design perspective.

Recall the history of Table. It was written very early in qooxdoo&#39;s history, and provided a concept of &quot;virtual&quot; that was not available for any widget that could provide table-like or tree-like functionality. As a &quot;version 1&quot; widget, it was awesome. Unfortunately, the author disappeared into never-never-land almost immediately after release of this widget, and I ended up learning many of the ins and outs of how it worked (and created treevirtual based on it). From the perspective of what was available at the time, the functionality of Table was fabulous. It may have been possible to foresee the many uses Table has since seen, but I can understand both not having foreseen all of them, and not wanting to spend the time, initially, to allow for all of them.

With 20/20 hindsight, we now need the new qx.ui.virtual.Table to be completed, so that we can eventually obsolete qx.ui.table.Table. (Hint, hint, hint. :-) )

&gt;&gt; My suggestion is for those users who need to have links
&gt;&gt; in cells to exclude the focus indicator manually. Maybe we should add a
&gt;&gt; property to exclude the focus indicator, and document that property as also as
&gt;&gt; disabling cell editing. In fact, maybe the property is &#39;enableCellEditing&#39; with
&gt;&gt; default true, and document that property as allowing setting it to false to
&gt;&gt; enable the possibility of live links in an HTML cell renderer.

&gt; Sounds like a really good idea to fix this. I think I go with that, thank you
&gt; very much Derrell!

I see you used a slightly different fix. I&#39;m glad you were able to come up with something elegant to allow both functionalities.

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21202</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-10 09:08:46 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>&gt; Recall the history of Table. It was written very early in qooxdoo&#39;s history,
&gt; and provided a concept of &quot;virtual&quot; that was not available for any widget that
&gt; could provide table-like or tree-like functionality. As a &quot;version 1&quot; widget,
&gt; it was awesome. Unfortunately, the author disappeared into never-never-land
&gt; almost immediately after release of this widget, and I ended up learning many
&gt; of the ins and outs of how it worked (and created treevirtual based on it).
&gt; From the perspective of what was available at the time, the functionality of
&gt; Table was fabulous. It may have been possible to foresee the many uses Table
&gt; has since seen, but I can understand both not having foreseen all of them, and
&gt; not wanting to spend the time, initially, to allow for all of them.
&gt; 
&gt; With 20/20 hindsight, we now need the new qx.ui.virtual.Table to be completed,
&gt; so that we can eventually obsolete qx.ui.table.Table. (Hint, hint, hint. :-) )

Totally agree!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>