<bug>
          <bug_id>4320</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-11-15 14:34:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Add demo specific config.json files</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-11-29 19:42:02 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>app.demobrowser</component>
          <version>1.2.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.4</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Tino Butz">tinobutz</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          <cc>thron7</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21297</commentid>
            <who name="Tino Butz">tinobutz</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-15 14:34:41 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>For the mobile demos we need demo specific variants set. Right now the variant is set by the demo namespace. This worked so far, as the variant to emulate touch support in desktop browsers was named &quot;qx.mobile&quot;. We have changed the name of the variant to:

     &quot;variants&quot; :
      {
        &quot;qx.mobile.emulatetouch&quot; : [&quot;on&quot;]
      }

Please add a support for demo specific conifg.json files. The job configs should merge with the default config.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21322</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-16 09:08:00 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Do we have a quick fix for that for the upcoming release?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21387</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-18 11:35:44 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I don&#39;t see a quick fix for this, given the work load with other bugs that have 
long been scheduled for the next release.

I see there are two new variants for mobile:

   qx.mobile.emultatetouch
   qx.mobile.nativescroll

Need both be supported for the demos?

Could the qx.mobile.emulatetouch be initialized by the existing qx.mobile, like

   statics.define(&quot;qx.mobile.emulatetouch&quot;, [ &quot;on&quot;, &quot;off&quot; ],  
statics.get(&quot;qx.mobile&quot;));

in qx.core.Variant?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21388</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-18 12:19:08 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Tino said he can disable this feature for the release which would be ok, so we 
can address this after 1.3.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21405</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-18 16:13:41 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Here is a rough outline of a possible new config setup for the demos:

The default behaviour for a demo could be like this:
config.demo.json:
{
  ...
   &quot;source-ui.Widget&quot; : {
       &quot;extend&quot; : [&quot;default-source&quot;],
       &quot;let&quot;: {
           ...
       }
   }
}

It appears to me that all variations between demos can be collected in a list 
of specific macros, which will be used in the general job &quot;default-source&quot;. 
E.g. the &quot;let&quot; would contain a macro &quot;DEMO&quot;: &quot;ui.Widget&quot;, and default-source 
would use this as &quot;include&quot; : [&quot;demobrowser.demo.${DEMO}&quot;,...], &quot;settings&quot;: 
{&quot;qx.application&quot;: &quot;demobrowser.demo.${DEMO}&quot;, ..} and so forth. The 
&quot;default-source&quot; job would be included in the config, and would take the role 
of the current template.

Still, for each demo 6 jobs have to be created (source, source-Classic, 
source-Modern, build, build-Classic, build-Modern), as these jobs need to be 
invoked by the generator (as it currently stands). So gendata.py will still 
have to generate job entries for each demo.

One approach then would be, if a demo with an own config file is encountered, 
to skip generating jobs for this demo. Rather, an &quot;include&quot; entry would be 
generated for the demo&#39;s config file, and the config file needs to provide the 
6 obligatory jobs.

Both auto-generated and demo-specific jobs would take advantage of the 
pre-defined default jobs, which they extend. I&#39;ve commited a very preliminary 
./tool/default.json, which illustrates this. It contains all of the default 
definitions, and the demo-specific jobs only have to provide two macros (see 
the comment section at the beginning of default.json).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23187</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-09 20:13:17 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Support for demo-specific config files is now added. 

If you want to add config information for a specific demo, add it next to the 
demo&#39;s .html file, under
  source/demo/&lt;category&gt;/&lt;demoname&gt;.json

E.g. I&#39;ve added source/demo/animation/Login.json as an example. The contents 
should be a normal generator config file that defines two jobs, one for source, 
the other for the build version of the demo, e.g.
{
  &quot;jobs&quot;: 
  {
    &quot;source-animation.Login&quot; : {
      ...
    },
    &quot;build-animation.Login&quot; : {
      ...
    }
  }
}

So it&#39;s &quot;source-&lt;category&gt;.&lt;demoname&gt;&quot; and &quot;build-&lt;category&gt;.&lt;demoname&gt;&quot; you 
have to define (the naming is crucial).

These job definitions will then be picked up when the corresponding demo is 
being built. The caveat here is that those job definitions server as 
*ancestors* for the default jobs that are generated from the job template for 
each demo. That means, you can *add* keys, and add values to maps and lists, 
but you cannot remove settings from the default definition. Let&#39;s see how this 
works.

With r25493.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27688</commentid>
            <who name="Tino Butz">tinobutz</who>
            <bug_when>2011-11-29 19:42:02 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Verified + Closed</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>