<bug>
          <bug_id>4388</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-12-01 00:15:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Cannot set value of TextField under some circumstances in FF 4</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-05-16 09:46:04 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.form</component>
          <version>1.2.1</version>
          <rep_platform>Firefox 4.0</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>DUPLICATE</resolution>
          <dup_id>4095</dup_id>
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>major</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Jason Priebe">jpriebe</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Firefox</cf_browser>
          <cf_browser_version>4</cf_browser_version>

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21648</commentid>
            <who name="Jason Priebe">jpriebe</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-01 00:15:06 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I am having trouble setting the value of a TextField to &#39;&#39; when the text field is hidden.  Specifically, I think that the TextField has to be nested inside of one or more TabViews which are hidden.

I have constructed this demo in the Playground:

http://tinyurl.com/24xo9gs

I have been testing this with Firefox 4, beta 7 under Windows XP.

I have tried to trace into this problem in my own application via console logging (Firebug isn&#39;t working for me in FF4b7).  I&#39;ve traced through the various classes like qx.ui.form.AbstractField, qx.html.Input, and qx.bom.Input.  It appears that all the way down to qx.bom.Input, qooxdoo truly believes that it has set the value to an empty string, even though it doesn&#39;t change on screen.

Hope this helps!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21653</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-01 08:53:11 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I am pretty sure thats a bug of Firefox 4: https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=598603
As you can see, I already openend up a report for mozilla but there was not much movement yet.
We also have a reminder in out database: http://bugzilla.qooxdoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=4095
So im sorry but we can&#39;t do much about it. :(

*** This bug has been marked as a duplicate of bug 4095 ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21673</commentid>
            <who name="Jason Priebe">jpriebe</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-01 15:13:10 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks, Martin.  Believe it or not, I did search for an existing bug before I posted.  Apparently, I didn&#39;t search very well.  :-)

I feel better already, knowing that you know about the issue, and that the Firefox team knows about it.  Thanks for setting me straight!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21680</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-02 08:59:22 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #2)
&gt; Thanks, Martin.  Believe it or not, I did search for an existing bug before I
&gt; posted.  Apparently, I didn&#39;t search very well.  :-)
I do believe you for sure. Sometimes even I (managing it daily) loose bugs in bugzilla so that can happen all the time. ;)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>