<bug>
          <bug_id>4455</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-12-08 08:06:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>When using the HBox-Decorator, it often happens that the application in the IE looks different than in firefox</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:19:29 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.layout</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.4</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Uwe Stahl">uwe.stahl</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</assigned_to>
          <cc>alexander.steitz</cc>
    
    <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21844</commentid>
            <who name="Uwe Stahl">uwe.stahl</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-08 08:06:48 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>We now had several times the problem that our application looked different in the IE than in the firefox.
The reason for this difference was always the HBox-Decorator.

We are using the HBox-Decorator with a background-image.
If the height of the background-image does not match the height of the decorated area, then the Firefox stretches the image, whereas the IE does not stretch the image.

Therefore it happened several time that we changed the margin, padding or height and then have updated the background-image so that the background-image is displayd correctly in the firefox.
Later on, we have noticed that this background-image is not displayd correctly in the IE.

To reduce this browser-specific behaviour of qooxdoo, I would recommend to update the HBox-Decorator so that the background-image is not stretched vertically in the Firefox.
The qooxdoo documentation does not say anything about the vertical stretching of Images in the HBox-decorator. There is also no background-repeat parameter that could be used to control this vertical stretching.

All this what has been said about the HBox-decorator probably also applies to the VBox-Decorator.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21851</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-08 08:38:47 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report. We gona check that and come back to you if we have further questions.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22750</commentid>
            <who name="Uwe Stahl">uwe.stahl</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-15 15:49:28 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Now, another developer has run into the same issue.
The other developer has been using an HBox-decorator and has now spent an hour wondering why the layout looks fine in Firefox, but not in IE.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23353</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-17 14:57:32 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The behaviour of IE cannot be used for all other browsers. All other use the 
CSS3 border-image style for which it is not possible to prevent the stretching.

Additionally it is not possible to detect the misbehaviour of the HBox / VBox 
decorator effectively , so outputting a warning is not possible.

In this case however it is better to use the Grid decorator. If the widget is 
increased in height the layout is broken. Using the Grid decorator will be safe 
solution here.

Updated the documentation with revision #25749 which will be available at

http://manual.qooxdoo.org/devel/pages/gui_toolkit/ui_decorators.html

by the end of the week.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36506</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:19:29 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>