<bug>
          <bug_id>4456</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-12-08 08:26:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>The slice-image-job should be able to slice images for HBox-Decorators</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:27:15 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>DUPLICATE</resolution>
          <dup_id>2962</dup_id>
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.4</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Uwe Stahl">uwe.stahl</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21849</commentid>
            <who name="Uwe Stahl">uwe.stahl</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-08 08:26:06 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The slice-image-job of the qooxdoo-generator seems to be optimized for grid-decorators.
We would like to use this slice-image-job for an image that is used by the HBox-decorator, but have found some things that do not work so fine for the HBox-Images:

1. The slice-image-job always generates 9 images (-tl, -tr, -br, -bc, ...), but we need onlice 3 images for the HBox-decorator. Therefore we always have to delete these extra images manually.

2. The height of the slice &quot;-r&quot; of our HBox-decorator should be equal to the height of the image-template. This height of the slice &quot;-r&quot; should not be reduced be the height of the top-slice and the bottom-slice.
We were able to reach this by setting the top-border-width and bottom-border-width to 0:
  border-width: [0, 68, 0, 68]
But then we get the following warning when running the slice-image-job
  Magick: geometry does not contain image &#39;...&#39;  @warning/transform.c/CropImage/620
This warning is generated by Image-Magick because the slice-image-job calls Image-Magick with the height 0.


Therefore I would recommend the following improvement of the slice-image-job:
The slice-image-job should be able to handle 0 values for the height like:
  border-width: [0, 68, 0, 68]
Then the slice-image-job should automatically detect that the height of the corresponding slices (-tl, -t, -tr, -bl, -b, -br) is 0 so that the slice-image-job does not have to call Image-Magick for these slices.
The result would be that the slice-image-job would only generate 3 images (-l, -c, -r) and these images could be directly used for the HBox-Decorator</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21867</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-08 14:19:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Daniel, pleas check the feedback. Havent we changed something in that area recently?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21869</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-08 14:29:26 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Yes, the fix for bug #2962 should cover these requirements. Uwe, if there&#39;s something I&#39;ve missed, please reopen this report.

*** This bug has been marked as a duplicate of bug 2962 ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>39404</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:27:15 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>