<bug>
          <bug_id>4461</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-12-08 18:10:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>ProgressBar: Review &#39;ProgressBar&#39; Contrib</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:28:03 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.indicator</component>
          <version>1.3</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>https://qooxdoo-contrib.svn.sourceforge.net/svnroot/qooxdoo-contrib/trunk/qooxdoo-contrib/ProgressBar</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.5</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Adrian Olaru">adrian.olaru</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21880</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-08 18:10:15 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>There is a contribution &#39;ProgressBar&#39; with the same objective as our new 
ProgressBar widget (s.URL).

(a) Check if the contrib code contains useful features for the framework widget.

(b) Come up with a strategy how to position the contrib, e.g. get in touch with 
the current maintainer/mailing list, add a hint in the contrib&#39;s README to the 
framework widget, remove its demo from the Contrib Demobrowser, etc.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21885</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-09 08:19:03 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Absolutely agree with you Thomas. 

Adrain, please check the first mentioned taks and see what could be useful for the framework widget.

As soon as we know that the framework widget can completely replace the contrib widget, we should think about a way to deprecate it and in time, remove it. Of course only in collaboration with the community and maintainer of that contrib.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22141</commentid>
            <who name="Adrian Olaru">adrian.olaru</who>
            <bug_when>2011-01-10 10:43:36 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>How can I found the maintainer(s) of this contrib? I could only found the authors.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22143</commentid>
            <who name="Adrian Olaru">adrian.olaru</who>
            <bug_when>2011-01-10 11:42:48 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I think that the contrib progressbar tries to do much more that it should do. It has a status text built in (with step status and % status), it has methods for setting the bar color, it has more ways to update the progress bar value trough update method.

Although I think that there is value on all these features of the contrib version, the trunk version is more light weight and it concentrate only on being a progressbar widget. 

For things like status text, you can use the provided events to get notified when the % is changed or when it&#39;s complete. It&#39;s fully integrated with the theme system and it seems more qooxdooish to me than the contrib version. 

This is my overall opinion about the two.

My opinion is to keep the progress bar as simple as it is and use the events provided for other things that can be added (like a status text).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22163</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-01-11 11:47:48 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Adrian, I agree with you. Did you also take a look at the controb code? Is is possible to use the framework progress bar as base for the one in the contrib? If the contrib is a pure feature addition it would be good to reduce the amount of code duplications.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22164</commentid>
            <who name="Adrian Olaru">adrian.olaru</who>
            <bug_when>2011-01-11 11:54:58 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Yes, I&#39;ve seen the contrib version (although I still don&#39;t know who is its maintainer).

The contrib version has more features than the framework version has (i.e. a label, bar color API, update the value in different ways, etc), so I think that the framework version can be a base for this contrib vesion.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22166</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-01-11 12:31:21 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>As for maintainers, I think there currently is none. Even Christian Boulanger who did some work on it didn&#39;t take over mainainership, IIRC. So there is nobody you need to worry about if you work on it.

As for the API, my impression was that the framework widget could use a few more features beyond a bare bar that could be turned on or off at will (e.g. percent label), as I suppose most people would want to use those. But I leave that decision to others, and if everybody feel a bare bar is the way to go, then so be it.

In any case, the contrib should make optimal use of the framework widget, and there should be a qooxdoo 1.3-compatible version of the contrib (e.g. 0.2). If it turns out that the contrib doesn&#39;t offer some benefit over the native framework widget, then its development should be frozen (ie. limited to fixing old versions), and the top-level README should just point to the framework widget.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24827</commentid>
            <who name="Adrian Olaru">adrian.olaru</who>
            <bug_when>2011-06-01 15:22:28 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Ok, I just took another look at the contrib. My opinion is that if we still wanna keep the contrib (no maintainer), we need to base it on framework&#39;s ProgressBar widget. I still think the PB widget should be stay as it is for now. 

If we wanna refactoring the contrib, we should add a new bug for it.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24833</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-06-03 10:05:03 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Then go ahead and open a new report for it.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>39677</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:28:03 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>