<bug>
          <bug_id>4462</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-12-09 12:41:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Reduce the Number of Version Strings in the Framework</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:25:26 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>other</component>
          <version>1.3</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://qooxdoo.org/documentation/general/how_to_build_a_release#adjust_version_number</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.6</target_milestone>
          <dependson>4391</dependson>
    
    <dependson>4567</dependson>
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21886</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-09 12:41:53 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>There are quite a few version strings spread across the framework that all 
represent the current qooxdoo version.

Among those places are (s. URL):
- ./version.txt  -- the &quot;master&quot; place for the version string
- ./index.html
- ./readme.txt
- ./framework/Manifest.json
- ./documentation/manual/source/conf.py

Some of these files contain the version string multiple times. Although it 
might not be possible to have the version string in just one single place, and 
all other locations just referencing it, it would be highly desireable to 
reduce the number of literal occurrences in the framework, as a manual, global 
search-and-replace during version shifts is tedious and error-prone.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22355</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-01-19 11:54:33 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The manual already uses a version macro, the value of which is taken from 
documentation/manual/source/conf.py.

This and other occurrences of version strings are handled by a batch utility, 
tool/admin/bin/bumpqxversion.py, which takes a version string, looks up all 
those occurrences in the framework, and patches the version. See the linked URL 
for details.

It is of course desireable to have as few places as possible that need to be 
patches on a version shift, so the use of macros, variables and placeholders 
that get automatically updated is highly desirable (like the many version 
occurrences in the manual pages that are fed from just the conf.py value). This 
works nicely for the manual, as during development you have to &quot;compile&quot; manual 
pages anyway (through Sphinx) before you look at them, so replacing the macro 
during development cycles is a non-issue, and links e.g. to the Demobrowser and 
Apiviewer are covered nicely.

The Apiviewer, OTOH, although also &quot;compiled&quot;, doesn&#39;t support a variable macro 
in JSDoc comments, so something like this is not possible currently:

   /**
   * The AliasManager is automatically invoked in various situations, e.g. when
   * resolving the icon image for a button, so it is very common to register
   * aliases for resource id&#39;s (s. 
http://manual.qooxdoo.org/%{qxversion}/pages/gui_toolkit/ui_resources.html).
   */
 
(See qx/ui/table/__init__.js for another example). It should be possible to 
support a qxversion macro in JSDoc comments as well. This might merrit its own 
bug.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27604</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-11-24 12:48:44 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The last open item, version macros in JSDoc comments (bug#4391), has been 
fixed, so I think we have covered all occurrences of qooxdoo version strings. 
Hence closing this bug.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>38748</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:25:26 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>