<bug>
          <bug_id>4473</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-12-13 08:08:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>DateChooser: (Re-)Implement WEEKDAY_FORMAT</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:20:15 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.form</component>
          <version>1.3</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.4</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Deacon">dfrost999</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          <cc>peyman.vasegh</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21909</commentid>
            <who name="Deacon">dfrost999</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-13 08:08:29 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext />
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21911</commentid>
            <who name="Deacon">dfrost999</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-13 08:16:25 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The weekday-format of the DateChooser widget used to be configurable. Please re-implement, because now one has to &quot;copy-and-paste&quot; DateChooser.js just to change the format, because _updateDatePane uses private property __weekdayLabelArr.

Best regards</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21915</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-13 08:49:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>*** Bug 4474 has been marked as a duplicate of this bug. ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21919</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-13 08:59:23 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report. 

(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; The weekday-format of the DateChooser widget used to be configurable. 
When did that change? Do you have some more details about what feature has been removed when?

&gt; Please re-implement, because now one has to &quot;copy-and-paste&quot; DateChooser.js just to
&gt; change the format, because _updateDatePane uses private property
&gt; __weekdayLabelArr.
That does not sound like a good thing at all. Could you maybe explain what the problem is with the current implementation and why you want to subclass it? Maybe its a general bug we should address?

Thanks, 
Martin</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21942</commentid>
            <who name="Deacon">dfrost999</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-13 18:26:08 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Martin,

I could not find the original source file with the implementation of WEEKDAY_FORMAT but found a link to a patch discussed here: http://www.mail-archive.com/qooxdoo-devel@lists.sourceforge.net/msg13001.html
I know it&#39;s a minor thing but this is the kind of stuff customers often want customized.
The general problem is that often to just customize small aspects of the standard components one has to copy the whole class file because overrideable member functions use private properties (as an example you have to copy the whole Spinner.js just to be able to add a simple transformer for the value property, or as mentioned for DateChooser to customize the weekday-format you cannot just customize _updateDatePane because of the private __weekdayLabelArr; then for convenience reasons one has to sub-class DateField as well just to use this modified DateChooser.)
As yooxdoo is discouraging the use of protected members (there is even a warning for this) but not having adequate accessors, it becomes more difficult to just inherit and modify one or two functions for the result desired. 
Anyway, maybe just something to keep in mind when implementing the standard components: they will most likely be customized in many (sometimes disgusting ;) ways...
Thanks for the great Framework!

D.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21959</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-14 16:26:15 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Totally agree, those components should be customizable in general. :) We will take care of that.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22128</commentid>
            <who name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</who>
            <bug_when>2011-01-04 16:06:53 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed with r24500 on trunk.

To bring some light into this, I pick-axed my git repository and found out that the static WEEKDAY_FORMAT was actually removed by the patch (r10928) Deacon was referring to. 

Steen Jansdal summarized his patch with:

&quot;The first letter of day names does not obey changing of locale. The same 
goes for the week numbering algoritm, that can differ from country to 
country.&quot;

Frankly, I don&#39;t know why the static was removed in the first place.

(24500! And it wasn&#39;t even on purpose)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22590</commentid>
            <who name="peyman">peyman.vasegh</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-08 00:40:46 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi,

DateField drop down window is not showing Day-of-Week (M T W...)

Today (Feb 7, 2011) I downloaded qx1.4-pre from GitHub and rebuilt my application; but found that DOW is not showing properly. It seems like this is the thread dealing with this bug.

Regards,
Peter.

p.s.: not sure if I had privileges to re-open the bug. let me know if not!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22591</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-08 08:40:14 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #7)
&gt; Hi,
&gt; 
&gt; DateField drop down window is not showing Day-of-Week (M T W...)
&gt; 
&gt; Today (Feb 7, 2011) I downloaded qx1.4-pre from GitHub and rebuilt my
&gt; application; but found that DOW is not showing properly. It seems like this is
&gt; the thread dealing with this bug.
Are you speaking of something like we have currently on the devel version: http://demo.qooxdoo.org/devel/demobrowser/#widget~DateField.html

I just checked the DateField with my checkout from yesterday and did not see anything wrang. Maybe you have another language / browser / OS combination? Can you perhaps share some more details whats wrong, a screenshot maybe?

&gt; 
&gt; p.s.: not sure if I had privileges to re-open the bug. let me know if not!
If something&#39;s wrong, sure, reopen!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22654</commentid>
            <who name="peyman">peyman.vasegh</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-09 23:57:02 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hello Martin,

The link you mentioned:
http://demo.qooxdoo.org/devel/demobrowser/#widget~DateField.html
is displaying (...cld...cld...) instead of day-of-week under the following environments:

Ubuntu 10.10 FF 3
Win 7, FF 3, IE 9
Win Vista, FF 3, IE 8

Please let me know when you get a chance to fix it.

Thanks.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22656</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-10 08:36:19 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>We already got a separate bug for that: #4602. Please add yourself as CC to get the updates.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22778</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-16 14:51:25 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The change has caused a regression: Locale changes are not reflected in the day 
names anymore.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22780</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-16 15:19:59 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Made WEEKDAY_FORMAT into a proper string, rather than a DateFormat instance, 
par. MONTH_YEAR_FORMAT; now locale changes are being picked up again; also 
lifted WEEK_FORMAT to the statics section; now all important format strings are 
available through the statics.

With r25059.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36816</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:20:15 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>