<bug>
          <bug_id>4528</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2010-12-31 16:25:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Inconsistent mouse wheel scrolling speed across WebKit browsers on OSX.</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-05-16 10:25:02 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.bars</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>Other</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>minor</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.4</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Nick Watkins">karbon</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Other</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22118</commentid>
            <who name="Nick Watkins">karbon</who>
            <bug_when>2010-12-31 16:25:12 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I first noticed in 1.2 that the scroll speed was painfully slow in framework 1.2 and above in Chrome 8 on OSX. In 1.1 it&#39;s much better, but not quite as sensitive as the native scroll speed in the OS.

I went back and compared Safari 5.0 and Firefox 3.6. Firefox is consistent across versions of the framework after 1.0, and consistently good. Safari&#39;s scroll speed is absurdly fast on 1.0 and after, but speed is consistent across versions up to trunk.

I compared by simply going to the following links and opening up a few folders:
http://demo.qooxdoo.org/1.0/demobrowser/#
http://demo.qooxdoo.org/1.1/demobrowser/#
http://demo.qooxdoo.org/1.2/demobrowser/#
http://demo.qooxdoo.org/1.3/demobrowser/#</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22155</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-01-11 09:54:39 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hello Nick an thanks for the report. 
Were on that topic for some time now try to fix it. The main problem is, that every browser has its own mouse wheel delta. Even worse, some browsers change that now and then. As the only chance is to use browser sniffing to normalize that behavior, old qooxdoo versions are likely not aware of new browser versions if there are changes.
I hade some kind of solution without browser sniffing which solved that problem but it didn&#39;t work that well. But still, we should check for the 1.4 release, that every browser has at least for the release a decent scrolling speed.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23358</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-17 15:26:22 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The default mouse wheel calculation in don now without any browser checks which means that every future browser should be at least somehow good to use. 

Committed that with r25750</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>