<bug>
          <bug_id>4530</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-01-04 14:56:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Text label problems when zooming in the browser</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:25:16 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop</component>
          <version>1.3</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.3.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Pascal">pascal.chorus</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22125</commentid>
            <who name="Pascal">pascal.chorus</who>
            <bug_when>2011-01-04 14:56:22 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>There is a problem regarding the zoom function in web browsers.
It can be reproduced in the qooxdoo demo browser.
 
When I open the demo browser in Firefox 3.6.13 the tree view appears on the left side containing icons with labels.
The texts in the labels are shown completely.
When I zoom by pressing ctrl and scrolling the mouse wheel, some of the labels are cutted and &quot;...&quot; is shown at the end of the label.
If I zoom a second time, sometimes the labels are shown completely again.
 
I assume that there is a problem regarding the calculation of the label&#39;s width.
At some zoom levels, the width is not sufficient for the rendered label.


Some further information by Derrell Lipman:
There was a bug about this long ago. IIRC, the problem was that the browsers didn&#39;t generate an event when the page was zoomed using ctrl-plus and ctrl-minus, so qooxdoo couldn&#39;t listen for it and adjust the layout. I don&#39;t know whether (some of) the browsers now generate an event, or whether mouse-wheel zooming is different.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22154</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-01-11 09:39:58 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Looks like there is still no solution for detecting a page zoom [1][2]. All other solutions I know of are way too complicated (like using flash) for such a feature. Reacting on a resize event is already implemented. I&#39;m sorry but can&#39;t see a way of fixing that not wasting too mich time for it.

[1] http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1713771/how-to-detect-page-zoom-level-in-all-modern-browsers
[2] http://stackoverflow.com/questions/995914/catch-browsers-zoom-event-in-javascript</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>38691</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:25:16 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>