<bug>
          <bug_id>4600</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-01-31 17:58:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Groupbox title appears at the bottom of the group</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-06-20 09:43:59 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>1.3</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.4</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="John Spackman">john.spackman</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22494</commentid>
            <who name="John Spackman">john.spackman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-01-31 17:58:45 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>There is a layout issue reproduced in FF and Chrome where the title of the groupbox appears at the bottom of the groupbox, not at the top.  I&#39;ve had this for some time when it has not been reproducible (a refresh usually sorts it out), but I&#39;ve unable until now to produce a playgroup snippet that reliably demonstrates it.

The problem occurs in this example if you click the button, dismiss the first window that pops up, and then click the button again - http://tinyurl.com/4sd5kdt.  The first time you click the &quot;click me&quot; button, the code creates (but does not show) a window (&quot;dlg&quot; variable) with two groupboxes, and then creates _and_shows_ another window (&quot;errorWindow&quot; variable); after you manually close the window and then click the &quot;click me&quot; button for the second time, the &quot;dlg&quot; window that was previously created is then shown.  The Groupboxes in &quot;dlg&quot; will be upside down.

I&#39;ve found two workarounds for this: (1) do not set the layout properties of the window to set the opening position of the &quot;errorWindow&quot;, or (2) if you create a second window, show it immediately – don&#39;t hang onto it until later.

Option (2) seems like it would be an unintended restriction by Qx, but I&#39;m not sure setting the layout properties as in option(1) is permitted.  OTOH I&#39;ve had the same (but intermittent) layout problems with GroupBox when displayed on Composite&#39;s that are initially hidden, ie I think it&#39;s not a Window/setLayoutProperties problem.

The playground code is:

var doc = this.getRoot();

var btn = new qx.ui.form.Button(&quot;click me&quot;);
var supl = null;
var dlg = null;
btn.addListener(&quot;execute&quot;, function() {
  if (!dlg) {
		dlg = new qx.ui.window.Window(&quot;Search for a product line&quot;);
		dlg.setLayout(new qx.ui.layout.VBox(5));
		
		var grp = new qx.ui.groupbox.GroupBox(&quot;Search Criteria&quot;);
		dlg.add(grp);
		
		dlg.add(new qx.ui.groupbox.GroupBox(&quot;Another Box&quot;));
	}
	if (!supl) {
		var errorWindow = new qx.ui.window.Window(&quot;close me and click &#39;click me&#39; again&quot;);
		var lp = errorWindow.getLayoutProperties()||{};
		lp.top = 200;
		errorWindow.setLayoutProperties(lp);
		errorWindow.setWidth(600);
		errorWindow.show();
		supl = 1;
		return;
	}
	dlg.show();
}, this);

doc.add(btn, {
	left : 100,
	right : 100
});</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22503</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-01 09:35:25 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report, John. Could reproduce it on my mac as well. We should check whats wrong here.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24534</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-16 10:09:44 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>John, that seems to be fixed with 1.4 already. Just checked the example with 1.4 and could not reproduce it. But still can reproduce it with the 1.3 release:
http://tinyurl.com/5saexnm

I mark that bug as fixed for 1.4 even that I don&#39;t know what fixed it in the end. If would ne nice if you could check it too and reopen the bug if you have any trouble.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24547</commentid>
            <who name="John Spackman">john.spackman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-16 12:16:02 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #2)
&gt; John, that seems to be fixed with 1.4 already. Just checked the example with
&gt; 1.4 and could not reproduce it. But still can reproduce it with the 1.3
&gt; release:
&gt; http://tinyurl.com/5saexnm
&gt; 
&gt; I mark that bug as fixed for 1.4 even that I don&#39;t know what fixed it in the
&gt; end. If would ne nice if you could check it too and reopen the bug if you have
&gt; any trouble.

Hi Martin,

That works for me too - I&#39;ve had the problem intermittently for ages but that was the only reproducible test case I could come up with, I&#39;ll keep a look out for it and reopen as you suggest.

John</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>