<bug>
          <bug_id>4682</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-02-18 13:57:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Error when using combination effects: Property queue of an instance of qx.fx.Base is not (yet) ready!</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-08-20 13:30:06 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>website.animation</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Uwe Stahl">uwe.stahl</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
    
    <cc>tinobutz</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22803</commentid>
            <who name="Uwe Stahl">uwe.stahl</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-18 13:57:44 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>We are getting the following error message when using the pulsate effect (qx.fx.effect.combination.Pulsate):

  Property queue of an instance of qx.fx.Base is not (yet) ready!

This issue can be reproduced by running the appended code in the qooxdoo playground.
The button &quot;Start effect&quot; starts the pulsate effect that runs for 2 seconds.
If the button &quot;Stop effect&quot; is pressed while the effect is running, we get the error &quot;Property queue of an instance of qx.fx.Base is not (yet) ready!&quot;.

The cause of this bug is probably that the class qx.fx.effect.combination.Pulsate does not have a cancel method, that cancels all sub-effects.
(A cancel of all combination effects is therefore not possible at all.)
This means that the sub-effects are still running after the pulsate effect has been cancelled and then disposed. And the effects that are still running although they are disposed

Another point is that an effect should be stopped automatically when it is disposed.

This issue is not very critical for us. As a workaround, we will not dispose these effects to avoid this problem.

-- ------------------------------

var doc = this.getRoot();

var animatedObject = new qx.ui.basic.Image(&quot;icon/22/apps/internet-web-browser.png&quot;);
doc.add(animatedObject,
{
  left : 300,
  top  : 50
});

var effect = null;

var buttonStart = new qx.ui.form.Button(&quot;Start effect&quot;);
buttonStart.addListener(&quot;execute&quot;, function(e) {
  effect = new qx.fx.effect.combination.Pulsate(animatedObject.getContentElement().getDomElement());
  effect.setDuration(2);
  effect.start();
});
doc.add(buttonStart,
{
  left : 100,
  top  : 50
});

var buttonStop = new qx.ui.form.Button(&quot;Stop effect&quot;);
buttonStop.addListener(&quot;execute&quot;, function(e) {
  if(effect) {
    effect.cancel();
    effect.dispose();
    effect = null;
  }
});
doc.add(buttonStop,
{
  left : 100,
  top  : 80
});</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22807</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-18 15:16:16 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Gabi, please have a look.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23001</commentid>
            <who name="Gabriel Munteanu">jajalinux</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-28 15:53:41 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>fixed on trunk with rev. 25281
fixed on 1_3_x branch with rev. 25282

I added a cancel method to Pulsate class that cancels first the member Fade effects and then cancels itself.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23002</commentid>
            <who name="Uwe Stahl">uwe.stahl</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-28 16:18:15 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I have successfully tested that the implemented fix has solved our problem.

The same problem that has fixed for the effect qx.fx.combination.Pulsate still exists for the other combination effects like qx.fx.combination.Shake.
This means that it is not possible to cancel the Shake effect.
I expected a generic fix for all combination effect, but got a fix for only the Pulsate effect that we need.
Well, since that is all what we need, thats okay for me.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23005</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-01 08:06:05 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thats a good point, Uwe. I would prefer a more generic solution as well! Gabriel, please check if thats possible. Maybe check if its possible to include that cancel method into the base.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23010</commentid>
            <who name="Gabriel Munteanu">jajalinux</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-01 09:37:47 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>yes, i went for Base class modification first myself. the idea is to have a generic way of an effect to have child/sub effects. this way, a cancel in Base would first check for child/sub effects, cancel them if found, and then cancel itself.
I didn&#39;t want to make such a big move - I always try to do the minimal change to the code that solve a certain bug - because, in this case, I already have a animation task that has a possible goal of redoing the animation framework itself, so this effect - child effects thing would go there.
check http://bugzilla.qooxdoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=4706.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23028</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-02 08:08:22 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Ok, so we don&#39;t need to get that fixed right away but mark that bug as dependency of the main &quot;redo animation&quot; bug to keep in mind to fix that in a general way.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27440</commentid>
            <who name="Tino Butz">tinobutz</who>
            <bug_when>2011-11-07 16:33:24 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Martin,

Please have a look on this bug as it is related with your animation bug.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30001</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2012-07-04 08:53:43 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This is a bug of the deprecated fx layer which will be removed anyway.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>