<bug>
          <bug_id>4700</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-02-23 16:28:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Slider&#39;s vertical orientation is &quot;backwards&quot; for many applications</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:47:19 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.bars</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22925</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-23 16:28:04 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The vertical orientation of the Slider produces the minimum value at the top of movement, and the maximum value at the bottom of movement. This is backwards for many applications. Consider a volume control slider or a power control slider. The intuitive operation would be to move the slider UP to increase the volume or increase the power, DOWN to decrease it.

Attempts to set the &quot;minimum&quot; property to the higher value and the &quot;maximum&quot; property to the lower value results in an error.

I suggest that in addition to an &quot;orientation&quot; property, there also be a &quot;direction&quot; property that determines whether the minimum values it to the top/left (as it is currently) or at the bottom/right.

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22931</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-24 08:15:13 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report Derrell. Would&#39;t it be enough that the developer can set a start value and a end value. This no information about orientation and direction and could be configured for all use cases as desired.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22936</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-24 12:53:42 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; Thanks for the report Derrell. Would&#39;t it be enough that the developer can set
&gt; a start value and a end value. This no information about orientation and
&gt; direction and could be configured for all use cases as desired.

If you are proposing renaming the &quot;minimum&quot; and &quot;maximum&quot; properties to &quot;startValue&quot; and &quot;endValue&quot; allowing either one to have the lower value, then yes, that would do fine for my purposes. It breaks backward compatibility, though, so I&#39;m not sure that&#39;s what you&#39;re proposing.

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22957</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-02-25 08:58:58 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>That was my first though how I would implement it in a new widget. I&#39;m not sure if that change is worth the deprecation. We will see the time we fix this how to solve it.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35864</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:47:19 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>