<bug>
          <bug_id>4737</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-03-04 17:47:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Provide mechanism for printable API docs</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:45:45 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23083</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-04 17:47:05 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>An announcement recently indicated that the manual was reorganized to provide the option of creating the manual in various formats, including a printable book. Please add the ability to generate printable versions of API documentation as well, in addition to the HTML versions.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23084</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-04 21:22:40 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>One possible option to achieve that could be to use the Sphinx system for API documentation as well. Sphinx has the option of extracting documentation from source code. I don&#39;t know how exactly that works at the moment, but if this proves viable then we might be able to use Spinx to extract JSDoc comments. We would need to convert the comment markup to reST, and would need to adapt the generation of the data for the Apiviewer. But then we could use Sphinx to also produce PDF as an output format for the API.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26904</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-23 15:11:57 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Another option would be start from the Json that is generated as api data.

The advantage could be that this data already encodes a lot of relational 
information, like inheritance chains, cross-linking of data types, etc.

But the Json data doesn&#39;t contain any rendering information, so it has to be 
&quot;interpreted&quot;. A renderer could be written, e.g. in Python, to render the data 
e.g. in reST. From there HTML and PDF formats would be accessible.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35279</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:45:45 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>