<bug>
          <bug_id>4740</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-03-05 15:09:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Alternatives for contrib downloading</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 09:21:45 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>1.3</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          <dependson>6674</dependson>
          
          <votes>8</votes>
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Stanislav Sinyagin">ssinyagin</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23089</commentid>
            <who name="Stanislav Sinyagin">ssinyagin</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-05 15:09:32 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Sourceforge SVN service is not always stable and available.

It will be great to have two configurable options (via &quot;let&quot; varibles):

CONTRIB_CHECKSVN: number of hours before re-checking the SVN for a new version;

CONTRIB_LOCATION:  alternative link to get Contribs from. It could be a local, manually checked out repository, or a URL to some alternative external repository.

Ideally it would also be able to fetch from Git repositories, such as Github.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23097</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-07 09:04:47 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thomas, what do you think? Could that be a good idea? I like the idea of using a git repo which fits to my vision of qooxdoo in the future.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23104</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-07 12:28:14 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>For one thing I want bug#3855 be implemented. This has the highest priority, as it can positively affect all qooxdoo installations in use. We need an abstraction from the repository interface when querying current contrib versions.

This is independent from the question *how often* the version should be checked, so this option can be implemented independently (which I think is a good one).

It is also independent from where and how a contrib is actually *downloaded*. It would be ideal if the config allowed a homogenous addressing scheme that works across different storage formats. Local, manually checked-out contribs already work, just provide a path string to the Manifest like with any library. For others (SVN, Github, arbit. URL) there should be a unified access procedure to keep things simple. Recursive URL download already works, maybe that&#39;s enought for all, and only the config syntax has to be extended.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23107</commentid>
            <who name="Stanislav Sinyagin">ssinyagin</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-07 14:33:40 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>once we&#39;re on it, I also don&#39;t like one huge repository for all contribs. Checking out the whole lot is quite a bit of an effort.

So, ideally it would be some central calalog (easy to mirror locally) of all available contributions, with links to their individual SVN or Git repositories or download paths.

Also one may think of downloading a .tar.gz packaged contribution instead of recursive source download.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23108</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-07 14:43:04 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #3)
&gt; once we&#39;re on it, I also don&#39;t like one huge repository for all contribs.
&gt; Checking out the whole lot is quite a bit of an effort.

I never do that, and there&#39;s no need to. I only check out individual contribs.

Also, keep in mind that checking out is for contrib *developers*, whereas the majority of contrib *users* don&#39;t have an interest in the checkout; they only need the download.

&gt; So, ideally it would be some central calalog (easy to mirror locally) of all
&gt; available contributions, with links to their individual SVN or Git repositories
&gt; or download paths.

This exists: http://qooxdoo.org/contrib/project

&gt; 
&gt; Also one may think of downloading a .tar.gz packaged contribution instead of
&gt; recursive source download.

&lt;sigh&gt; ... yes, but as long as the generator needs the files on disk individually, why not download them individually.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23111</commentid>
            <who name="Stanislav Sinyagin">ssinyagin</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-07 15:22:06 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #4)
&gt; (In reply to comment #3)
&gt; &gt; once we&#39;re on it, I also don&#39;t like one huge repository for all contribs.
&gt; &gt; Checking out the whole lot is quite a bit of an effort.
&gt; 
&gt; I never do that, and there&#39;s no need to. I only check out individual contribs.

yes, SVN allows that. But not Git. So, if there&#39;s a mirror on Github, one would pull the whole lot.


&gt; Also, keep in mind that checking out is for contrib *developers*, whereas the
&gt; majority of contrib *users* don&#39;t have an interest in the checkout; they only
&gt; need the download.

true. and that&#39;s why I speak about a new package distribution system :)

&gt; &gt; So, ideally it would be some central calalog (easy to mirror locally) of all
&gt; &gt; available contributions, with links to their individual SVN or Git repositories
&gt; &gt; or download paths.
&gt; 
&gt; This exists: http://qooxdoo.org/contrib/project

I was meaning some kind of a database, in some kind of machine-readable form.
Not Wiki really :)

&gt; &gt; Also one may think of downloading a .tar.gz packaged contribution instead of
&gt; &gt; recursive source download.
&gt; 
&gt; &lt;sigh&gt; ... yes, but as long as the generator needs the files on disk
&gt; individually, why not download them individually.

then you would be able to work with packages and versioning for each contribution. 

so, the current contrib system is OK, but for a long-term solution, there are ways for improvement. Also there are lots of out-of-the-box packaging systems, like Debian debs or Redhat RPMs or anything :)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>