<bug>
          <bug_id>480</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2007-06-11 17:26:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Refining the width property init attribute to &quot;auto&quot; has no effect for a qx.ui.layout.HorizontalBoxLayout derived class</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2007-07-09 11:10:15 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.layout</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>INVALID</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1545</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2007-06-11 17:26:44 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&#39;ve derived a class from qx.ui.layout.HorizontalBoxLayout where I refine the width property so the init value is &quot;auto&quot;:

    width : {
      refine : true,
      init   : &quot;auto&quot;
    },
    
Then a few RadioBoxes are added to an instance of that class. The width of the horizontal box is not calculated correctly: The width should be the sum of the width plus some padding and border, but the width seems to be only a few pixes. The RadioBoxes are displayed correctly one after the other from left to right corresponding their adding order.

If I set the width via

   this.setWidth(&quot;auto&quot;) in the constructor the width is calculated correct.

So my impression is that the refinement of this property has not effect.


The dom inspector of firebug shows that the width of the div of the instance is not set.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1566</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2007-06-13 16:59:23 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I think I found the problem:

In TreeFolder.js in method open, the global cursor is set to &quot;progress&quot; to indicate work in progress while opening the tree folder.

       this.getTopLevelWidget().setGlobalCursor(&quot;progress&quot;);

If this call is commented out IE7 opens the tree folder without delay.



</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1567</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2007-06-13 17:01:09 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; I think I found the problem:
&gt; 
&gt; In TreeFolder.js in method open, the global cursor is set to &quot;progress&quot; to
&gt; indicate work in progress while opening the tree folder.
&gt; 
&gt;        this.getTopLevelWidget().setGlobalCursor(&quot;progress&quot;);
&gt; 
&gt; If this call is commented out IE7 opens the tree folder without delay.
&gt; 

Sorry this was meant for another bug.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1571</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2007-06-14 12:59:38 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>You must add a initWidth() to the constructor as described in the property documentation.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1572</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2007-06-14 13:19:35 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #3)
&gt; You must add a initWidth() to the constructor as described in the property
&gt; documentation.
&gt; 

Ah here is the paragraph:

&gt; If you do not use the init method you must be sure that the instances created from &gt; the classes are in a consistent state. The getter will return the init value even if not &gt; initialized. This may be acceptable in some cases, e.g. for properties without apply &gt; or event. But there are other cases, where the developer needs to be carefully and &gt; call the init method because otherwise the getter returns wrong information about &gt; the internal state (due to an inconsistency between init and applied value).

But how can I be sure that a refined a property does or does not need the call to initMyRefinedProperty? By walking up the class hierarchy and studying the code?

Would it be possible to have something like 

    this.initilizeProperties();

which does property init stuff?
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1573</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2007-06-14 14:02:02 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>All automated things where to late (if only placed in Widget) and to performance critical. Many of our properties do not need the initialization. I think these are about 60% of the cases.

You have to study the code of the super classes. But generally you just must know which properties have any influence in the apply routine which must be executed to correctly initialize the init value. Typically critical things are stuff which will be reflected to the layout system and things which redirect values to styles and attributes e.g. tabIndex, cursor, ...</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1916</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2007-07-09 11:10:15 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>