<bug>
          <bug_id>4832</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-03-21 16:14:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Hovered state is not applied to atom icon if icon is set manually.</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-05-16 09:46:05 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>Firefox 4.0</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Linux</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>INVALID</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Johannes Kissel">johannes.kissel</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Firefox</cf_browser>
          <cf_browser_version>4</cf_browser_version>

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23440</commentid>
            <who name="Johannes Kissel">johannes.kissel</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-21 16:14:11 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Lets assume a button appearance which defines different icons for normal and hovered state.

The different icons are not applied if the button icon is set manually.

Example: http://tinyurl.com/6xhzsep</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23444</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-22 08:20:58 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the bug report and the good playground example. But sadly, I have to close the bug as invalid. 

This behavior is due to a simple fallback chain in the property system. The highest priority has the user value, which is the one you set for the right button in the user code. If no user value is given, the themed valus is used. This means that the theme is evaluated and reacts on state changes. As a last option, we use the init value. But as you can see, as soon as you have a user value set in the code, the value coming from the theme is not taken into account which means, no hovered icon anymore.

This is, in my opinion, the proper behavior. Imagine it is the way you expected it, how would you get rid of the hovered icon? We don&#39;t have an API for that so its not possible.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>