<bug>
          <bug_id>4890</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-03-28 19:17:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Tree controller allows multiple bindings to one property but this doesn&#39;t work</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-08-08 08:20:28 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.databinding</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>minor</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.4.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter>qooxdoo</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23680</commentid>
            <who name="">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-28 19:17:44 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi,

by accident I had set up a tree/treemodel/tree controller and used a delegate with bindItem that way that I had set up two bindings from two model properties to the same property of the tree item:

controller.bindProperty(&quot;negate&quot;, &quot;font&quot;, ...);
controller.bindProperty(&quot;enabled&quot;, &quot;font&quot;, ...);

Because this completely unsupported by the way the controller is currently implemented, it should report an error for this at create time and/or should refuse to create such.

At the moment the code silently creates the items but fails to remove tree nodes and throws an error at removal. 

Cheers,
Axel</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23685</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-03-29 08:58:57 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report. :) I will check that.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24994</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-06-08 15:50:46 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Just checked that out and seems like this is a bigger issue than I thought in the first place. Sometimes it could be very handy to have such a binding and we are doing it already the multi column tree demo. Thats why we should change the architecture to get that working because as you said, this can fail during the clean up process.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25834</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-07 15:47:29 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>That was a tough one because the tree controller did not care much about dispose and cleaning up so most of the time, the old binding id&#39;s were hanging around so I had to clean up those stuff first before I could check for the double bindings. Anyway, ended up in refactoring some parts and getting things the way they should have always been! :)
Also changed the mentioned demo which uses the double binding as a hack. Now the demo is much nicer!

trunk: 28059, 28060, 28064
1.4.x: 28061, 28062, 28065</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>