<bug>
          <bug_id>4911</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-04-01 16:20:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Rethink design of Manual start page</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:19:42 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>documentation.manual</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.6</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          <cc>marcputs</cc>
    
    <cc>tinobutz</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23756</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-01 16:20:11 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The current start page of the manual does not containing any information text about qooxdoo or anything else. In fact, its just a set of links more or less. We could/should enhance the start page with a bit of description to get the reader a quick start where to search.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23821</commentid>
            <who name="Tino Butz">tinobutz</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-04 16:41:41 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I think the Android developer guide looks nice:

http://developer.android.com/guide/basics/what-is-android.html

Clear Structure: Navigation left with expandable topics, Content right</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23978</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-12 10:46:56 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I want to do this - any input, e.g. as comments to this bug, are welcome.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24017</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-13 13:48:57 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I took a look at some other frameworks documentation pages and here are my results:

Nokias Qt: http://doc.qt.nokia.com/4.7/index.html
I like the idea of links to the manual. It is very important to get a good connection between manual and API docs. I also like the presence of examples and demos as one big topic.

jQuery: http://docs.jquery.com/Main_Page
Too much links for me and too less description. But the two columns make it look less messy and the clean structure is also something nice. But they also have a cross reference to the APIs and getting started at the beginning.

dojo Toolkit: http://dojotoolkit.org/reference-guide/
The inline examples are very nice! Would be great for our widget reference e.g.

Mootools: http://mootools.net/docs/core
Too less text for me but still the dedicated headlines give a good structure and overview.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26303</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-28 18:36:35 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Commited a first whack. Separated table of contents from &quot;index&quot; page (keeping 
this name for the start page of the manual for now). The start page now has 
some icons and highlights interesting points in the manual. I only used links 
pointing inside the manual, so no external links used. The images used are our 
own snapshots, or are from the framework&#39;s Tango/Oxygen icon themes.

With r28324.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26325</commentid>
            <who name="Marc Puts">marcputs</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-29 19:31:39 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>That looks nice.

It took me a little time to realize that the links do not all go to separate pages, but sometimes to different headings on the same page.

If I were a new user, I would click the first link `Requirements` and start reading to the bottom of that page. Then I go back to the index page and click the next link `Download`, only to find out that I already read that page.

IMHO that could be a little clearer. For example, by making the &quot;Getting started&quot; text or its icon clickable too, it might be a bit clearer that Getting Started takes me to the full page and the other links takes me to different parts of that page.

Maybe part of my confusion also comes from the fact that clicking a link does not always take you to a heading with the same name.
Examples:
- everything under `Getting Started` goes to the `Hello World` page
- prerequisites -&gt; goes to `Requirements` heading
- &quot;Hello World&quot; -&gt; goes to `Create your Application` heading


I would move the PDF link out of the overview. It&#39;s not a part of the manual, but rather another way to get to the manual. Maybe it should be a big glossy button on the side, or possibly have the user choose between HTML and PDF *before* browsing to the HTML manual (ie. on the qooxdoo.org/documentation page).



One of the manuals that I find easiest to navigate is the Doctrine documentation:
http://www.doctrine-project.org/docs/orm/2.0/en/

The index page lets you pick a chapter, and once you&#39;re in that chapter there&#39;s a nested table of contents of every heading in that chapter. It usually takes me no more than two clicks to get to where I want.

It also caters to both new users as well as experienced users, because every chapter covers the entire subject; starting with the basics, but when you get to the end, everything is covered.


Anyway, nice to see this being looked into. The current manual could do with a bit easier navigation (meaning: less scrolling) and a little eye candy never hurts. ;)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26328</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-29 23:47:37 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #5)
&gt; IMHO that could be a little clearer. For example, by making the &quot;Getting
&gt; started&quot; text or its icon clickable too, it might be a bit clearer that Getting
&gt; Started takes me to the full page and the other links takes me to different
&gt; parts of that page.

Marc, thanks for your feedback. - I&#39;ll think about this one. In general, I&#39;m quite fond of blurring the distinction between page and section. I&#39;d rather think of pieces of information that can be sensibly referred/linked to, and forget whether they live in their own physical page, or be part of a larger page. This makes it also easier when you push things around across various files. But maybe that&#39;s not to everybody&#39;s liking.

&gt; 
&gt; Maybe part of my confusion also comes from the fact that clicking a link does
&gt; not always take you to a heading with the same name.
&gt; Examples:
&gt; - everything under `Getting Started` goes to the `Hello World` page
&gt; - prerequisites -&gt; goes to `Requirements` heading
&gt; - &quot;Hello World&quot; -&gt; goes to `Create your Application` heading

Yes, I&#39;ve deliberately taken the opportunity to re-phrase section titles. But maybe that&#39;s confusing, yes.

&gt; 
&gt; 
&gt; I would move the PDF link out of the overview. It&#39;s not a part of the manual,
&gt; but rather another way to get to the manual. Maybe it should be a big glossy
&gt; button on the side, or possibly have the user choose between HTML and PDF
&gt; *before* browsing to the HTML manual (ie. on the qooxdoo.org/documentation
&gt; page).

Ok, I&#39;ve moved it to the bottom for the time being.

&gt; One of the manuals that I find easiest to navigate is the Doctrine
&gt; documentation:
&gt; http://www.doctrine-project.org/docs/orm/2.0/en/

Great, I&#39;ll have a look.

&gt; It also caters to both new users as well as experienced users, because every
&gt; chapter covers the entire subject; starting with the basics, but when you get
&gt; to the end, everything is covered.

That probably takes a much more disciplined approach than we are currently able to muster. But maybe we get there eventually :).

&gt; Anyway, nice to see this being looked into. The current manual could do with a
&gt; bit easier navigation (meaning: less scrolling)

Mh. The new index page emphasizes &quot;easier&quot;, but that means you have to leave out a lot, and only provide highlights.

The new table of contents is deeper and therefore much longer now. I like that because I&#39;m fond of completeness, having all relevant titles on one page. I don&#39;t mind scrolling, and some like the fact that you can use the browser page search to spot things. We&#39;ll see...</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26387</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-08-04 12:56:19 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Adding a tutorial section, slightly re-worked some wording and ordering.

With r28396.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26475</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-08-12 11:52:36 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>As the samples in this bug have a bigger scope than just the entry page, here 
is another interesting online manual:

http://www.ebayopensource.org/wiki/display/VJET/VJETDoc+Quick+Reference</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36595</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:19:42 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>