<bug>
          <bug_id>4952</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-04-05 13:42:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Opera 11: Some tests have light green background (simultaneously)</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-07-04 10:40:55 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>app.testrunner</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>Opera</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Opera</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23857</commentid>
            <who name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-05 13:42:03 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>To reproduce:
1.) Open test runner
2.) Run qx.test.bom.element.Background

Result:
All results have a light green background. 

Note:
If you can&#39;t reproduce, try to reload.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23872</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-05 14:37:32 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This looks like a really obscure timing problem. I was never able to reproduce this issue when loading the Testrunner from a server running on localhost. From a physically separate machine, I can reproduce the issue about 3 out of 5 times, but only if both the Testrunner and the AUT are build versions.

Interestingly, the delay between the Testrunner GUI being rendered and the test tree being populated is sometimes noticeably longer (~2 sec versus ~1 sec). Only if that&#39;s the case will the described behavior be exhibited.

Also, I couldn&#39;t reproduce the issue at all in Opera 11.10 (running on the same machine), so hopefully this is a browser issue specific to Opera 11.01 and already fixed in the coming version.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23873</commentid>
            <who name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-05 14:53:36 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Can&#39;t reproduce with Opera 11.10 Beta on Mac neither. Tried ~10 times from remote host with build version while loading other pages in other browser to keep the system busy.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25355</commentid>
            <who name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</who>
            <bug_when>2011-06-29 15:55:07 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Can reproduce with Opera 11.50, build version, from localhost, with bom.element package. Also observed maximum recursion depth errors.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25960</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-12 15:04:43 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I had a similar phenomenon testing Opera 10.63 on XP for the 1.5 release:

If you load the Testrunner, select qx.core and then run tests, the whole 
testing and displaying is corrupted:

- the progress bar stops at about 15%, even when all the tests have been run
- the display of &quot;Failed&quot; tests is wrong; e.g. it shows 0, while in the test 
results pane there are about 50 failed tests
- &quot;Succeeded&quot; is wrong, e.g. 6 instead of 9, again counting the individual test 
entries in the results pane
- Most of the failed test show a &quot;Maximum recursion depth exceeded&quot; message
- several results in the test result pane are displayed with a solid green 
background

Funnily, to fix this behaviour it suffices to do a reload of the AUT in the 
Testrunner, either by using the reload button, or activating auto-reloading. 
After the AUT reload, qx.core tests run just fine.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>