<bug>
          <bug_id>4975</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-04-07 13:05:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Mark the Devel Demos as Non-Final</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:24:50 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>app</component>
          <version>1.3</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.6</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23913</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-07 13:05:30 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>With the dropping of the &quot;-pre&quot; suffix from the trunk version during 
development time, the devel demo apps that go online during that time show no 
indication to the user that they are non-final, devel versions.

To amend for this, a suitable indication should be added to the trunk demos so 
it becomes apparent that they do not reflect the final version. (This might 
take the form of an SVN revision number being displayed, or something else). Of 
course, this indication should vanish in the released version.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23914</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-07 13:12:31 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I would like to achieve this through tooling, e.g. when running the &#39;release&#39; 
Makefile target.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23921</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-08 08:15:40 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I would suggest that the make file puts an environment setting in the apps which is called &quot;qx.devel&quot; or something else. The app could check for that setting and print the revision instead of the version in the applications header. On the App sied, thats only a few lines of code each app. :)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27407</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-11-04 17:15:45 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The implementation is slightly different from what Martin suggested:

- Applications check for &#39;qx.revision&#39; and use its value when available, else 
fall back to using &#39;qx.version&#39;.

- To make it easier for this code to maintain (and change) it, it has been 
forked out into a small class, qxc.ui.versionlabel.VersionLabel (under 
component/library/versionlabel).

- These are the apps currently using VersionLabel:

  - Feedreader
  - FCE
  - Widgetbrowser
  - Playground
  - Demobrowser
  - Apiviewer
  - Testrunner

- qx.revision is usually unset, so it can be filled on the command line, using 
a macro assignment, e.g. with -m QOOXDOO_REVISION:master:asdf1234

- A suitable revision string can be obtained by running the 
tool/admin/bin/gitinfo.sh shell script. It reflects the branch (e.g. &quot;master) 
and the short hash of the latest commit.

- All of this is done in our Makefile which uses gitinfo.sh to fill a make 
macro and provide it when building our applications. This way the demo apps get 
the created with a revision string.

- For release the make macro just needs to be empty, and the apps will fall 
back to the proper qooxdoo version in effect.

With 3d2ad2f90219.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>38537</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:24:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>