<bug>
          <bug_id>4976</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-04-07 14:18:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>autosizable TextArea not displayed correctly</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-09-20 07:43:40 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.form</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>major</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.4.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Rainer Koschnick">arkay</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</assigned_to>
          <cc>daniel.wagner</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23915</commentid>
            <who name="Rainer Koschnick">arkay</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-07 14:18:22 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>A TextArea which has autoSize enabled doesn&#39;t work with wrap disabled (apparant in  Demoviewer).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23916</commentid>
            <who name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-07 14:23:34 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>You mean when you first disable wrapping, then press enter?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23917</commentid>
            <who name="Rainer Koschnick">arkay</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-07 14:54:19 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>That&#39;s one of the problems, yes.

You can see it in the Demobrowser.  If you disable wrap the TextArea looks as if it would have 2 or 3 lines when there&#39;s only one.  Things get worse when you start adding lines, it gets even more out of proportion, and there&#39;s suddenly a scrollbar and the text scrolls out of focus.

With wrapping disabled at creation time it looks even worse.  Open the demo in the Playground and turn wrap off in the code to see the effect.  The TextArea is as tall as it would be with wrapping turned on.  It doesn&#39;t seem to consider the wrapping option at all when trying to determine the layout.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23918</commentid>
            <who name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-07 15:32:33 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report. We&#39;ll have a look.

What browser did you use?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>23919</commentid>
            <who name="Rainer Koschnick">arkay</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-07 15:44:19 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Chrome 10.0.648 (primarily) and Firefox 4.0.  It seems to work slightly better in Firefox, but it&#39;s also broken there.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25138</commentid>
            <who name="Rainer Koschnick">arkay</who>
            <bug_when>2011-06-17 12:30:13 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>New -&gt; Assigned -&gt; New?  Will this really be fixed for 1.4.2?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25139</commentid>
            <who name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</who>
            <bug_when>2011-06-17 12:39:10 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>That&#39;s the plan.

Changing from ASSIGNED to NEW means that we&#39;ll probably not be working on it in the next couple of days (usually a week).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25406</commentid>
            <who name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-01 15:58:57 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I fixed some bugs related to the auto-size textarea.

Can you please check again with r27929 on trunk? Or, visit the nightly build of the demo as soon as they get published (usually Friday evening), see http://demo.qooxdoo.org/devel/demobrowser/demo/ui/AutoSizeTextArea.html.

Also applied fixes to branch_1_4_x with r27934.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25700</commentid>
            <who name="Rainer Koschnick">arkay</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-01 20:08:36 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Under Windows I will have to check again on Monday at work, currently I&#39;m on Mac OS X.

As far as I can tell from here the wrap handling appears to be fixed.  

Entering new lines in Chrome on the &quot;Auto-Size&quot; Text Area doesn&#39;t work correctly though.  Hitting enter on an empty line doesn&#39;t create a new blank one.  If I move around (one line up and down again), enter text or a blank I can hit enter twice before it gets stuck again.  In Firefox it works.

In Safari it doesn&#39;t work either, it looks as if the text area would lose focus after I press enter to create, or backspace/delete to remove a line.

I also noticed that when moving around with the cursor key and pressing enter the cursor jumps to the end of the area, regardless of where you are.  I am not sure if auto-sizing can actually be accomplished.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25708</commentid>
            <who name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-04 07:43:15 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&#39;m using Mac OS X myself. With Chrome, wenn I press enter in an empty text area, I get a new line. However, when I press enter again I do not get another new line. About the jumping cursor, I believe I know the reason.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25732</commentid>
            <who name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-04 17:16:34 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Jumping cursor and entering multiple new lines fixed with r27984 on trunk.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25780</commentid>
            <who name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-06 07:34:39 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Rainer, do you observe any other issues?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25801</commentid>
            <who name="Rainer Koschnick">arkay</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-06 14:06:27 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Is the fix in the devel demo?  I can&#39;t check out the source from work.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25821</commentid>
            <who name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-07 08:26:26 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Unfortunately, the fixes are not in the developer demos yet. They are released on Friday.

From my point of view, I consider this bug fixed. However, the auto-size text area is affected by subtle changes in Browser / OS combinations and there are many ways to use it (how fast to enter text, copy and paste, where to enter breaks etc.). So if you still find any bugs, please feel free to reopen.

With r28034 on trunk and r28036 on branch_1_4_x.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26144</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-21 08:50:13 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The unit test qx.test.ui.form.TextArea:test: textarea with autoSize grows when long line is wrapped fails when run in IE8 with IE7 compatibility mode enabled:

Must grow when long line is unwrapped: Expected &quot;72&quot; to be not equal with &quot;72&quot;!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26223</commentid>
            <who name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-25 11:25:12 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed with r28251 on trunk and r28252 on branch_1_5_x.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>