<bug>
          <bug_id>5044</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-04-20 11:11:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Engine detection returns wrong names for Opera and IE</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 09:22:29 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>minor</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>derrell.lipman</cc>
    
    <cc>richard.sternagel</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24150</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-20 11:11:18 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The engine detection is currently returning &quot;mshtml&quot; for IE browsers. But the engine used in IE is called trident which would be the correct name. Same is true for opera. Our checks return &quot;opera&quot; but the name should be &quot;presto&quot;.

One of the big challenges here is how to get that change in the framework with a good deprecation!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24153</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-20 11:40:49 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Keep in mind to also check the engine version to ensure that not the browser version is returned.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24155</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-20 12:55:38 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The other issue to consider is that with the current, not quite technically correct identifiers, it&#39;s obvious to which browser it applies. I would have had no idea what those other names meant, and even now that I&#39;ve been told, unless I see them frequently and have reason to associate them with a particular browser, I&#39;ll forget.

At the expense of a loss of technical accuracy, I&#39;d recommend not trying to &quot;fix&quot; this.

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24163</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-20 15:29:04 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #2)
&gt; The other issue to consider is that with the current, not quite technically
&gt; correct identifiers, it&#39;s obvious to which browser it applies. I would have had
&gt; no idea what those other names meant, and even now that I&#39;ve been told, unless
&gt; I see them frequently and have reason to associate them with a particular
&gt; browser, I&#39;ll forget.
&gt; 
&gt; At the expense of a loss of technical accuracy, I&#39;d recommend not trying to
&gt; &quot;fix&quot; this.
&gt; 
&gt; Derrell


Thanks for you input, Derrell. Maybe we are mixing things up here. You can still use the &quot;browser.name&quot; key to query for the browser names which menas that still &quot;ie&quot; and &quot;opera&quot; will be returned. But for the engine name, thats just wrong and should be fixed. We should not offer and API and return knowingly wrong stuff.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33247</commentid>
            <who name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</who>
            <bug_when>2013-07-05 15:55:24 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Note that with Opera 15 the engine switched to Blink so &quot;window.opera&quot; is undefined and the browser is (rightly) masquerading itself as &quot;AppleWebKit&quot;:

&quot;window.navigator.userAgent&quot; yields:

Opera Next:
&quot;Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10_8_4) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/28.0.1500.52 Safari/537.36 OPR/15.0.1147.100 (Edition Next)&quot;

Opera 15:
!Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10_8_4) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/28.0.1500.52 Safari/537.36 OPR/15.0.1147.132&quot;

&quot;OPR/15.0.1147.132&quot; seems to be the new Opera user agent hint.
&quot;(Edition Next)&quot; seems to be attached when using the dedicated developer build(s).

So this code snippet is currently a little bit misleading (though it results in a technically valid and working outcome):

var engineName = qx.bom.client.Engine.getName();
if (engineName === &quot;opera&quot;) {
  // means Opera &lt; 15
} else if (engineName === &quot;webkit&quot;) {
  // means Opera &gt;= 15
}

So now the rename to &quot;presto&quot; would help even more.

Marginal note: If Blink diverges more and more from WebKit there might also be use cases for a dedicated engineName &quot;blink&quot;.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33252</commentid>
            <who name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</who>
            <bug_when>2013-07-05 18:04:22 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Also mind that this affects &quot;qx.dev.unit.MRequirements&quot; when using lines like:

this.require([&quot;notOpera&quot;]);</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>