<bug>
          <bug_id>5095</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-05-06 19:24:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>add a &quot;server&quot; type to create-application</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2013-12-16 12:45:22 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>DUPLICATE</resolution>
          <dup_id>5100</dup_id>
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          <cc>giesen.florian</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24360</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-06 19:24:27 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I want to create an application using qooxdoo&#39;s OO features. It will run on the server, and can not contain any references to browser features. This seems to be what the help screen of create-application implies that the &quot;native&quot; type is for. When I do a &quot;generate.py build&quot;, however, the resultant script assumes a browser environment, with references to &quot;window&quot; and &quot;navigator&quot; and DOM elements requiring an onload handler, etc.

If I have properly interpreted the purpose of a &quot;native&quot; application, it seems the build must be done differently.

If I have not interpreted the purpose of a &quot;native&quot; application correctly, then what is it for?

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24362</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-06 21:58:46 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; I want to create an application using qooxdoo&#39;s OO features. It will run on the
&gt; server, and can not contain any references to browser features. This seems to
&gt; be what the help screen of create-application implies that the &quot;native&quot; type is
&gt; for. When I do a &quot;generate.py build&quot;, however, the resultant script assumes a
&gt; browser environment, with references to &quot;window&quot; and &quot;navigator&quot; and DOM
&gt; elements requiring an onload handler, etc.
&gt; 
&gt; If I have properly interpreted the purpose of a &quot;native&quot; application, it seems
&gt; the build must be done differently.
&gt; 
&gt; If I have not interpreted the purpose of a &quot;native&quot; application correctly, then
&gt; what is it for?

I&#39;m not an expert on this, but my take on &quot;native&quot; is that while it puts away with widgets, it&#39;s still browser-bound, supporting browser events and BOM actions and such. I&#39;m sure you get more elaborate answers from the mailing list.

What you really want is the qx-oo [1][2] package that was specifically crafted for non-browser environments. (Actually, it was featured in the last release).

[1] http://demo.qooxdoo.org/current/ (scroll far to the bottom)
[2] http://news.qooxdoo.org/download-qxoo-now (but use download from above)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24364</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-06 22:30:04 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
 
&gt; What you really want is the qx-oo [1][2] package that was specifically crafted
&gt; for non-browser environments. (Actually, it was featured in the last release).

Thanks. and yes, I&#39;m well aware of qx-oo, and am using it. What is lacking, though, with just that, is the whole tool chain that takes all of my classes, compresses and optimizes them into a single JS file. Using only qx-oo, I have to do the combining myself. That&#39;s what I was hoping to gain by creating a Native application. It sounds like maybe one more application type would be useful: &quot;Server&quot;.

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24366</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-06 22:36:39 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Very good point. Please open a bug for it (or rededicate this one).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24368</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-06 22:42:41 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #3)
&gt; Very good point. Please open a bug for it (or rededicate this one).

Consider it rededicated. :-)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24468</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-12 14:06:11 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The intend of this bug will be carried on in #5100, as John as provided a lot
of implementation details there.

*** This bug has been marked as a duplicate of bug 5100 ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>