<bug>
          <bug_id>5096</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-05-06 19:26:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>&quot;create-application.py -t native&quot; won&#39;t build: no resource directory</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2013-12-16 12:45:59 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.6</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</assigned_to>
          <cc>martin.wittemann</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24361</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-06 19:26:00 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>When create-application is used to create a &quot;native&quot; type application, the source/resource directory is not automatically created, so the generator fails.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24363</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-06 22:23:45 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Cannot confirm. After running create-application, there is a source/resource/&lt;namespace&gt; directory alright. Source and build versions build and run just fine. I did this from SVN trunk on Windows.

Which qooxdoo version are you using? On which platform? (It&#39;s not one of those &quot;git doesn&#39;t like empty directory&quot; things, is it?!)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24365</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-06 22:33:18 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; Which qooxdoo version are you using? On which platform? (It&#39;s not one of those
&gt; &quot;git doesn&#39;t like empty directory&quot; things, is it?!)

I&#39;m using r26943.

Yes, it&#39;s certainly possible that it&#39;s a git issue, if the resource directory is copied from someplace, and not created by the create-application script. If an empty directory exists in the tool/ subtree or something, that&#39;s supposed to be copied, then git wouldn&#39;t have created that empty directory.

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24367</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-06 22:39:09 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>You can check the component/skeleton/native path, to see if your repository contains the directory.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24369</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-06 22:47:13 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #3)
&gt; You can check the component/skeleton/native path, to see if your repository
&gt; contains the directory.

That path did not contain the resource directory. Creating it manually solved the problem.

It would be useful to add a readme file to that resource directory (and any other empty directories in the skeleton path), as is done with a few other empty directories. Yes, it&#39;s a git problem, but more and more people are moving to git, and the work-around is pretty easy.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24370</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-06 23:32:52 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Martin, can you confirm this issue? Do you have a better solution?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24373</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-09 09:17:10 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I am aware of that and had that issue myself some times. But that was some time ago so I checked it and can not confirm it anymore. Which git version do you use, Derrell? Maybe I updated some time ago which fixed that problem on the git side. Mine is 1.7.3.2 on OSX.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24388</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-09 14:47:37 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&#39;m running git 1.6.3.3.

I did a bit of looking around about this, and the current online documentation for git indicates that it is supposed to handle empty directories properly on _some_ commands. There&#39;s a &quot;git svn mkdirs&quot; command now, that is supposed to be called (by the user) after a &quot;git reset&quot; or &quot;git checkout&quot; but is, supposedly, run automatically by a &quot;git svn rebase&quot;.

If it&#39;s actually resolved in git, then there&#39;s probably no reason to make qooxdoo-specific changes just to handle this.

BTW, the suggested (former) method of dealing with these empty directories was to add a .gitignore file to them, which doesn&#39;t affect svn, but makes the directory non-empty.

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24403</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-10 09:00:37 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thomas, what do you think? Is there a need to add a placeholder file to the directory?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24408</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-10 10:22:14 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Actually, as long as we don&#39;t support git officially, I don&#39;t see a need to work around its limitations. At the moment, I don&#39;t want to be constantly on the look-out for empty directories, and fix them with some file. On the other hand, I don&#39;t mind Derrell doing this, he has commit rights.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24414</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-10 14:28:30 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Sure, I&#39;ll take this.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27750</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-12-01 16:17:05 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>This has already been fixed with 440423c437c6b15485a5e03da88841cf92995cc3.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>