<bug>
          <bug_id>5103</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-05-11 08:39:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>When the load of a json store (qx.data.store.Json) fails, we need the error code in the response object</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-06-14 08:20:16 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.databinding</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.5</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Uwe Stahl">uwe.stahl</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          <cc>alexander.steitz</cc>
    
    <cc>tinobutz</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24427</commentid>
            <who name="Uwe Stahl">uwe.stahl</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-11 08:39:13 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>We are using a json store (qx.data.store.Json).
It may happend that the http request that loads data from the backend into the store fails. In that case, the store fires an error event.
The problem is that the error event does not pass the http response object as event data. Therefore we do not know the reason for the error and always display the same error message &quot;the backend does not work&quot;.

But now we want to display more differentiated error messages like &quot;permission denied - please re-enter the password&quot;. To display better error messages, we need to know the reason for this error. But the problem is that the json store swallows the cause of the error and the http response object and does not provide any information about the information of the error.

The enhancement request is to make the &quot;error&quot; event of the json store a data event that passed the http response object.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24432</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-11 11:01:17 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>*** Bug 4716 has been marked as a duplicate of this bug. ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24434</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-11 11:44:24 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Added the described behavior. The error event is now a data event. The data contains the Response object returned by the transport layer (qx.io.remote.Response). 

Unfortunately, we plan to change the request for the data stores to the new transport layer (see bug #5104). As this new layer does not use the response object, the API may change in some time before the release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24435</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-11 11:45:29 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>trunk: r27166</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>