<bug>
          <bug_id>5124</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-05-13 22:29:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Blank screen after generation of one of two forks of the same cache</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:46:25 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Stefan Andersson">dev</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24518</commentid>
            <who name="Stefan Andersson">dev</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-13 22:29:16 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>1. two applications with the same cache; A and B
2. generate A
3. run A works fine
4. run B -&gt; blank screen and nothing happens

Conclusion: B was not generated, but there should at least be a message telling what is going on f.i. &quot;Application B is out of sync of current cache.&quot;.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24520</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-14 01:15:46 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This information is far too little and too vague to reply anything helpful. Generally, it is no problem compiling multiple applications against the same cache path. We do it all the time, even with multiple qooxdoo frameworks. Try to answer some of the following questions:

- You didn&#39;t mention that you generated B. Did you generate B before A, or after A? Did you generate B at all?

- What are the details behind &quot;blank screen and nothing happens&quot;? Is the index.html loaded? Is the application loader script loaded? Is there any indication that a specific file is missing?

- Is a loader script being generated? Look into source/script/&lt;appname&gt;.js or build/script/&lt;appname&gt;.js, depending on which version you built. Does the file resemble a qooxdoo loader script (see tool/data/generator/loader.tmpl.js for the template)? Does it have a recent time stamp?

- Can you reproduce the issue in the source version of apps A and B? Which messages do you get in the browser console of the failing app.

- Can you run the failing app from a web server? This can give a better indication which files cannot be loaded (e.g. in Firebug&#39;s Net tab). Which files are these?

- Try to narrow down the circumstances under which the issue appears. E.g. &quot;I clear the cache, then I generate source in application A, it loads in the browser ok; then I generate source in application B, it results in the blank screen.&quot; Use the exclusion principle, to exclude premature conclusions. E.g. &quot;If I first generate source in A, then in B, B doesn&#39;t run; if I generate source first in B, then in A, A doesn&#39;t run&quot;, to exclude it depends on a particular app or a particular order.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24521</commentid>
            <who name="Stefan Andersson">dev</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-14 14:40:16 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for you absolutely best answer ever. It was VERY professional!

That nothing is run is reasonable, but not that the screen becomes blank and no message.

- not mentioned = not done -&gt; B was generated before, but never generated for the new version

- no error messages. index.html seems to be loaded but empty. question if it is the default of the FF browser.

- it is not in the browser. it is in the index.html file as usual. no files missing.

- if I generate B (as I didn&#39;t do with the new version) it works fine. Reproducible with a new revision from trunk and with the same procedure: NOT generating B -&gt; empty screen

- web server no diff

- as above

Thomas I think that the reason must in some way be that B, which has not been generated, can not be run with the new updated version put in cache when generating A. Isn&#39;t it as simple as that?

If it is, then there should reasonably be an error message and not a blank screen.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24522</commentid>
            <who name="Stefan Andersson">dev</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-14 14:40:42 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>forgot to say: all generated in source version</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35525</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:46:25 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>