<bug>
          <bug_id>5126</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-05-14 20:24:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Remove focus border for tab views in the simple theme</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-07-18 10:05:34 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>app</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.5</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Leandro Santiago">leandrosansilva</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24525</commentid>
            <who name="Leandro Santiago">leandrosansilva</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-14 20:24:34 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I don&#39;t know if it only happens on linux (I&#39;ve tested on chrome, opera, firefox, konqueror, and webkit-qt), but when you click in a tab, a dotted rectangle os displayed around this selected item.

I don&#39;t see any sense for this and I think tabview should looks better without it.

I&#39;m linking some screenshots, one with modern theme and other with simples theme:
[1] http://dl.dropbox.com/u/3550969/qxaround2.png
[2] http://dl.dropbox.com/u/3550969/qxaround3.png</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24531</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-16 09:12:41 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This is by design currently. But still we have to look at the two themes separate.

In the classic theme, this concept of the dotted line is pretty helpful for showing the focused element. As this theme is a more functional theme, we should keep that the way it is.

In the simple theme, this dotted line has the same purpose but is not that important. So we should remove that in the simple theme.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24591</commentid>
            <who name="Leandro Santiago">leandrosansilva</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-18 14:14:51 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #0)
&gt; I don&#39;t know if it only happens on linux (I&#39;ve tested on chrome, opera,
&gt; firefox, konqueror, and webkit-qt), but when you click in a tab, a dotted
&gt; rectangle os displayed around this selected item.
&gt; 
&gt; I don&#39;t see any sense for this and I think tabview should looks better without
&gt; it.
&gt; 
&gt; I&#39;m linking some screenshots, one with modern theme and other with simples
&gt; theme:
&gt; [1] http://dl.dropbox.com/u/3550969/qxaround2.png
&gt; [2] http://dl.dropbox.com/u/3550969/qxaround3.png

ops, I attached the wrong screenshot. sorry :-(

Although it also happens in the classic theme (which mimics win9x visual) and it&#39;s useful, IMHO it isn&#39;t useful in modern theme too, as it isn&#39;t in simple theme.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24980</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-06-08 10:08:25 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Removed the focus line of the tabview for the simple theme. IMHO it is useful for the modern there so I keept it there.

trunk: r27600</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>