<bug>
          <bug_id>5155</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-05-23 14:59:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>fireEvent changeContent in _applyValue Label class</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-07-18 10:05:48 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>trivial</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.4.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Stefan Andersson">dev</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24670</commentid>
            <who name="Stefan Andersson">dev</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-23 14:59:58 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Where is this event picked up?

same as _applyValue ?

It has not been documented as far as we can see. Is it an old remnant intended to be removed?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24682</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-24 08:27:14 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Stefan, is that a general question or a real issue? That sounds more like a question so please consider asking that on our support channel, the mailing list. Bugzilla should not be used for plain questions or bugs which are not clear if they are bugs at all. The main work on the mailing list is shared among all core developers which isn&#39;t the case with bugzilla.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24683</commentid>
            <who name="Stefan Andersson">dev</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-24 08:43:43 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>My friend.....it WAS asked on the mailing channel. Tino Butz asked me to file a bug for it and so I did. Now you punish me for doing that......! Left hand does not know what right hand is doing...</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24685</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-24 09:49:13 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>How should I know that if your description does not mention it? If there was already a discussion about it, maybe a link would be helpful in the bug report. You don&#39;t expect me to read every single mail on the mailing list? ;)

So I&#39;m going to reopen the bug and say sorry for the &quot;punishment&quot;. But still, the description is kind of sloppy and I don&#39;t get what its about. Whats the problem?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24689</commentid>
            <who name="Stefan Andersson">dev</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-24 10:39:10 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>&gt;How should I know that if your description does not mention it?

Regardless of a previous discussion, all reports should be taken seriously.

&gt; If there was already a discussion about it, maybe a link would be helpful in the bug report. You don&#39;t expect me to read every single mail on the mailing list? ;)

You are correct. Link is helpful: http://sourceforge.net/mailarchive/forum.php?thread_name=EF2AE766-00BC-439F-B195-E9C68C50CC94%401und1.de&amp;forum_name=qooxdoo-devel

It was Tristan answering this question not Tino as I previously said.

No, we don&#39;t expect anything from you at all! The 23rd had 13 message threads and you participated in more than three. I can see from your activity on the mailing list that you are very active, which is appreciated.

&gt;So I&#39;m going to reopen the bug and say sorry for the &quot;punishment&quot;.

It is accepted.

&gt; But still, the description is kind of sloppy and I don&#39;t get what its about. Whats the problem?

The report is very short. It is true, but not sloppy. I think you see it very well if you give it time as you are one of the main architects and you are a fast thinker.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24979</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-06-08 09:59:01 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This was an old event which has not been removed the time we moved all &quot;content&quot; property names to value to harmonize labels and form items in qooxdoo.

Removed it with:

trunk: r27598
1.4.x: r27599</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>