<bug>
          <bug_id>5226</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-06-08 17:50:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Feature request: Add a way to set value.</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:46:38 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>contrib</product>
          <component>ComboTable</component>
          <version>trunk</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Germán Del Tedesco">gpdeltedesco</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>tobi</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Tobias Oetiker">tobi</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25004</commentid>
            <who name="Germán Del Tedesco">gpdeltedesco</who>
            <bug_when>2011-06-08 17:50:07 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>There is not way to programatically set the value for the widget(*). By using the &quot;setValue()&quot; method, will set the textbox&#39;s value, but &quot;getSelectedRowData()&quot; will not work as expected.

Use case: an &quot;edit form&quot;, with a ComboTable widget, between others.

I need to be able to set a value obtained from the server. Currently, if i use the &quot;setValue()&quot; method, and if the user doesn&#39;t touch the ComboTable, the selection will be lost. Additionally, if the ComboTable widget is required, validation will fail.

So, i think that if i set a value (through &quot;setValue()&quot; or another provided method), and if that value &quot;exactly&quot; match a row&#39;s value in the datamodel, then that row must be automatically selected.

(*) Or, if there is, this is not obvious for me by after study the api.

Thanks... and please, if something in my poor english writing is unreadable, let me know, and i will try to re explain that. Greetings from Argentina.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25007</commentid>
            <who name="Tobias Oetiker">tobi</who>
            <bug_when>2011-06-08 18:19:44 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>as far as I understand the table model, there is no way to select &#39;by value&#39; except by searching through all entries of the table model ... for a &#39;normal&#39; model this is fine, and you can do it by walking through the model data, but for the remote model this would require you to actually load all the data until you find a match which is not a good idea AT ALL ... so there would have to be additional serverside calls for it to work ... 

in other words, I am aware of the limitation but until now I was not required to solve it for my use ... if you want to contribute a patch please do! ... we are also available for hire :-)

cheers
tobi</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25011</commentid>
            <who name="Germán Del Tedesco">gpdeltedesco</who>
            <bug_when>2011-06-08 19:09:14 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hello!

Ok, i will try to solve the problem for my use case, and then study how to implement the solution in an unobtrusive and generic way.

After reading your response, i see it seems to be that i misunderstood the side effects. Before this, i believed that the remote model would not give us major problems (except an additional request to the server, of course), based on the fact that in my setSearchString() method&#39;s implementation, i will receive only the rows that partially match the string. This way, i would only need to verify:

1) I got only one row from the server? Then check 2), else act as usual.
2) The row&#39;s value match the search string? Then set as selection, else act as usual.

Any way, i will do a better study of the case, and submit a patch for your analysis, if i found an &quot;good&quot; solution.

Thanks for your time, patience, and fast reply! :-)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35606</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:46:38 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>