<bug>
          <bug_id>5336</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-07-06 16:10:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Finalize &#39;config-warnings&#39; API and Implementation</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:48:03 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator.config</component>
          <version>1.4.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25811</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-06 16:10:27 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This is a follow-up on bug#4441.

The current config API and implementation of the &#39;config-warnings&#39; key, to 
suppress well-known configuration warnings, is preliminary and marked 
&#39;experimental&#39; in the manual. Finalize it. This probably means that the API and 
the implementation have to be re-thought.

- it is open which sub-keys are best for the config-warnings key (fixed keys 
like &#39;job-shadowing&#39; which refer to a single warning; &#39;config-includes&#39; which 
refers to an entire sub-action of the config system; variable keys like job 
keys that can be repeated literally in the config-warnings key; ...)

- it is unclear which values are best for those sub-keys: lists (as it is now), 
boolean, ... should mixed types be allowed?

- the current implement is ad-hoc; config-warning settings are queried just 
before the corresponding console.warn() call; as these console.warn() calls are 
distributed over the entire generator (at least generator.py, Generator.py and 
generator.config.*), so are the queries; more code like this will increasingly 
blur the actual effect code in the generator (the code that acutally *does* 
something); but there is no concept to e.g. delegate config-warnings settings 
to general log routines or something

- the top-level &#39;config-warnings&#39; might itself become a sub-key of a more 
general &#39;defaults&#39; top-level key

- i think the current way of integrating the top-level key with a single job 
(like with the global &#39;let&#39;) is ok

Of course answers also depend on usage experiences, feedback and future 
requirements.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30472</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2012-08-22 18:22:25 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>One insight from working on bug#4615 is that it&#39;s probably best if warnings 
related to code are configured with some lint options for the 
lint/source/build/... jobs, or as @hints in the code itself. The 
config-warnings key could then be restricted to warnings that affect the config 
system alone (job definitions, job shadowing, include files, ...), which seems 
like a much better separation of concerns.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31138</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2012-10-30 14:02:37 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I think the best way is to separate purely config-related issues and issues 
having to do with JS code, as indicated in the previous comment. Code-related 
warnings should have their own dedicated tools to deal with. The remainder of 
the config-warnings key should be focussed on config issues only. This part 
(i.e. the affected config-warnings subkeys) could probably be left as is and 
this bug be closed, until concrete requirements show up to modify it in a 
certain way.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36119</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:48:03 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>