<bug>
          <bug_id>5391</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-07-12 16:42:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Make us of the new page visibility API</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2013-05-23 10:08:08 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>website.bom</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>3.0</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Tino Butz">tinobutz</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>25971</commentid>
            <who name="Tino Butz">tinobutz</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-12 16:42:45 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The W3C introduced a new Page Visibility API. 
http://www.w3.org/TR/2011/WD-page-visibility-20110602/

We should add this to the framework. Perhaps we could provide an &quot;page visible&quot; event.

The API is already supported by IE10 &amp; Chrome 13:

http://blogs.msdn.com/b/ie/archive/2011/07/08/using-pc-hardware-more-efficiently-in-html5-new-web-performance-apis-part-2.aspx

&quot;The Page Visibility specification defines a means for site developers to programmatically determine the current visibility of a document and be notified of visibility changes. Without knowing the visibility state of a page, a web developer must design the webpage as if it is always visible. This not only results in higher machine resource utilization, but it prevents web developers from making runtime decisions based on whether the webpage is visible to the user. Designing web pages with knowledge of the page visibility will allow for improved user experiences and power efficient sites.

With this interface, web applications may chose to alter behavior based on whether they are visible to the user or not. For example, this interface can be used to scale back work when the page is no longer visible. If a web based email client is visible, it may check the server for new mail every few seconds. When hidden it might scale checking email to every few minutes. This interface can also be used to provide better runtime user experience decisions not related to power management. For example, a puzzle game could be paused when the user no longer has the game visible. Further, this interface can be used by advertisers to not charge for ads that are not visible to users.&quot;</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31769</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-19 13:22:59 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Added a cross browser wrapper for the page visibility API.

master: 0db0ecc841f3211230d4bab71e2d5dd42365da54</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>