<bug>
          <bug_id>5454</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-07-27 16:57:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>List looses selection when filtering</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-07-29 08:45:27 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.list</component>
          <version>1.5</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Johannes Kissel">johannes.kissel</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26281</commentid>
            <who name="Johannes Kissel">johannes.kissel</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-27 16:57:46 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Example: http://tinyurl.com/435226f

Filtering and selection are model-based and not based on the visible list items. So it would be nice if the selection doesn&#39;t get lost when the list item is temporarily removed.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26282</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-27 18:21:34 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Johannes, right the selection can only contains visible items. This is the current behavior and not a bug. Maybe it is better to make it more &quot;model-based&quot;, but we should open an enhancement bug for this feature. I will talk with Martin about it. Maybe I need more information from your use case, so I will get in touch with you.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26288</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-28 08:43:42 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>As Chris said, this is by design. We decided to have only visibile items in the selection. In the case of additive selection, the user does not have a change to remove the selection of not visible items because he can not click on it anymore.
Whats your use case where such a feature would be handy?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26291</commentid>
            <who name="Johannes Kissel">johannes.kissel</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-28 08:51:52 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>My use case is a list of 3D models. When I click on one of them, the model is displayed beside the list. The selected list item corresponds directly to the displayed model. The list can be filtered with a text field. If I do so and the filter hides the selected item, the selection is lost.

As I understood, your new list (the virtual list) is quite model-based: You fill it with a model, the selection is a model, you filter on model data. So from my point of view it breaks at this point.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26312</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-07-29 08:45:27 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #3)
&gt; My use case is a list of 3D models. When I click on one of them, the model is
&gt; displayed beside the list. The selected list item corresponds directly to the
&gt; displayed model. The list can be filtered with a text field. If I do so and the
&gt; filter hides the selected item, the selection is lost.
I think that you could have your desired behavior very easily. Only change the source of your model displayed besides the list if a new model is selected.


&gt; As I understood, your new list (the virtual list) is quite model-based: You
&gt; fill it with a model, the selection is a model, you filter on model data. So
&gt; from my point of view it breaks at this point.

And where exactly does it break with the model centered design? You still have to handle only models so I can&#39;t see a break here in any case. 
As already said, this is a problem of the additive selection mode so we won&#39;t change it. Maybe in exactly your use case, the different behavior would fit but not in a general sense.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>