<bug>
          <bug_id>548</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2007-07-10 15:17:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Mouse handling in Opera</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-05-16 10:12:20 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop</component>
          <version>0.7</version>
          <rep_platform>Opera</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://demo.qooxdoo.org/current/demobrowser/</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Rüdiger Herrmann">rherrmann</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Opera</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1971</commentid>
            <who name="Rüdiger Herrmann">rherrmann</who>
            <bug_when>2007-07-10 15:17:38 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I just noticed several issues when using Opera (at least version 9):
- changing the cursor doesn&#39;t work. E.g. hovering over a splitter shows default cursor instead of the resize cursor that is visible on other browsers
- double-click on a widgets selects its text, e.g. on Button and TreeFolder. In addition a popup menu is shown
- right click always opens the browsers&#39; popup window
- qooxdoo popup menus don&#39;t show up, instead the browsers&#39; popup menu is shown
- dragging a window selects the underlying text

Is there anything that can be done about these issues?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1972</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2007-07-10 15:58:46 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>At least the problem with the context menu cannot be solved completely by us. Opera has a configuration option, which toggles whether JavaScript can catch the right mouse button. Unfortunately this setting is set disabled by default. 

I have to look closer at the other ones.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1974</commentid>
            <who name="Rüdiger Herrmann">rherrmann</who>
            <bug_when>2007-07-10 16:16:04 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; At least the problem with the context menu cannot be solved completely by us.
&gt; Opera has a configuration option, which toggles whether JavaScript can catch
&gt; the right mouse button. Unfortunately this setting is set disabled by default. 
Even with the mentioned option enabled, Opera 9.21 doesn&#39;t react on right clicks. Or is there another option that might prevent this?

&gt; 
&gt; I have to look closer at the other ones.
&gt; 
Thanks

</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1978</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2007-07-10 19:11:52 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I think qooxdoo is listening to the &quot;contextmenu&quot; event, which Opera doesn&#39;t seem to fire. I see
only the keydown event. Maybe we could normalize keydown events fired by the right mouse
button to issue a contextmenu event as well.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>1992</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2007-07-13 09:39:00 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>General it&#39;s bad to describe multiple issues in one bug.

* changing the cursor doesn&#39;t work. E.g. hovering over a splitter shows default
cursor instead of the resize cursor that is visible on other browsers =&gt; NEW Bug (Please create a seperate bug from this)

* double-click on a widgets selects its text, e.g. on Button and TreeFolder. In
addition a popup menu is shown =&gt; WONTFIX (Opera does not support any known way to omit text selections)

* right click always opens the browsers&#39; popup window =&gt; WONTFIX (No known way to block this menu using JS)

* qooxdoo popup menus don&#39;t show up, instead the browsers&#39; popup menu is shown (maybe a bug which will be fixed with the new event layer in 0.8). I don&#39;t think this will be fixed in the bugfix release cycle of 0.7.x

* dragging a window selects the underlying text =&gt; WONTFIX (Opera does not support any known way to omit text selections)

Closed as WONTFIX as this is OK for the most mentioned misbehaviors. For the first one please open a new bug report.
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>