<bug>
          <bug_id>5557</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-08-24 20:55:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Tutorial code needs to be migrated</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-10-24 08:51:27 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>website</product>
          <component>other</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>DUPLICATE</resolution>
          <dup_id>3829</dup_id>
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P1</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.6</target_milestone>
          <dependson>3829</dependson>
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          <cc>thron7</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26590</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2011-08-24 20:55:15 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>On behalf of Bruce Dickey as seen on the mailing list:

&quot;I downloaded v1.5 and was working thru the Getting Started twitter tutorial.
For Part 1 and Part 2, all was fine. Then while adding code in Part 3, the generator started spitting out 

Warning: Hint: Unknown global symbol referenced: qx.core.Variant
(twitter.Application:46)

Things I did after this (none resolved the problem) were:
* Copy &amp; paste the .js code directly off git
* Revert code to tutorial Part 1
* Delete ALL generated files (I think -- the .js files in
twitter/source/script)
* Blow away the qooxdoo tree and re-unzip it.

Anyone know how to fix this?&quot;</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26591</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2011-08-24 21:02:30 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Due to the switch from qx.core.Variant to qx.core.Environment the tutorial apps no longer seem to work with qooxdoo 1.5. They need to be migrated.

This also raises the question again that those tutorial should be maintained directly within the project (see bug #3829). As the tutorials are part of the manual, they should also be included into the automated nightly testing and the regular release ramp-down.

@Martin, please migrate the tutorials and come up with task reports to address the open issues, thanks.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26592</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-08-24 22:21:41 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>We could maintain them under 

    component/tutorials</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26805</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-15 13:20:03 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I still think that the tutorial code is a simple addition and they don&#39;t need to be maintained in the framework. Additionally, I don&#39;t see a solution how the tags should be organized then? Each step is a separate tag which can not work in the regular svn trunk structure the framework code currently is.

To the report about the missing variant class. I think we need to define which step should work with which version of qooxdoo. Should all steps work with the current version of qooxdoo or should each step work with the version which was current the time the step was added? If it should always work with the newest qooxdoo version, we should keep in mind that we need to merge commits in for step 1 e.g. which means we have to change the whole commit order which is already on the server.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26824</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-19 13:39:35 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>

*** This bug has been marked as a duplicate of bug 3829 ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>