<bug>
          <bug_id>5614</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-09-14 19:06:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>ListItems showing wrong icons after scrolling virtual list</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:24:39 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.list</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>Chrome</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://tinyurl.com/6xh46ax</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>minor</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.5.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Andrew Goldberg">madtownphd2b</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Chrome</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26793</commentid>
            <who name="Andrew Goldberg">madtownphd2b</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-14 19:06:42 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The URL listed is a playground example demonstrating the problem. It simply displays a list of icon names next to their corresponding icons. Clearly, the icon images should always match the labels in the ListItems.

I am seeing the following buggy behavior in Chrome 13.0.782.220 on Mac and Windows. If you scroll up and down in the list, after a little while, you should start to see the wrong icons. For example, the folder.png icon may appear next to a user-trash.png label. 

On the qooxdoo-devel list, Christian Hagendorn &lt;christian.hagendorn@1und1.de&gt; wrote the following:

I can remember that we have seen the issue with a devel version from
Chrome in the past.  At that time this was a browser bug, because the
image was not applied to the DOM element even though it was set.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26794</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-15 08:39:05 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I can remember that too and just gave it a try in chrome 15 and it did work for me quite fine. What version of chrome did you try?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26796</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-15 09:12:23 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I also used Chrome 13.0.782.220.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26993</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-27 16:38:02 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I debugged the application and it is a browser bug. Chrome doesn&#39;t set sometimes the correct background image even though it was set. I tried to find a workaround for this issue, but did not found it.

I tested the issue with 15.0.874.24 (beta) and couldn&#39;t reproduce it with the new version. It seems to me that the issue is fixed with the next Chrome release. Therefore I close the bug as WONTFIX, when the issue occurs with the new Chrome release, then please reopen this bug. Thanks.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>38470</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:24:39 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>