<bug>
          <bug_id>5634</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-09-23 13:57:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Adding cldr data for phone country codes</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:46:05 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Stefan Andersson">dev</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26897</commentid>
            <who name="Stefan Andersson">dev</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-23 13:57:55 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Here is a proposal to add cldr data for country codes:

1. create a directory tool/data/cldr/supplemental
2. put telephoneCodeData.xml file from unicode cldr in the created directory

This is very useful for mapping phone country codes in f.i. a SelectBox.

It has nothing to do with localization! Universal application-specific.

The point here is that the developer does not need to have a double download of the cldr file and then getting version discrepancies. As qoxxdoo already has data (main subdirectory) from the cldr lib then it would be useful to include the above file too!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26925</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-26 08:59:01 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Sounds reasonable. What do you think, Thomas?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26930</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-26 10:05:35 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; Sounds reasonable. What do you think, Thomas?

I have several concerns regarding this:

- The file in question (telephoneCodeData.xml) has nothing to do with I18N, meaning it doesn&#39;t contain information that changes with the selected locale. The file is just a mapping from phone to country codes.

- We don&#39;t have tooling support for its format. What would be the interface to it for application developers? I&#39;m not sure we should just include raw XML in the SDK, without any integration.

- As far as I can see there is just a single project wanting this (Stefan&#39;s), and I&#39;m not sure we should invest for a one-off effort.

- It would be much better IMO if Stefan makes this file part of his custom project, so he can write a parser for it and integrate it into his app as he sees fit. He could also make a static class out of it.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26944</commentid>
            <who name="Stefan Andersson">dev</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-26 12:44:15 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thomas!

Just some ideas...

&gt;- The file in question (telephoneCodeData.xml) has nothing to do with I18N,
&gt;meaning it doesn&#39;t contain information that changes with the selected locale.
&gt;The file is just a mapping from phone to country codes.

Well, it is part of the standard and it is in the file and has its own directory. It means that the standard commission already considered this and they mean it is relevant to include...

&gt;- We don&#39;t have tooling support for its format. What would be the interface to
&gt;it for application developers? I&#39;m not sure we should just include raw XML in
&gt;the SDK, without any integration.

Yes and no. Of course it is good with integration. We have and we can give you that! But no integration is really no argument for not helping developers making it is easier at least when the standard commission already considered to include the whole map (though it has nothing directly to do with locale integration of qx now)

- As far as I can see there is just a single project wanting this (Stefan&#39;s),
and I&#39;m not sure we should invest for a one-off effort.

Who has not been checking phone numbers? Few projects haven&#39;t... In Validate you do check email addresses....

- It would be much better IMO if Stefan makes this file part of his custom
project, so he can write a parser for it and integrate it into his app as he
sees fit. He could also make a static class out of it.

Well we have integrated into qooxdoo already for our use. We can share that with you if it makes life easier for you.


Keep up the good work!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35409</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:46:05 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>