<bug>
          <bug_id>5644</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-09-26 17:00:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>List Enhancment - Currently Selected Model Item Buffer</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-09-28 10:15:52 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.list</component>
          <version>1.5</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter>simonwhite</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26958</commentid>
            <who name="">simonwhite</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-26 17:00:18 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi

I would like to suggest a buffer be added to the list and table widgets which would contain the currently selected item in the model.  It would be updated on every selection change. This would allow the detection of changes made to the currently selected model item by data bound widgets.  One could simple check each item in the currently selected model item with the same item in the buffer to see if changes were made.  If changes have been made the programmer would then be able to send only the changed items back to a remote database for storage.

There should be several new methods created related to the buffer.  

1) getChangedItems() should return an array of changed item names.
2) getPreviousValue(name) should return the value of the named item from the buffer.

Example The list model.ARMaster contains the following items: Name, Address1,Address2,ZIP,TelNo and the user has changed the values of the ZIP, and TelNo.  In this case the getChangedItems().getLength() would return 2  and getChangedItems(0)=&quot;ZIP&quot;,getChangedItems(1)=&quot;TelNo&quot; and getPreviousValue(&quot;TelNo&quot;) would return the value the TelNo had when the item was most recently selected in the list.

Thanks,
Simon</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26975</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-27 10:30:59 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hey,
thanks for the report. Did you check out the changeBubbles events of the models? Those are somehow what your looking for. Additionally, take a look at the change event of an data array. It contains also necessary data which items have changed. You can implement that yourself because I really doubt that we are going to add such a feature.
Regards,
Martin</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>26997</commentid>
            <who name="">simonwhite</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-27 22:26:14 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>It appears to me that they would indeed serve my purpose but I do not think I want to trigger saving to the database on every change.  I would prefer to wait until the user navigates to another item in the list or closes the window.  This way I send all the changes for database record together and reduce the number of trips to the server.

So unless you have a better suggestion I will implement a single item array buffer that is loaded on every change of selection and then use it to determine what to send to the database because I presume that the information about the changed items is only accessible from one of the change events.

Simon</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27004</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-28 10:15:52 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #2)
&gt; It appears to me that they would indeed serve my purpose but I do not think I
&gt; want to trigger saving to the database on every change.  
You don&#39;t have to. Just save the changes somewhere and write back the changes whenever you desire.

&gt; So unless you have a better suggestion I will implement a single item array
&gt; buffer that is loaded on every change of selection and then use it to determine
&gt; what to send to the database because I presume that the information about the
&gt; changed items is only accessible from one of the change events.
I think thats a good idea to solve that on the application side and I don&#39;t have any other suggestion for you except to try to sue the events to fill that buffer.

I will close the bug as wontfix because, as already said, I don&#39;t expect us to add something here.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>