<bug>
          <bug_id>5666</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-09-29 17:29:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>encodeUriComponent should be encodeURIComponent</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2011-09-29 19:19:57 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>contrib</product>
          <component>UploadMgr</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Steve Thomson">organicpanda</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>derrell.lipman</cc>
          <qa_contact name="John Spackman">john.spackman</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27053</commentid>
            <who name="Steve Thomson">organicpanda</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-29 17:29:46 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Guys,

In XhrHandler.js on line 108 encodeUriComponent should be encodeURIComponent (notice RI in URI is uppercase).

I noticed this because I added an extra param like so:

var uploader = new com.zenesis.qx.upload.UploadMgr(btn, uploadUrl);
uploader.__uploadHandler.addParam(&#39;test&#39;, &#39;this is a test&#39;);

Which causes the error.

Another thing I wondered about is why there is no easy way to add params. Is this intentional? As you can see from the example I have worked around it by accessing __uploadHandler directly but I was wondering if there was a reason there are no &#39;public&#39; methods for adding params, unless i&#39;m missing something?

Thanks for the awesome uploader!
Hope this helps.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27054</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-29 17:37:25 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #0)
&gt; Another thing I wondered about is why there is no easy way to add params. Is
&gt; this intentional? As you can see from the example I have worked around it by
&gt; accessing __uploadHandler 

Your work-around will fail as soon as you generate a &quot;build&quot; version. That private member will no longer be accessible to you.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27055</commentid>
            <who name="Steve Thomson">organicpanda</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-29 17:41:05 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Ahh good point. I guess I&#39;ll add a getter to com.zenesis.qx.upload.UploadMgr as a better work-around. It would be nice to see an easier way to add params added to this contrib in future though.

Thanks for the tip!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27056</commentid>
            <who name="Steve Thomson">organicpanda</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-29 17:52:28 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thinking about it i&#39;ve just extended com.zenesis.qx.upload.UploadMgr in my own namespace to add the getter which seems like a pretty clean solution so I&#39;m happy. The original bug still stands though (encodeUriComponent -&gt; encodeURIComponent)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27057</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-29 18:02:15 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #3)
&gt; Thinking about it i&#39;ve just extended com.zenesis.qx.upload.UploadMgr in my own
&gt; namespace to add the getter which seems like a pretty clean solution so I&#39;m
&gt; happy.

Are you sure? Subclasses have no more access to private variables than do users of a class. (Protected variables, those with a single underscore, are intended to be accessed by subclasses but not by other users.) If you are now accessing that private variable __uploadHandler from your subclass, you&#39;re in the same shape you were with your original use. It will fail in the build version...</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27058</commentid>
            <who name="Steve Thomson">organicpanda</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-29 18:23:50 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Ahh, I&#39;m making a bit of a fool of myself here - I just really didn&#39;t want to hack the UploadMgr classes but I guess I&#39;ll have to.

Sorry for the confusion - at least I learned something about Qooxdoo private variables haha!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27059</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-29 18:30:32 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #5)
&gt; Ahh, I&#39;m making a bit of a fool of myself here

Nope, not at all.

&gt; - I just really didn&#39;t want to
&gt; hack the UploadMgr classes but I guess I&#39;ll have to.

The UploadMgr contrib is new within the past month, I believe. (Maybe it is just a new version that I&#39;m recalling, but I hadn&#39;t remembered seeing it previously.) I&#39;m quite sure, given an adequate argument for the need (as it appears you have), that the maintainer would be perfectly willing to add a getter for that variable. I&#39;d post to the mailing list about it, if I were you.

Cheers,

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27062</commentid>
            <who name="John Spackman">john.spackman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-29 18:59:45 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>&gt; The UploadMgr contrib is new within the past month, I believe. (Maybe it is
&gt; just a new version that I&#39;m recalling, but I hadn&#39;t remembered seeing it
&gt; previously.) I&#39;m quite sure, given an adequate argument for the need (as it
&gt; appears you have), that the maintainer would be perfectly willing to add a
&gt; getter for that variable. I&#39;d post to the mailing list about it, if I were you.

No worries, i&#39;m just doing it now :)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27063</commentid>
            <who name="John Spackman">john.spackman</who>
            <bug_when>2011-09-29 19:19:35 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #7)
&gt; &gt; The UploadMgr contrib is new within the past month, I believe. (Maybe it is
&gt; &gt; just a new version that I&#39;m recalling, but I hadn&#39;t remembered seeing it
&gt; &gt; previously.) I&#39;m quite sure, given an adequate argument for the need (as it
&gt; &gt; appears you have), that the maintainer would be perfectly willing to add a
&gt; &gt; getter for that variable. I&#39;d post to the mailing list about it, if I were you.
&gt; 
&gt; No worries, i&#39;m just doing it now :)

Fixed; UploadMgr has a new method getUploadHandler() and the encodeURIComponent is fixed too</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>