<bug>
          <bug_id>5726</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-10-20 14:27:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Table blocks scrolling</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2013-07-22 12:50:46 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.table</component>
          <version>1.5</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>DUPLICATE</resolution>
          <dup_id>7095</dup_id>
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Théo SOULIE">soulie</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27274</commentid>
            <who name="Théo SOULIE">soulie</who>
            <bug_when>2011-10-20 14:27:14 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>it is not possible to scroll in a qx.ui.container.Scroller containing multiple tables as the tables seems to block the mousewheel events

this bug can be reproduced using the following playground:
http://tinyurl.com/3zu34j2</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27284</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-10-21 08:03:52 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>It is, like with every other scroll container, only possible if the inner container is at its edge which means if you have scrolled your table container to the bottom, the events will passed to the site and that will scroll to the bottom as well. Thats how the browsers implement it and thats why we decided to do that as well. Give it a try, its possible to see it in your sample as well.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27285</commentid>
            <who name="Théo SOULIE">soulie</who>
            <bug_when>2011-10-21 08:58:50 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; It is, like with every other scroll container, only possible if the inner
&gt; container is at its edge which means if you have scrolled your table container
&gt; to the bottom, the events will passed to the site and that will scroll to the
&gt; bottom as well. Thats how the browsers implement it and thats why we decided to
&gt; do that as well. Give it a try, its possible to see it in your sample as well.

I understand this is a normal behavior, but our problem is that we can&#39;t scroll the table. As you can see in my playground, when your mouse is over the table the wheel has no effect, you can only scroll while pointing outside of the tables (or the header and statusbar).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27304</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-10-24 08:22:02 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The tables in your sample are empty. There is nothing to scroll in it. Sorry but I don&#39;t get what&#39;s wrong here. :(</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33039</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-06-21 08:10:02 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>

*** This bug has been marked as a duplicate of bug 7095 ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>