<bug>
          <bug_id>5857</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-12-01 16:56:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Decorator &quot;qx.ui..decoration.Background&quot; should inform developer that backgroundPosition does not work in IE &lt;=8</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:24:38 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>1.5</version>
          <rep_platform>IE 8</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P1</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>2.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</assigned_to>
          <cc>katja.deutschmann</cc>
    
    <cc>uwe.stahl</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Internet Explorer</cf_browser>
          <cf_browser_version>8</cf_browser_version>

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27755</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2011-12-01 16:56:57 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>If a developer uses a background decorator with a PNG image (which is normally 
the case) together with setting the &quot;backgroundPosition&quot; property the decorator 
should inform the developer that IE browsers are not capable of this.

At least with IE browsers till version 8 qooxdoo uses the AlphaImageLoader 
internally and this filter is not capable of using the &quot;background-position&quot; 
CSS property.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27770</commentid>
            <who name="Katja Deutschmann">katja.deutschmann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-12-02 08:21:23 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>However it would be very helpful if Qooxdoo would make it possible to use background-position for background-images filtered with AlphaImageLoader. As far as I know the AlphaImageLoader internally converts the background-image into a &quot;normal&quot; image. Qooxdoo nearly positions everythings absolute and puts it into divs so why not creating an extra div, setting the background-image to that div, filter the background-image and position the wrapper div with the position settings made originally for the background-image. You&#39;ll find a few workarounds with google, but I think that one was common practise some years ago when everyone had to handle IE6.

This problem is really annoying as you cannot even position an image simply on the right side or at the bottom of somethings or even use &quot;normal&quot; sprites. That leads to long-winded workarounds with a lot more images and rows of code for things that are so easy with background-positioning.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29761</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2012-06-13 18:23:51 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Out of scope -&gt; move to 2.1</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31288</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2012-11-08 12:59:20 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed bug with 

  34f6788f0fa36785f8f69ffbe6e95e9960476510 (master)

Now the background decorator displays a message whenever &#39;backgroundPosition&#39; 
is used together with an enabled AlphaImageLoader (relevant for IE6 - IE8).

The possibility to make use of the &#39;backgroundPosition&#39; property with the 
AlphaImageLoader is described at Bug #6980</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>38459</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:24:38 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>