<bug>
          <bug_id>5902</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-12-06 18:34:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Different dropdown width behavior of ComboBox and VirtualComboBox</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:45:47 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.virtual</component>
          <version>1.5</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://tinyurl.com/84jv5nm</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="saaj">id</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</assigned_to>
          <cc>simonwhite</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27850</commentid>
            <who name="saaj">id</who>
            <bug_when>2011-12-06 18:34:42 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>It stared when I tried virtual combobox as a drop-in replacement for common one. The problem is that dropdown doesn&#39;t grow in width having longer list items. Also there&#39;s no straight way to set fixed width separately to the main part of widget and to the dropdown. So it may be tricky to use it in some cases.

Looking in code, comboxes are implemented in similar way, but forcing width of dropdown (__adjustWidth) in virtual one, which seemed confusing. Some after the major difference has been found, common combobox&#39;s dropdown uses qx.ui.form.List, whereas virtual uses qx.ui.list.List. 

Since this difference I&#39;m not sure whether it&#39;s actually possible to grow the dropdown of virtual combobox, considering current virtual widget infrastructure.

Also qx.ui.virtual.core is marked &quot;experimental&quot; but is used by many stable widgets like qx.ui.form.VirtualComboBox through qx.ui.list.List, which is a bit misleading.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27852</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-12-07 08:21:16 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>As far as I know, this is currently a known problem / restriction of the virtual rendering. But Chris will sure remember better and can tell you, as the creator of the widget, some more details.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27856</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2011-12-07 09:16:36 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>It&#39;s like Martin sad, the virtual infrastructure doesn&#39;t support auto sizing (bug 5615), therefore the ellipsis when the items are to large. &quot;__adjustWidth&quot; is only to ensure that the popup has the same width like it&#39;s target for example VirtualSelectBox or VirtualComboBox (this was a requirement). The only workaround it to set the with to the target (VirtualSelectBox or VirtualComboBox).

The &quot;experimental&quot; means more like &quot;the API can change, be care full when use it&quot; and not &quot;be care full it is not tested&quot;.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>27859</commentid>
            <who name="saaj">id</who>
            <bug_when>2011-12-07 10:32:42 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for explanation, Christian. But setting target&#39;s width isn&#39;t the only workaround. More useful workaround is setting width in resize listener of dropdown (in my example), so the dropdown width may be controlled separately.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28008</commentid>
            <who name="">simonwhite</who>
            <bug_when>2011-12-15 00:33:12 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I would like to see an additional width property to that you could define the width of the popup list separately from the VirtualComboBox.  I would assume that this property would default to the width of the VirtualComboBox however it could be made wider by using a method like setPopupWidth().

Simon</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35291</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:45:47 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>