<bug>
          <bug_id>5959</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2011-12-19 13:18:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>One has to duplicate documentation when using interfaces</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:46:36 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.oo</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Johannes Kissel">johannes.kissel</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>vladimir.dobriakov</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28039</commentid>
            <who name="Johannes Kissel">johannes.kissel</who>
            <bug_when>2011-12-19 13:18:56 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The api viewer marks documentation as incomplete when stuff is only documented in an interface.

To fix this one has to copy the documentation from the interface to the implementing class which is not maintainable. This gets even worse when using super-interfaces.

Interface documentation should be inherited like for &quot;normal&quot; classes. Or there should at least be a workaround like an ignore annotation or one to signal that this is just interface implementation.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28040</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-12-19 16:21:09 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>As far as I know, this works like expected because we use that in the framework alike. Just take a look at the main method of the Basic Application:
http://demo.qooxdoo.org/current/apiviewer/#qx.application.Basic~main

The documentation is located in the interface itself.

Could you be a bit more precise whats not working? Just a little hint here, the signatures have to be exactly the same, renaming or omitting the parameter can cause such a break.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28043</commentid>
            <who name="Johannes Kissel">johannes.kissel</who>
            <bug_when>2011-12-19 16:42:02 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Our voluminous frontendframework.app.Context implementation is split into mixins for a better overview, with one mixin per concern. frontendframework.app.IContext also consists of multiple interfaces - one interface per concern.

So actually the problem is that it seems that one cannot use &quot;implements&quot; in a mixin. That would be the easiest way to point out the relation between Mixin and Interface and to recycle interface documentation in the mixins.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35591</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:46:36 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>