<bug>
          <bug_id>6017</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-01-10 15:22:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Add button to display full set of demos</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-07-04 10:22:27 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>app.demobrowser</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28211</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2012-01-10 15:22:25 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>There used to be a nice set of demos available, for those looking for code examples of many widgets. Those many demos were REALLY useful to learn about a widget.

Some time recently, many demos have been excluded by default, but I just found they are available by adding the query string:

  ?qxenv:demobrowser.withTests:true

Please add button to the demobrowser button bar that refreshes the demobrowser with the above query string, so that it displays all of the available demos.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28212</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2012-01-10 16:04:12 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>This button already exists, in the Debug menu. I think it would be nice to have it more obvious. I&#39;d never even noticed the Debug menu before. At least it&#39;s available. 

My recommendation would be to add a &quot;Test Demos&quot; or &quot;Advanced Applications&quot; button at the top level, so that these extra demos are clearly available to someone looking for them.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28218</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2012-01-11 09:28:09 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>We put the button and the demos away for a good reason. Those are not really good demos to show the good parts of the framework. Mostly they are tests for the developers, either those who build the feature initially or those who want to put something on top. As this is a rare case, I think it is ok to have it that way, at least currently. During the restructuring of the demo browser (#5938), we sure come up with another solution how to handle these &quot;tests&quot;. But until that, I don&#39;t want to put any effort into the current view.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>