<bug>
          <bug_id>6051</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-01-17 16:36:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Add support for readOnly in the checkbox</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-11-27 08:07:46 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.form</component>
          <version>1.6</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Benjamin Dreux">dreux.benjamin</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          <cc>dietrich.streifert</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Tristan Koch">tristan.koch</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28296</commentid>
            <who name="Benjamin Dreux">dreux.benjamin</who>
            <bug_when>2012-01-17 16:36:44 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>TextField have a property called readOnly.
When this property is set to true, the value of the field can not be changed by the user.

According to Daniel Wagner, this checkbox should not support this property, because the usage of this property could misslead the user.

But i think this support will make the form field  api more cohersive.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28297</commentid>
            <who name="Benjamin Dreux">dreux.benjamin</who>
            <bug_when>2012-01-17 16:49:00 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>In my opinion it would be really easy to do that.

We need to add a readOnly property.
Then in the _onExecute  method, we juste need to check the state of this property.
If it&#39;s false just return, else do the normal things of this method.

This would be the minimum for this functionnality to work.

But to be coherant with the behavior of the textField, we also need to change the behavior of the focus.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28304</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2012-01-18 09:30:59 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I just don&#39;t see the use case for a read-only checkbox. If you want to communicate a boolean state to the user without allowing them to change it, just use an icon. A checkbox is an interactive element, so if it&#39;s disabled, then it should be visually marked as such.
Read-only on text fields makes a certain amount of sense because unlike disabled, it still allows the text value to be copied. But that obviously doesn&#39;t apply to checkboxes.

I&#39;m all for keeping APIs consistent across related classes, just not at the cost of adding behavior to objects whether it makes sense or not.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31452</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2012-11-26 13:50:22 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Just found this report in qooxdoo-devel.

The use case for us would be the following:

We have a huge qx.ui.form.Form and renderers based on qx.ui.form.renderer.AbstractRenderer with a lot of radiobuttons and checkboxes.

The resulting rendered form widget is used (via model, controller et.al.) to retreive the form content from the backend which works perfect.

Based on the access rights of the current user the form is in a editable or a readonly state so we would like to use the same form for viewing data without allowing the user to change the contents or states of the form fields.

It would be a tremendous work to create another form widget for viewing the data readonly eg. by replacing radiobuttons and checkboxes by simple images because we have then to implement another stack for getting the data from the backend to the readonly form widget.

Please consider the implementation of readonly buttons.

Thank you.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31463</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2012-11-27 08:07:46 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>See my answer on the mailing list.
http://qooxdoo.678.n2.nabble.com/CheckBox-fields-and-readOnly-td7196506.html;cid=1353999539135-615</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>