<bug>
          <bug_id>6053</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-01-17 20:03:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Data Binding Fails to Save Value to List Model</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-01-19 07:58:48 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.databinding</component>
          <version>1.6</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter>simonwhite</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28302</commentid>
            <who name="">simonwhite</who>
            <bug_when>2012-01-17 20:03:05 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>If you change the value of a textbox which is bound to a list but you do not press Tab or Enter first and then click on a new list item your changes in the textbox are not saved to the list model.  If you press Tab or Enter first the changes are saved to the list model.  If you click on the same item in the list without first pressing Tab or Enter the changes are saved.  The problem only occurs if you make a new list selection without first pressing Tab or Enter.


http://tinyurl.com/7zf2n2h</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28303</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2012-01-18 09:10:26 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hey,
this is easy to explain but hard to fix so I take at first the easy way and explain why this happens. It all comes down to events and the change event of the textfield. If you press tab or enter in the text field, the value will be applied and the change event will be fired. This causes the list to update in the end. If you just leave the textfield and click the same selected item, the list does not fire a changeSelection which then does not change the content of the text field. But if you click another item, the change selection event will be fired and the binding executed which changes the content of the textfield before your changes has been applied to the model. Its a matter of execution order of bindings which is not guaranteed to be in any order at all.
Now comes the hard part, I don&#39;t see a way to fix that. A fix would cause a huge amount of work to investigate and fix the problem. Instead, I would suggest to enable the live update on the textfield which changes the behavior but fixes the problem.
Best,
Martin</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28305</commentid>
            <who name="">simonwhite</who>
            <bug_when>2012-01-18 14:51:47 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Excuse my ignorance but is live update on the textfield?

Simon

(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; Hey,
&gt; this is easy to explain but hard to fix so I take at first the easy way and
&gt; explain why this happens. It all comes down to events and the change event of
&gt; the textfield. If you press tab or enter in the text field, the value will be
&gt; applied and the change event will be fired. This causes the list to update in
&gt; the end. If you just leave the textfield and click the same selected item, the
&gt; list does not fire a changeSelection which then does not change the content of
&gt; the text field. But if you click another item, the change selection event will
&gt; be fired and the binding executed which changes the content of the textfield
&gt; before your changes has been applied to the model. Its a matter of execution
&gt; order of bindings which is not guaranteed to be in any order at all.
&gt; Now comes the hard part, I don&#39;t see a way to fix that. A fix would cause a
&gt; huge amount of work to investigate and fix the problem. Instead, I would
&gt; suggest to enable the live update on the textfield which changes the behavior
&gt; but fixes the problem.
&gt; Best,
&gt; Martin</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28307</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2012-01-19 07:58:48 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #2)
&gt; Excuse my ignorance but is live update on the textfield?
&gt; 
&gt; Simon

It&#39;s a property on the TextField and you can use it like this:

textBox.setLiveUpdate(true);

http://tinyurl.com/7b4xp5w</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>