<bug>
          <bug_id>6156</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-02-18 16:18:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Add Support for Running the Source Version from a Web Server</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:47:17 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator.config</component>
          <version>1.6</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://qooxdoo.org/documentation/general/snippets#running_a_source_version_from_a_web_server</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28592</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2012-02-18 16:18:48 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Many people try to run the &#39;source&#39; version of their qooxdoo app through a web server. While most manage to load the application&#39;s source/index.html over the server, subsequent loads for framework classes and resources (and maybe classes and resources of other qooxdoo libraries or contribs) fail. The reason for this is that the relative paths generated by the generator break under the web server&#39;s configuration, as they are overstepping the web server&#39;s DocumentRoot (ie. too many &quot;../&quot; in the URI, s. linked URL).

The generator could check if the source version it is building will run from a given web server. To achieve that, it would need to know the DocumentRoot of the web server that will later export the application. This could be passed as a configuration entry, or as a command line parameter, and would then trigger the check. The generator would match the calculated relative paths to all the involved libraries to this DocumentRoot, to see if there is an overstepping of the root, and would then issue a corresponding shell message.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35852</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:47:17 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>