<bug>
          <bug_id>6157</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-02-20 15:39:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Set the build Version &#39;format&#39; to False by Default</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:22:20 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>1.6</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>2.0</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          <cc>derrell.lipman</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28601</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2012-02-20 15:39:14 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The build parameter &#39;format&#39; (compile-options/code/format) is true by default. 
This means that the generator inserts newlines in various places in the 
generated version. This can sum up to a couple of KB in the generated script 
which could be saved. (Any modern compressor like uglifyjs or Closure 
compressor is removing those). The reason for the extra line breaks is easier 
debugging of the build version. But this is rarely used. So I suggest setting 
&#39;format&#39; to false by default. Any project wanting to retain the extra line 
breaks can set it to &#39;true&#39; in their app config.json.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28603</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2012-02-20 16:10:38 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Setting this parameter to true by default will completely eliminate the possibility of debugging a newly-discovered bug on a version out in the field. The overhead of those extra few kb pale in relationship to the pain that would be caused by forgetting to change this parameter back to false. Please don&#39;t change the default.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28604</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2012-02-20 16:34:10 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; Setting this parameter to true by default will completely eliminate the
&gt; possibility of debugging a newly-discovered bug on a version out in the field.
&gt; The overhead of those extra few kb pale in relationship to the pain that would
&gt; be caused by forgetting to change this parameter back to false. Please don&#39;t
&gt; change the default.

Derrell,

I see your argument, but I&#39;m not so sure. I don&#39;t see why people shouldn&#39;t turn it back on if they so wish. On the other hand, people are reaching out for uglifyjs and Google Closure to run them over the *generated* build version, because they can gain those extra kb (which can be in the range of 5-10KB for larger apps). None of those tools leave the line breaks in, and I&#39;m a bit tired of the argument the others &quot;compress better&quot;. Hints at this point towards turning &#39;format&#39; to false have been constantly ignored.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29690</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2012-06-06 18:20:35 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed with

master: 631a61f</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37636</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:22:20 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>