<bug>
          <bug_id>617</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2007-09-04 10:37:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>missing in documentation and/or demo: use of qxsettings</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2008-09-02 23:14:54 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>website</product>
          <component>documentation</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Torsten Wesolek">torsten.wesolek</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2181</commentid>
            <who name="Torsten Wesolek">torsten.wesolek</who>
            <bug_when>2007-09-04 10:37:46 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The demo for use of qx.ui.basic.Inline (Inline_1.html) does not explain how to switch on the browser scrollbars.

Solution: Include something like this in the doc and/or source:
To enable scrollbars on the client document, please change the setting
(default defined in qx.ui.core.ClientDocument), e.g. include the
following in a &lt;script&gt; block before the your application js is
included:
var qxsetting = new Object();
qxsettings[&quot;qx.enableApplicationLayout&quot;] = false;</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2217</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2007-09-11 13:54:21 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The usage of settings is explained here:
http://qooxdoo.org/documentation/0.7/settings

I don&#39;t think we need to repeat this in the separate demos.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2321</commentid>
            <who name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</who>
            <bug_when>2007-09-14 11:41:33 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>&gt; I don&#39;t think we need to repeat this in the separate demos.

I disagree most strongly. The documentation system for settings is appalling and must be improved. The wiki page you reference makes no mention of:

a) how to define settings before including the main script, as described in the bug report
b) This particular setting (or indeed any other possible settings that might be useful).

This implies another wiki page is required describing possible settings as well as rectifying the first point.

Regarding the API system, settings aren&#39;t even included in the output. So you have no idea what is there. And when you look at a setting in the source code there may not even be a comment about what it is for.

I think that the API system should at least include all settings in the output for a class, with normal comment description. And in addition, as the settings are designed to be global, another section should be placed at the top level description of each package which lists the available settings for all the classes within a package, and links to the class/setting to get a detailed description.

Hugh</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2322</commentid>
            <who name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</who>
            <bug_when>2007-09-14 11:43:35 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Just as a further note: if a user is saying that documentation needs to be improved, that&#39;s normally because they&#39;ve wasted a day or two trying to work out how to do something in qooxdoo. It might be obvious to you how to use a particular area, but spare a thought for the user coming to this cold.

Hugh</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2343</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2007-09-18 18:13:59 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>OK, you are right. But it is always nice to get some more details. Sorry for the bit short version of my question.

However this is not a framework bug then, but a website/documentation bug. Corrected this.

If you really think you &quot;wasted a day or two trying to work out how to do something in qooxdoo&quot; wouldn&#39;t it be nice to add your result to the wiki as well and helping other users this way too? This is my understanding of open source: helping each other.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2348</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2007-09-18 18:20:07 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Changed to severity=enhancement</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5007</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-02 23:14:54 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Think this is already done with the new generator sections in the wiki.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>