<bug>
          <bug_id>6199</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-03-07 13:48:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Button focus partially hides button image</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2013-09-30 09:00:57 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.theming</component>
          <version>1.6</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://preview.tinyurl.com/8y4arrl</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>minor</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>3.0.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Jonathan">jonathan.wolfe</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28764</commentid>
            <who name="Jonathan">jonathan.wolfe</who>
            <bug_when>2012-03-07 13:48:36 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>You can reproduce the issue when toggling the button twice (on - off), and then moving between hovered and not hovered.

http://preview.tinyurl.com/8y4arrl</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>28774</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2012-03-08 08:41:03 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33753</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-08-27 15:23:36 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This is a theme dependent issue. It only appears in the modern theme. 

The reason for that is the different border width of focused and non focused state. The default border width of the modern theme&#39;s button is 1 px. In the case of a focused button, it gets a inner blue border on top with 2 px, which means the border is 3 px in total. That leads to a change of dimensions on a focus which is not good at all. So the theming uses the padding to keep the size the same by simply reducing the padding by 2 px each side on focus. 

Now back to the given sample. In it, the padding is set manually which then, ofc, does not consider the focus state which causes the button to increase its size if you remove the fixed size setting. With the size setting, the images moves and we have the seen effect.

Now that we know why this happens, we still have to question how to fix that. I currently have no idea how to fix that with a common an generic solution. The theming uses the padding which is the right thing to do but the user overrides these values. So the system takes the user values which is also the right thing to do. So I would suggest to fix that in the user code and attach a listener to the focus/blur event and reduce the padding there.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>