<bug>
          <bug_id>620</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2007-09-05 11:44:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Stray mouseup causes unwelcome selection in a table</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:27:50 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.table</component>
          <version>0.7.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://www.nabble.com/combobox-and-event-question-tf4335283.html</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.7.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Til Schneider">tilman.schneider</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2188</commentid>
            <who name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</who>
            <bug_when>2007-09-05 11:44:26 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This is from an email thread - see http://www.nabble.com/combobox-and-event-question-tf4335283.html

Text of message documenting the reason for the issue is:

&gt; Assuming that we have a widget like a combobox. If I want to select 
&gt; an
&gt; entry, the popup of the combobox opens. I click on an ListItem. The 
&gt; combobox
&gt; disappears.
&gt; But the click event is not eaten. In my case it changes the active 
&gt; Row in a
&gt; table, which is below the combobox.
&gt; If you want to see this in action please have a look at here:
&gt; http://www.fitnesswelt.com/shopajx.html - In the first field type in
&gt; something, the table should be filled. Then you can try to change 
&gt; the
&gt; listboxes. If you have your browser configured to allow open 
&gt; popups, you
&gt; will se what I mean.

It happens on the first click, when there is nothing selected in the
table. And then it only happens if you have just clicked on the selected
row (for example, select the second row and then click on it again).

Also it only happens when the mouse is being released. If you do mouse
down, and hold it, the combo-box disappears and the table is reloaded but
nothing is selected in it. Then release the mouse and the first row is
selected.

*BUG 1* The main issue would appear to be that qooxdoo should handle the
selection process in mouse up in the combo box, rather than mouse down.
Then the mouse up wouldn&#39;t be sent to the table that&#39;s underneath.

Analysing the reason for the mouse up behaviour, we can see it by looking
at qx.ui.table.selection.Manager.js. handleMouseUp has this code:

      if (evt.isLeftButtonPressed() &amp;&amp; !this._lastMouseDownHandled) {
        this._handleSelectEvent(index, evt);
      }
      
But this._lastMouseDownHandled is only created when there has been a
mouse down event on the table. So it is &quot;undefined&quot; when the first
mouseUp event occurs. *BUG 2* - prevent this happening perhaps with
another flag to indicate that no mouse event has come through yet.

Then in handleMouseDown there is code that affects
this._lastMouseDownHandled - setting it to false if a click is made on
the current selection (which is why the problem you see occurs when you
click on a row that is already selected). *BUG 3* - reset the flag in
mouseUp if you have clicked on a row that is already selected.

There are some options to fix this:

1. rename this._lastMouseDownHandled to this._handleClickOnMouseUp which
also inverts the sense of it, so the test in handleMouseUp tests for
&quot;true&quot; rather than false. If it&#39;s true, then on MouseUp it&#39;s reset to
false. Then when it is undefined, or a mouseUp is made on the same table
entry (with no mouseDown), the flag is false and it doesn&#39;t result in a
select event.

2. Another way, which would fix the combo box problem as well, is to only
handle click events on mouse up anyway. That way the combo box would eat
the mouse up event.

Option 2 is probably the best way of handling it as otherwise the
drag/drop functionality is probably going to be affected.

Hugh</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2216</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2007-09-11 13:52:04 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Added to the list for 0.7.2.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2342</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2007-09-18 18:01:53 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>fixed in trunk and legacy.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>39603</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:27:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>