<bug>
          <bug_id>6298</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-04-10 15:22:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Test Ripple for mobile development</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-04-11 13:36:19 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>mobile</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Tino Butz">tinobutz</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Christopher Zuendorf">christopher.zuendorf</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Tino Butz">tinobutz</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29090</commentid>
            <who name="Tino Butz">tinobutz</who>
            <bug_when>2012-04-10 15:22:11 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>&quot;What Is Ripple

Ripple is a multi-platform mobile environment emulator that runs in a web browser and is custom-tailored to HTML5 mobile application testing. Ripple aims to reduce the challenges being faced by mobile developers caused by today&#39;s platform fragmentation in the marketplace.

It offers the ability to look under the hood of your mobile applications, gaining full visibility into what your it is doing. It also allows for the use of existing tools to perform JavaScript debugging, HTML DOM inspection, automated testing, as well as multiple device and screen resolution emulation in real-time without having to redeploy the mobile application or restart the emulator.

Ripple is built as a Chrome extension, running as part of the Chrome browser and takes advantage of our back-end services to perform some of the more complex operations.&quot;

http://ripple.tinyhippos.com/</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29107</commentid>
            <who name="Christopher Zuendorf">christopher.zuendorf</who>
            <bug_when>2012-04-11 13:35:40 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Ripple does not have a lot of benefits for non-Blackberry mobile developers. Because it was bought by Blackberry the main focus of Ripple now lies in supporting Blackberry devices and BB Webworks. Even the documentation of Ripple refers to Blackberry website.
It is possible to simulate sensors, or GPS location changes, but this is not relevant to qooxdoo mobile.
The phonegap simulator only runs on v1.0.

The biggest benefit i see: It knows the screen sizes of several mobile devices, just like iPod, iPhone, Samsung Galaxy...
But for daily work, I would prefer weinre.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>