<bug>
          <bug_id>6348</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-04-20 19:02:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Dynamic stylesheets are not always recognised by Chrome</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-07-29 07:53:40 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>website.bom</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          <keywords>FixIncluded</keywords>
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="John Spackman">john.spackman</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29239</commentid>
            <who name="John Spackman">john.spackman</who>
            <bug_when>2012-04-20 19:02:55 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Dynamical stylesheets such as those added by qx.bom.Stylesheet.createElement sometimes do not take effect in Chrome.

In my test case, I had a full width table using default cell renderers and the cells would not appear; this was because the cells have styling applied by creating a stylesheet and adding the &quot;qooxdoo-table-cell&quot; class, but the class was being ignored.

Using the Chrome Debugging tools, I could open the Elements tree to find the cell&#39;s DIV; if I click on the DIV (in the Elements pane) the cells redraw themselves correctly.  If I do not click on the DIV but hover over it, a rectangle appears over the webpage showing where the DIV is...and it&#39;s below the table, well out of position.

Running this code in the javascript console also fixed the problem:

   var sheet = qx.bom.Stylesheet.createElement(&quot;.stuff { font-weight: inherit; } &quot;);
   qx.bom.Stylesheet.addRule(sheet, &quot;.more-stuff&quot;, &quot;font-weight: inherit;&quot;);

The key thing in this fix is that q.b.Stylesheet.addRule uses insertRule and *that* causes the stylesheet to be reevaluated.  q.b.Stylesheet.createElement on its own does not work because it only sets the style tag&#39;s cssText property.

It&#39;s difficult to provide a reproducable test case for this because it&#39;s so hard to reproduce - the two test cases I had would not occur if that section of my app was removed into a separate, standalone application but it appeared to be connected to adding a table during the appear event of a tab view page.

There is however an easy fix for this: in qx.bom.Stylesheet.createElement, for webkit browsers only, call insertRule to create a dummy rule after adding the style tag to the document head.

This problem occurs on Chrome 18 &amp; Safari on OSX 10.7 and Chrome 18 on XP 32bit.

Pull request to follow.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29240</commentid>
            <who name="John Spackman">john.spackman</who>
            <bug_when>2012-04-20 19:05:50 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Pull request https://github.com/qooxdoo/qooxdoo/pull/26</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>32949</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-06-17 11:11:54 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hello John,
I just checked your pull request and report. Tried to reproduce it as well but failed. I do have a bad feeling including the fix without knowing / understanding the reason why its necessary. If I can&#39;t reproduce it, there is no way of knowing when the browser bug in webkit is fixed and we can remove that fix. :(
I also had the problem that my system has non of the browsers you mentioned. Can you still reproduce the issue with the current chrome version? If so, is it possible to send me the your app (does not have to be public).
Regards,
Martin</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33298</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-07-10 13:24:35 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I won&#39;t fix that for the 3.0 release because we don&#39;t have a sample to reproduce the issue.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40848</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-07-29 07:53:40 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>