<bug>
          <bug_id>6384</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-05-08 11:07:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Enhance MScroll options</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:23:21 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>mobile.core</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>3.0</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Tino Butz">tinobutz</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Christopher Zuendorf">christopher.zuendorf</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Christopher Zuendorf">christopher.zuendorf</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29352</commentid>
            <who name="Tino Butz">tinobutz</who>
            <bug_when>2012-05-08 11:07:04 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>iScroll provides some convenient features as options:

e.g. var myScroll = new iScroll(&#39;wrapper&#39;, { hScrollbar: false, vScrollbar: false });

These options are:

- hScroll, used to disable the horizontal scrolling no matter what. By default you can pan both horizontally and vertically, by setting this parameter to false you may prevent horizontal scroll even if contents exceed the wrapper.
- vScroll, same as above for vertical scroll.
- hScrollbar, set this to false to prevent the horizontal scrollbar to appear.
- vScrollbar, same as above for vertical scrollbar.
- fixedScrollbar, on iOS the scrollbar shrinks when you drag over the scroller boundaries. Setting this to true prevents the scrollbar to move outside the visible area (as per Android). Default: true on Android, false on iOS.
- fadeScrollbar, set to false to have the scrollbars just disappear without the fade effect.
- hideScrollbar, the scrollbars fade away when there’s no user interaction. You may want to have them always visible. Default: true.
- bounce, enable/disable bouncing outside of the boundaries. Default: true.
- momentum, enable/disable inertia. Default: true. Useful if you want to save resources.
- lockDirection, when you start dragging on one axis the other is locked and you can keep dragging only in two directions (up/down or left/right). You may remove the direction locking by setting this parameter to false.
- zoom: true
- zoomMax, this is the maximum allowed scale. Defaulted to 4, it means 4 times the original size.
- snap: true,
- snap : &quot;li&quot;

We should allow to pass this options as a constructor argument.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31954</commentid>
            <who name="Christopher Zuendorf">christopher.zuendorf</who>
            <bug_when>2013-01-21 17:16:41 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Master:
4c9fc83da3535a5ee0ebcae4070a8762ce9b838f</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37981</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:23:21 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>