<bug>
          <bug_id>6421</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-05-16 11:40:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>VirtualSelectBox has selection property whose changeSelection event is confusing</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-05-21 08:22:25 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>documentation.api</component>
          <version>1.6</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>DUPLICATE</resolution>
          <dup_id>6012</dup_id>
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>trivial</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Omri Har-Shemesh">omrihar</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29474</commentid>
            <who name="Omri Har-Shemesh">omrihar</who>
            <bug_when>2012-05-16 11:40:28 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The VirtualSelectBox has a property named &quot;selection&quot; which contains the qx.data.Array which represents the selection in the select box.
Unlike the SelectBox, the &quot;changeSelection&quot; event of the VirtualSelectBox never gets fired because the selection Array does not change.
In order to attach an event that will be called when the selection in the VirtualSelectBox changes, one has to attach (imho counter-intuitively) the event handler in the following way:

var list = new qx.ui.form.VirtualSelectBox();
list.getSelection().addListener(&quot;change&quot;, callback);

Since changing this behavior is complicated, I suggest stressing this in the API documentation of the changeSelection event which is the only event in qx.ui.form.VirtualSelectBox. For the newbie it is extremely confusing, and I also keep forgetting it though I use VirtualSelectBox quite often.

Thanks,
Omri</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>29489</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2012-05-21 08:22:19 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thats a pattern we have all over the framework and we know that it might be confusing compared to the old style. Thats why we intend to write an article for the manual about the whole topic which will cover the topic in detail. Adding a hint to the API is still a good idea but not as easy because the changeSelection event of VirtualSelectBox e.B. is a generated event which also covers its documentation.
Still, we will take care of that topic and write the article to clear things up.

*** This bug has been marked as a duplicate of bug 6012 ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>