<bug>
          <bug_id>6640</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-07-16 17:33:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Add possibility to check used translation keys</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:21:21 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>2.0</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>2.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          <cc>alexander.steitz</cc>
    
    <cc>mustafa.sak</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30152</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2012-07-16 17:33:15 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>At the moment it is not possible to verify whether the generated application is completely translated.

What we need is a warning for each used key which is not translated in an used po file. The check should only be done for the created application. This means that removed code form the code optimization should not be logged as warning.

It should also be possible to set one language as default. The default language should be ignored from the checks, because this is normyl the language which is used for the keys.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30540</commentid>
            <who name="Mustafa Sak">mustafa.sak</who>
            <bug_when>2012-08-30 16:22:04 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The generator is able to print the percentage value of translated msgid&#39;s for each language. this can easily done with the parameter -v e.g. ./generate.py translation -v

A out print like this will be shown at the end:


- Updating 5 translations...
      - Processing: en
        - Percent translated: 99
      - Processing: de
        - Percent translated: 69
      - Processing: es
        - Percent translated: 99
      - Processing: fr
        - Percent translated: 99
      - Processing: pl
        - Percent translated: 99


In that example de is &quot;default&quot; language, so his result could be ignored. But for the other languages by such a out print, it means to be carefully, at least one msgid is not translated.

That why we should set the scope to make the generator able to just calculating the statistics for optimized code. That means, only classes which will be used for build version should be count. That helps developers to handle translations carefully even if they write one code base at source version, but generating different build versions with code exclusion (qx environment). This not needed msgid&#39;s wouldn&#39;t be counted and warned.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30781</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2012-09-24 10:30:49 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Commited a solution.

In order to get the translation reporting for a built app you need to run the 
generate.py job (source, build, ...) with the &#39;-v&#39; flag.

In order to filter out verbose messages not related to translations, add the 
following key to the job&#39;s config:

  &quot;log&quot; : { &quot;filter&quot; : { &quot;debug&quot; : 
[&quot;generator.code.CodeGenerator.printTranslationStats&quot;] }}

To filter out locales for which you don&#39;t want translation reporting, add 
something like the following to the job:

  &quot;log&quot; : { &quot;translations&quot; : { &quot;untranslated-keys&quot; : { &quot;skip-locales&quot; : [ &quot;C&quot;, 
&quot;en&quot; ] }}}

The Feedreader has a demo job &#39;source-with-translations&#39; to showcase these 
settings and to see the results. Please test and provide feedback.

master: 4b4cba7</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30865</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</who>
            <bug_when>2012-10-02 13:45:50 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Verified. The feature is implemented like described.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31657</commentid>
            <who name="Mustafa Sak">mustafa.sak</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-06 10:56:03 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Could you please provide the logs with line numbers?

I would love to see the untranslated message ids in a list grouped by the corresponding po file.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37258</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:21:21 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>