<bug>
          <bug_id>6659</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-07-23 08:39:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Indigo Input Elements in a Grid Layout</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-10-01 14:12:21 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.theming</component>
          <version>2.0.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>INVALID</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>2.0.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Marc S.">qooxdoo</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30223</commentid>
            <who name="Marc S.">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2012-07-23 08:39:58 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hey, it seems that I found a little bug with the new Indigo Theme and Input Elements in a Grid Layout

Please take a look on this Demo page

http://tinyurl.com/cydhsec

(the window will be appear on the top left of your browser (!)).

If you focus an input element, the elemts gets bigger because of the big fat blue decoration. That causes that the layout jumps for a view pixel.

In the old Theme this doesn&#39;t happen.

Regards

Marc</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30490</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2012-08-27 10:25:12 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hey,
this problem hast its root in the demo code. To simplify the discussion, here is the striped down sample:

var window = new qx.ui.window.Window(&quot;hello world&quot;);
window.setLayout(new qx.ui.layout.Grid());
window.fieldName = new qx.ui.form.TextField();
				
window.add(window.fieldName.set({
  paddingTop: 3
}), {row: 0, column : 0});


this.getRoot().add(window);
window.show();


The problem is the paddingTop which will be set. Taking a look at the theme make it clear:

        } else if (states.focused) {
          decorator = &quot;focused-inset&quot;;
          padding = [1, 2];
        } else {
          padding = [2, 3];
          decorator = &quot;inset&quot;;
        }

The theme reacts on on the focused state and reduces the padding by 1 because the border set by the decorator is bigger. If you now set a paddingTop as a user value, the theme value will no longer be used and with that, the padding will stay stable no matter what state the textfield is is. But the decorator will be changed which causes the layout issues.

I don&#39;t know what you wanted to do with that paddingTop? If you want to make sure the text fields are 3 px away from each other you should use margin and the problem is gone. Another solution would be to use a custom appearance for your textfields and react on the states as well.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>