<bug>
          <bug_id>6689</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-08-03 23:46:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>App Cache Manifest Generation for HTML5 Apps</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:46:48 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter>sub.contact</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30318</commentid>
            <who name="">sub.contact</who>
            <bug_when>2012-08-03 23:46:52 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I haven&#39;t found this feature around anywhere yet but I think it&#39;s an obvious killer feature

It would provide a configurable way to walk through the build source tree and generate the manifest (or part of it)
It would also update the tag to reference the manifest
It would be configurable in terms what to include/exclude, insert a version number and all that sort of stuff.

This would be great!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30319</commentid>
            <who name="">sub.contact</who>
            <bug_when>2012-08-04 01:37:47 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Just added more context to the request:

The HTML5 App Cache feature is usually associated with the ability of offline capability but in my opinion the strongest capability this brings is fast (really fast) app start up. That&#39;s especially important on mobile and brings Web Apps closer to parity with Native Apps.

(In reply to comment #0)
&gt; I haven&#39;t found this feature around anywhere yet but I think it&#39;s an obvious
&gt; killer feature
&gt; 
&gt; It would provide a configurable way to walk through the build source tree and
&gt; generate the manifest (or part of it)
&gt; It would also update the tag to reference the manifest
&gt; It would be configurable in terms what to include/exclude, insert a version
&gt; number and all that sort of stuff.
&gt; 
&gt; This would be great!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30325</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2012-08-06 09:53:57 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Could you elaborate more on the benefits of this approach?! E.g. why would anybody maintain data in config.json when it is the same effort to maintain the cache manifest directly?! Which &quot;tag&quot; are you speaking of?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30329</commentid>
            <who name="">sub.contact</who>
            <bug_when>2012-08-06 11:06:03 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Thomas,

Thanks for looking at this.

I believe the key benefit is that it allows for web applications to be, in effect, &quot;installed&quot; on the local device. This allows the web application to start up much faster. It eliminates all of the network download, latency etc that is associated large web applications, especially when multiple HTTP requests are involved.

The second benefit is the ability for offline support (when you tie it together with localStorage), which allows you to run the application even though you may not be online. This could provide interesting options for mobile app development.

I&#39;m not sure I understood what you meant by maintenance of config.json vs cache manifest. Would you explain this a little more?

Sorry about the tag reference - I meant &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; . Meaning this feature would add or remove the reference to the manifest file inside of the &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; tag.
It must have been stripped out when I entered the feature request.

I don&#39;t think this would be too hard. Essentially you need to walk through the build directory tree and compile a file list, add a version number, a few filtering and maybe template options and ensure it&#39;s referenced in the html tag.
I&#39;m not a python programmer so I don&#39;t where you would start but I did come across a starting point from another build tool that&#39;s in JavaScript -&gt; https://github.com/volojs/volo-appcache

It looks like this would be a duplicate of bug #4248 though I believe the fast startup capability is a stronger benefit than offline capability.

By the way - your build tools are fantastic (just like the rest of Qooxdoo) - I would think that the build tools could be adapted for more generic JavaScript / HTML5 development. 

(In reply to comment #2)
&gt; Could you elaborate more on the benefits of this approach?! E.g. why would
&gt; anybody maintain data in config.json when it is the same effort to maintain the
&gt; cache manifest directly?! Which &quot;tag&quot; are you speaking of?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30330</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2012-08-06 11:22:28 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #3)
&gt; I believe the key benefit is that it allows for web applications to be, in
&gt; effect, &quot;installed&quot; on the local device...

My question was not concerning the benefits of the app cache manifest, but concerning *generating* the cache manifest (as this is the purpose of your bug). Where would generation be advantageous over maintaining the cache manifest by hand, esp. given the fact that most of its information needed to go into config.json, so why not putting it into the cache manifest directly?

&gt; Sorry about the tag reference - I meant &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; . Meaning this feature
&gt; would add or remove the reference to the manifest file inside of the
&gt; &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; tag.

You mean in the app&#39;s index.html.

&gt; It looks like this would be a duplicate of bug #4248 though I believe the fast
&gt; startup capability is a stronger benefit than offline capability.

Indeed, and I would kindly ask you to add your arguments and use cases as comments there (I&#39;m going to close this bug as duplicate).

&gt; 
&gt; By the way - your build tools are fantastic (just like the rest of Qooxdoo)

Thanks :).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30359</commentid>
            <who name="">sub.contact</who>
            <bug_when>2012-08-11 05:43:48 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #4)
&gt; (In reply to comment #3)
&gt; &gt; I believe the key benefit is that it allows for web applications to be, in
&gt; &gt; effect, &quot;installed&quot; on the local device...
&gt; 
&gt; My question was not concerning the benefits of the app cache manifest, but
&gt; concerning *generating* the cache manifest (as this is the purpose of your
&gt; bug). Where would generation be advantageous over maintaining the cache
&gt; manifest by hand, esp. given the fact that most of its information needed to go
&gt; into config.json, so why not putting it into the cache manifest directly?
&gt; 

It&#39;s to manage the resources folder such a theme icons, #asset declarations etc.


&gt; &gt; Sorry about the tag reference - I meant &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; . Meaning this feature
&gt; &gt; would add or remove the reference to the manifest file inside of the
&gt; &gt; &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; tag.
&gt; 
&gt; You mean in the app&#39;s index.html.

Yes

&gt; 
&gt; &gt; It looks like this would be a duplicate of bug #4248 though I believe the fast
&gt; &gt; startup capability is a stronger benefit than offline capability.
&gt; 
&gt; Indeed, and I would kindly ask you to add your arguments and use cases as
&gt; comments there (I&#39;m going to close this bug as duplicate).
&gt; 
&gt; &gt; 
&gt; &gt; By the way - your build tools are fantastic (just like the rest of Qooxdoo)
&gt; 
&gt; Thanks :).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35669</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:46:48 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>