<bug>
          <bug_id>6707</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-08-13 15:49:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Patch data with multiple &quot;=&quot; in a Line corrupt Patterns</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:19:18 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.migration</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>2.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30365</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2012-08-13 15:49:42 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Trying to migrate a desktop skeleton to 2.1 fails with an error message of the migrator.py script.

Somehow the regular expressions seem to be wrong.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30366</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2012-08-13 16:06:40 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This line caused the issue:

  \bqx\.lang\.Object\.hasMinLength\((.*)\s*,\s*(.*)\)=($1.length &gt;= $2)

The issue is that the line contains two &quot;=&quot; signs. As &quot;=&quot; is part of the syntax of patch files, it is critical when it appears in either the search or replacement string. 

The migrator tries to amend for this, and supports escaping &quot;=&quot; signs with a backslash (&quot;\=&quot;). For those cases when there are multiple unescaped &quot;=&quot; signs in the patch line, all but the last would previously be assigned to the search pattern (ie. the search pattern automatically extended until the last unescaped &quot;=&quot;).

I inverted that logic in that the first unescaped &quot;=&quot; is now used to separate the search pattern from the replacement, no matter what comes after it. If you have &quot;=&quot; in your search pattern, you have to escape it.

(I think it is more intuitive to use escapes in the search pattern than in the replacement, so unescaped &quot;=&quot; in the replacement are now harmeless. It would be ugly, too, to escape the replacement in this case: &quot;... $1.length &gt;\= $2..&quot;).

But this introduces a subtle difference to the old processing, and there might be old *.dat files that implicitly rely on the old implementation, so we might get issues with old *.dat files when they are processed during migration. In such cases we have to correct the .dat files.

master: 2246b2f</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36431</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:19:18 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>