<bug>
          <bug_id>6767</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-09-03 13:24:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>IE8 has issues with gradient filter</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:22:59 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>2.0.2</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          <cc>uwe.stahl</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Internet Explorer</cf_browser>
          <cf_browser_version>&lt; 9</cf_browser_version>

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30570</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2012-09-03 13:24:17 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>IE8 has an issue when a gradient filter is used within a nested structure of widgets. E.g. if you use a gradient filter on a button which is nested within a widget structure the text of the button is not displayed anymore by IE8.

IE9 wasn&#39;t tested, yet.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30607</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2012-09-05 14:20:39 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This is a bug in IE triggered by the combination of the alpha (opacity) filter and the gradient filter.

IE9 doesn&#39;t have this issue, presumably because it supports CSS opacity instead of the alpha filter.

A comment on the MSDN page for GradientFilter suggests adding an invisible drop shadow filter to fix the text display:
http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms532997(v=vs.85).aspx

However, this only works if the drop shadow is applied to the element containing the text node so we can&#39;t simply add it to the decorator element created by ui.decoration.MLinearBackgroundGradient. We would have to listen for changes on the opacity property and traverse the child widget hierarchy, looking for gradient decorators and applying the fix to the content elements of labels as needed. Conversely, we would also have to check the parent hierarchy for elements with the alpha filter every time a widget with a gradient decorator is added or an existing widget&#39;s decorator changes. Considering this seems to be a fairly exotic scenario since we never noticed this issue before, I&#39;m not sure it this is worth the runtime performance hit.

Alternatively, we could add the drop shadow filter to the content element of qx.ui.basic.Label by default, but that&#39;s hardly a clean solution either.

I would suggest avoiding the opacity/gradient combination in the application code for old IEs.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30611</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2012-09-05 16:26:26 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&#39;m fine with that.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37848</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:22:59 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>