<bug>
          <bug_id>6844</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-09-21 19:13:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>SelectBox/List initialization improvement</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:47:19 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.form</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Zdenko Turcan">qooxdoo-bugzilla</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30775</commentid>
            <who name="Zdenko Turcan">qooxdoo-bugzilla</who>
            <bug_when>2012-09-21 19:13:41 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>A performance of a rendering script processing of SelectBox can be significantly and quite easily improved by postponing list initialization to the first access of the list component (either programaticaly or by user interaction - e.g. by focusing).

From my own experience with QooXDoo I know that when we postpone the initialization of an embedded list widget, the main SelectBox component can be ready much soon (e.g.: in IE8 the script of selectbox initialization is done about 70% quicker when compared to full (not postponed) initialization; in chrome or firefox the improvement is about 40%). Of course, the results can vary, but improvement will be still significant. I&#39;ve had only few list items in selectbox and not a big number.

Just think about situation when you need to have a lot of selectboxes in your application...

I think that such scenario can be used also for other widgets and so it doesn&#39;t relate only to SelectBox.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30780</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2012-09-24 09:53:40 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Did you see the virtual widgets? There is also a virtual select box which only renders the widgets in the scroll pane. That improves rendering time as well.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30794</commentid>
            <who name="Zdenko Turcan">qooxdoo-bugzilla</who>
            <bug_when>2012-09-24 17:56:48 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hello, yes I know the virtual widgets, but still I think that some improvement can be done with non-virtual widgets as well (especially with SelectBox).

(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; Did you see the virtual widgets? There is also a virtual select box which only
&gt; renders the widgets in the scroll pane. That improves rendering time as well.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30805</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2012-09-25 08:09:58 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Sure.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35862</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:47:19 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>