<bug>
          <bug_id>6864</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-10-01 11:31:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Support mousewheel events on VirtualSelectBox</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-10-07 08:55:56 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.form</component>
          <version>2.0.2</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Marc Puts">marcputs</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30842</commentid>
            <who name="Marc Puts">marcputs</who>
            <bug_when>2012-10-01 11:31:23 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>With the regular SelectBox, it&#39;s possible to use the mousewheel to scroll through list without needing to open it first.

This is not possible with the VirtualSelectBox; it does not respond to mousewheel events at all. This is easily seen in the Widget Browser app.

It would be nice to have the same functionality here as in the regular SelectBox.

The same could also be done for the ComboBox and VirtualComboBox, both of which don&#39;t handle wheel events on the textfield part of the control. Scrolling in a ComboBox field could work the same as in a SelectBox.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30847</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2012-10-01 14:07:45 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #0)
&gt; With the regular SelectBox, it&#39;s possible to use the mousewheel to scroll
&gt; through list without needing to open it first.
I know and I really dislike the feature! This triggers a lot of change events, blocks scrolling and could cause unintentional value changes.

&gt; This is not possible with the VirtualSelectBox; it does not respond to
&gt; mousewheel events at all. This is easily seen in the Widget Browser app.
This is on intension because we decided not to remove the behavior in the old select box. Adding it to the virtual was never an option. :)

&gt; 
&gt; It would be nice to have the same functionality here as in the regular
&gt; SelectBox.
&gt; 
&gt; The same could also be done for the ComboBox and VirtualComboBox, both of which
&gt; don&#39;t handle wheel events on the textfield part of the control. Scrolling in a
&gt; ComboBox field could work the same as in a SelectBox.

Thats even worse because you might loose your entered content (which might not even be in the list) on scroll.

Sorry but I don&#39;t think thats a good feature to add.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30860</commentid>
            <who name="Marc Puts">marcputs</who>
            <bug_when>2012-10-02 11:26:05 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I see. I thought that the &quot;missing&quot; functionality from the virtual selectbox was an oversight, so I wanted to bring it up. But it&#39;s clearly not an oversight. Whether it&#39;s a likeable feature or not comes down to personal taste, but all of your points are absolutely valid, so the won&#39;t fix reso seems ok to me. :)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30897</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2012-10-07 08:55:56 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the reply and your understanding.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>