<bug>
          <bug_id>6880</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-10-05 12:11:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>SingleValueBinding: Converter not called when property chain breaks</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2013-01-21 09:13:31 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.databinding</component>
          <version>2.0.2</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>minor</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>2.1.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Marc Puts">marcputs</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          <cc>dietrich.streifert</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30894</commentid>
            <who name="Marc Puts">marcputs</who>
            <bug_when>2012-10-05 12:11:16 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>As posted on the mailing list [1]:

I&#39;m binding a property chain &quot;a.b.c&quot; using a converter function.

If &quot;a.b.c&quot; are all set, or if &quot;c&quot; is null, the converter function is 
called as expected (with c or null as data).

However, when the property chain breaks because &quot;a&quot; or &quot;b&quot; is null, then 
the converter function is not called at all. I&#39;d expect the converter to be called even in this case, with &quot;undefined&quot; data, so that I can influence the result even when the property chain is broken.

Playground example:
     http://tinyurl.com/96wm26o


[1] http://sourceforge.net/mailarchive/message.php?msg_id=29914299</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>30895</commentid>
            <who name="Marc Puts">marcputs</who>
            <bug_when>2012-10-05 12:13:48 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Dietrich also posted on the mailing list [1] with a different case in which he observed the same behaviour:

&gt;&gt;&gt;
I&#39;m observing the same misbehaviour (or bug).

I&#39;m trying to bind a nullable string property to a non nullable boolean 
property. In order to get this working I need the converter to be called 
if the value of the string property gets a null value, converting null 
to false.

As the converter is not called on null values this ends up in an 
exception with &quot;Null value is not allowed!&quot; for the binds target.

Dietrich
&lt;&lt;&lt;


[1] http://sourceforge.net/mailarchive/message.php?msg_id=29922695</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31767</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-18 15:48:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I checked the code and the sample (thanks for that btw.) and did see that it was somehow on intension that the textfield goes blank. The value has been reseted which means in the textfield, its empty. But you are still right, if the converter is available, it would be a good idea to call that converter to handle the case. I added exactly that to the single value binding. As soon as a converter is given, the converter is called and the returned value set. If no converter is given, the old behavior will still be used.

master: f405dcbb236173662e0f60f6d8cac68d20d78da6
2.1.x: ddfef5bbb16604109979ec2acbb338a43f8a4da5</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>