<bug>
          <bug_id>693</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2007-10-12 11:06:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Disposed Windows added to document hang around</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:23:12 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core</component>
          <version>0.7.2</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.7.4</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Sebastian Werner">info</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2474</commentid>
            <who name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</who>
            <bug_when>2007-10-12 11:06:00 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I recently hit an issue that required a top level window to be removed from the document prior to disposal.

We have a qx.ui.window.Window object which contains an editor. It has to have addToDocument called on it, otherwise the window doesn&#39;t appear.

After finishing editing dispose() is called on the Window (in a Timer.Once call). If the Window was maximised before being closed, the document still tried to resize it if the browser window was resized causing a JS error with getParent() null.

The document still had a reference to the Window in its children list and was trying to resize it even though __disposed was true.

I worked around the issue by removing the Window from the document. However, there are two issues:

1. There is qx.ui.core.Widget.addToDocument, but no removeFromDocument. It would make it easier to remove the window if one was added.

2. You should look at making removal from the document automatic for any widget that has been added to the document and then disposed of.

Hugh</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2612</commentid>
            <who name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</who>
            <bug_when>2007-12-20 09:58:42 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hello Hugh!

If you really want to remove the window widget completely, you have to remove it from the DOM first. You can use qx.ui.core.ClientDocument.getInstance().remove(window) or window.getParent().remove(window); After that you can call window.dispose().

You will seldom need to remove a window widget completely. Did you know that you can hide a window widget using window.close() and show it again by using window.show()?

We will probably add a removeFromDocument() method to the widget class. I will inform you on any news about this.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2621</commentid>
            <who name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</who>
            <bug_when>2007-12-20 15:50:29 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for your response.

Yes, I had to remove the window from the DOM completely before disposing. In this case we didn&#39;t want the window to hang around.

Having a removeFromDocument method would be great. Once you have that, it would be trivial to set a flag in addToDocument, and check the flag in destruct() to see if removeFromDocument should be called. removeFromDocument could also reset the flag.

This would be much neater and not leave nasty traps for the unwary and inexperienced, who wouldn&#39;t know why addToDocument was needed in the first place, and that removeFromDocument was needed before disposing. I&#39;m always in favour of code that looks after itself.

Hugh</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>3276</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2008-06-12 16:03:05 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>to sebastian</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>3960</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2008-07-17 16:10:16 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>move to 0.7.4</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>4461</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-08-19 17:37:02 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This is fixed with the destroy method of qx.ui.core.Widget in 0.8. A backport 
of this functionality is not possible easily and not planned.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37928</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:23:12 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>