<bug>
          <bug_id>695</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2007-10-14 19:26:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Tree element cannot be retrieved by pageX/pageY</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2007-10-17 15:28:28 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.tree</component>
          <version>0.7.3</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          <blocked>688</blocked>
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter>chase-r</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2477</commentid>
            <who name="">chase-r</who>
            <bug_when>2007-10-14 19:26:08 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>As I was working on extended drag&amp;drop behaviour with a feedback widget below the cursor, I submitted a patch (Bug #688) for the DragAndDropHandler. In short: if the handler detects that the drop target is the feedback widget, it tries to find the real target widget through 
qx.html.ElementFromPoint.getElementFromPoint(e.getPageX(), e.getPageY());

Now, this works just fine for &quot;simple&quot; structures, but when it comes to the qx.ui.tree.Tree, this method won&#39;t work. The getElementFromPoint() method always returns the tree&#39;s DIV element instead of the hovered tree element.

After hours of debugging, I found out why:

1) getElementFromPoint descends into the body&#39;s children and recursively calls itself for every child container that has pageX and pageY within it&#39;s bounds.  When no child matching the coordinates can be found, it will return the last found child.

2) The TreeFolder widget contains two child layouts, the first is a HorizontalBoxLayout  with indent, icon and label, the second one a VerticalBoxLayout containing all the folder&#39;s children (instances of AbstractTreeElement). The VerticalBoxLayout has no (or in numbers 0) height.

3) These two facts combined, getElementFromPoint cannot detect the VerticalBoxLayout of the Root-Folder as an element below pageX/pageY because it is invisible.

SOLUTION
Add the following statement into line 350 of qx.ui.tree.TreeFolder:

this._containerObject.setHeight(&quot;auto&quot;);


Fabio

PS: I added 688 to the &quot;blocked bugs&quot; as the detection of the real drop target fails for Trees.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2498</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2007-10-17 15:28:28 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed by r10600 (trunk) and r10601 (0.7)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>