<bug>
          <bug_id>6972</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-11-07 10:08:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>ZIndex issue with popup and menu button</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-07-01 14:59:58 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.popups</component>
          <version>2.0.2</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://tinyurl.com/d2dj4fb</bug_file_loc>
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>minor</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="saaj">id</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31250</commentid>
            <who name="saaj">id</who>
            <bug_when>2012-11-07 10:08:08 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>MenuButton put on a popup opens its menu with smaller zIndex which leads it to be positioned under popup.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31279</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2012-11-08 08:17:18 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report and the demo.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33125</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-06-27 16:06:49 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I think this is by design. I check how the zIndex is calculated for popup like widgets and found the following numbers.

windows have zIndex starting with 1e5
menus have zIndex starting with 1e6
popups have zIndex starting with 1e7

So there is a hierarchy designed in the code that a window is always below a menu and a menu is always below a popup.
I mark the bug as &#39;worksforme&#39; as this is by design and a restriction we can life with. As you already wrote in your sample code, it can be easily worked around and thats what I suggest to do.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33126</commentid>
            <who name="saaj">id</who>
            <bug_when>2013-06-27 17:29:23 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I can&#39;t agree this is something that can be called &quot;by design&quot;. The design doesn&#39;t expect all cases the can be produced with the API. In particular, a menu opened from a popup, which results in the flaw. In case of the example it is actually broken by design, so WORKSFORME is kind of strange resolution.

Leaving this as-is is unintuitive because legit API calls should not result in broken UI. So WONTFIX isn&#39;t a good idea as well (however better than WORKSFORME).

What I suggest is to turn it into enhancement where zIndex values will be calculated correctly during widget hierarchy construction (add, _add) or tuned at render phase or on appear, considering parent&#39;s value. So some day it could be universally correct and for now we can live with the workaround.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33134</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-06-28 08:13:52 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I agree that we would leave the bug open to give it a chance to get fixed later on.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40626</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-07-01 14:59:58 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year
or we don&#39;t think it will be fixed in the near future.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>