<bug>
          <bug_id>7073</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2012-12-03 18:57:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>qx.ui.mobile.container.MasterDetail broken?</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-12-04 17:58:30 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>mobile</component>
          <version>2.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Alexander Voronin">alexander.voronin</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Christopher Zuendorf">christopher.zuendorf</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Christopher Zuendorf">christopher.zuendorf</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31601</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Voronin">alexander.voronin</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-03 18:57:11 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>After switching from landscape back to portrait mode details container not hidden.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31602</commentid>
            <who name="Christopher Zuendorf">christopher.zuendorf</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-03 19:30:59 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Do you use git trunk? or current version 2.1?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31603</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Voronin">alexander.voronin</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-03 19:34:42 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; Do you use git trunk? or current version 2.1?

Using 2.1 from site download section.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31604</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Voronin">alexander.voronin</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-03 19:38:23 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Perhaps this can help. I&#39;m adding container into page that added in manager as detail page. Just avoiding higher level master/detail page separation with page manager.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31611</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Voronin">alexander.voronin</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-04 11:38:57 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Could you please confirm bug or reject it if I misunderstood container behaviour? It&#39;s important for me to continue development process. Thanks in advance.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31612</commentid>
            <who name="Christopher Zuendorf">christopher.zuendorf</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-04 11:49:11 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I can not detect a bug on MasterDetail logic.

Can you please check the following manual page, and cross-check whether it differs from that behaviour?

http://manual.qooxdoo.org/2.1/pages/mobile/mobile_tablet_switch.html

The detail container should always be shown, according to the manual. The Master is the page to control application flow. It contains some kind of application overview menu, from which you can switch between several detail pages.

&quot;Master&quot; does not mean, that the page is always visible on screen. &quot;Master&quot; is more to say, that it handles the application&#39;s page flow.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31613</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Voronin">alexander.voronin</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-04 12:06:06 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Is qx.ui.mobile.container.MasterDetail behaviour depends on qx.ui.mobile.page.Manager settings? 

(In reply to comment #5)
&gt; I can not detect a bug on MasterDetail logic.
&gt; 
&gt; Can you please check the following manual page, and cross-check whether it
&gt; differs from that behaviour?
&gt; 
&gt; http://manual.qooxdoo.org/2.1/pages/mobile/mobile_tablet_switch.html
&gt; 
It&#39;s describes manager behaviour and it&#39;s working as expected. Im talking about container qx.ui.mobile.container.MasterDetail here.

&gt; The detail container should always be shown, according to the manual. The
&gt; Master is the page to control application flow. It contains some kind of
&gt; application overview menu, from which you can switch between several detail
&gt; pages.
&gt; 
&gt; &quot;Master&quot; does not mean, that the page is always visible on screen. &quot;Master&quot; is
&gt; more to say, that it handles the application&#39;s page flow.

IC, that&#39;s my mistake. I mean both containers left visible. Scenario is following:

- create qx.ui.mobile.page.Manager(false)
- create page (based on qx.ui.mobile.page.NavigationPage) with qx.ui.mobile.container.MasterDetail container
- add page to manager as details page
- run
- first page view in portrait mode (only details widget visible - ok)
- rotate device to landscape mode (both widgets visible - ok)
- rotate back to portrait mode (still both widgets visible - not ok on my mind)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31614</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Voronin">alexander.voronin</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-04 12:37:49 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Here is example of page that i&#39;m testing on http://pastebin.com/y8FTYucW</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31616</commentid>
            <who name="Christopher Zuendorf">christopher.zuendorf</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-04 13:55:34 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I think that you use MasterDetail Container in a wrong context.

It is not intended to be container inside a NavigationPage. It is intended to be added to application root, as Page Manager does.
If you want to use it completely on your own way, then add it to applicaton root, too:

qx.core.Init.getApplication().getRoot()

Please tell me what you are trying to reach. I think there are different solutions for you problems.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31617</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Voronin">alexander.voronin</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-04 14:37:13 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #8)
&gt; I think that you use MasterDetail Container in a wrong context.
&gt; 
&gt; It is not intended to be container inside a NavigationPage. It is intended to
&gt; be added to application root, as Page Manager does.
&gt; If you want to use it completely on your own way, then add it to applicaton
&gt; root, too:
&gt; 
&gt; qx.core.Init.getApplication().getRoot()
&gt; 
&gt; Please tell me what you are trying to reach. I think there are different
&gt; solutions for you problems.

Argh, that&#39;s what i&#39;ve expected. You see, i do not need completely master/detail page based UI. But I would like to use some of it&#39;s features, such as NavigationPage basis with &quot;back&quot; functionality. I need only one page with master/detail container. So I found qx.ui.mobile.container.MasterDetail and just added it as page content. It&#39;s almost working as I thought.. :)

Ok, sorry for trouble You. Also based on this I&#39;d like to propose additional layout for such kind of issues - something like qx.ui.mobile.layout.MasterDetail maybe? It could be usefull I guess. For now Im going to write something by myself using &quot;layoutChange&quot; event handling.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31618</commentid>
            <who name="Christopher Zuendorf">christopher.zuendorf</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-04 15:54:28 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>So I close this bug.

I would expect, that you can reach a lot by extending the MasterDetail Logic. It is not that difficult at all. Just two states where you order the page differently. 
The page manager has a lot more the application specific content inside.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31619</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Voronin">alexander.voronin</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-04 16:07:35 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #10)
&gt; So I close this bug.
Sure.

&gt; I would expect, that you can reach a lot by extending the MasterDetail Logic.
&gt; It is not that difficult at all. Just two states where you order the page
&gt; differently. 
&gt; The page manager has a lot more the application specific content inside.

The problem with MasterDetail logic is that I can&#39;t avoid showing both content pages in landscape mode on demand - it&#39;s always shows both main and detail parts even when i hide() master part. But I need to show just one page all the time at any device orientation except just one case. That&#39;s why Im not using it. Thanx for Your time.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31620</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Voronin">alexander.voronin</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-04 16:11:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>And one more thing. It&#39;s not clear for me why I can use qx.ui.mobile.container.Composite container to arrange elements on page and can not use qx.ui.mobile.container.MasterDetail for the same purpose. Perhaps you could separate this stuff in different namespaces or throw exception if user adds this container in wrong place.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31626</commentid>
            <who name="Christopher Zuendorf">christopher.zuendorf</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-04 16:59:39 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hm,

have a look at the latest implementation of qooxdoo Mobile...

http://demo.qooxdoo.org/devel/mobileshowcase/index.html#%2F

There you can hide the master on Landscape mode, if you want to. Does this help?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>31629</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Voronin">alexander.voronin</who>
            <bug_when>2012-12-04 17:58:30 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #13)
&gt; Hm,
&gt; 
&gt; have a look at the latest implementation of qooxdoo Mobile...
&gt; 
&gt; http://demo.qooxdoo.org/devel/mobileshowcase/index.html#%2F
&gt; 
&gt; There you can hide the master on Landscape mode, if you want to. Does this
&gt; help?

Im understanding qx.ui.mobile.page.Manager logic. But such application structure is not suitable for my case. I&#39;m having set of separate pages with self navigation logic and just one of this pages uses MasterDetail logic. I do not like to have show/hide button and kind of dropdown menu at each page. Thanx.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>