<bug>
          <bug_id>716</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2007-10-31 15:20:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Inconsistent table cells click event behavior with Firefox</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:23:22 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.table</component>
          <version>0.7.2</version>
          <rep_platform>Firefox 2.0</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.7.3</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Emil Prichici">eprichic</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Firefox</cf_browser>
          <cf_browser_version>2</cf_browser_version>

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2539</commentid>
            <who name="Emil Prichici">eprichic</who>
            <bug_when>2007-10-31 15:20:48 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I have a table that has the showSetFocusIndicator property set to true. When I click in any cell, except the focused cell, the click event doesn’t get dispatched; there is a mouse down and up but no click. If the table showSetFocusIndicator property is set to false the click event get dispatched. I added some debug statements in qx.event.handler.EventHandler._onmouseevent to get this confirmation.

As result, for the first case, a cell click listener will get the cell click event only if one clicks in the focused cell. So, to handle a click event in a table cell one has to click once to set the focus on the cell and than to click again to get the click event.
Another aspect of this click behavior is that embedded html links doesn’t work with Firefox and tables that have the showSetFocusIndicator property set to true.

In my opinion the cause of the problem is the qx.ui.table.pane.Scroller._focusIndicator. When this widget is set to visible a click event is dispatched only if the click is located in the focused cell as opposed to when the widget is not visible when every mouse click gets dispatched.

It looks like when visible this _focusIndicator acts like a screen that stops the click event from being dispatched.
I think that a table cell embedded html link is handled directly by the browser. If the _focusIndicator is not visible Firefox handles properly the links; the moment the _focusIndicator is made visible Firefox doesn’t react anymore to these links like it doesn’t get the click event.

I tried a “quick and dirty” fix; to hide the _focusIndicator on mouse down and show it again on click. In this case I do see a click event for each unfocused cell but not for the focused cell. The proper way to solve this problem is to figure out why that widget stops the click event to reach the browser.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2643</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2008-01-10 15:32:19 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>to me</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2671</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-01-11 11:04:07 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Corrected target.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2681</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2008-01-11 11:32:10 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>fixed.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37992</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:23:22 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>