<bug>
          <bug_id>7188</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2013-02-01 15:12:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Provide a simple way to mock HTTP backends</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:21:13 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.dev</component>
          <version>2.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>3.0</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          <cc>derrell.lipman</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>32083</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2013-02-01 15:12:46 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>For development and testing of RESTful applications it would be nice to have a convenient way to define a client-side mock backend that gives predefined responses to XmlHttp requests. SinonJS already provides the necessary infrastructure (FakeXMLHttpRequest and FakeServer).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>32084</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2013-02-01 15:42:31 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>You might take a look at LIBERATED, which provides a methodology for web-based client-server application development, in which a simulated server is built into the browser environment to run the backend code. This allows the frontend code to issue requests to the backend in either a synchronous or asynchronous fashion, step, using a debugger, directly from frontend code into backend code, and to completely test both the frontend and backend portions. That exact same backend code, now fully tested in the simulated environment, can then be moved, unaltered, to a real server. 

LIBERATED currently provides a built-in JSON-RPC server that operates in the simulated and/or &quot;real&quot; environment. LIBERATED is a qooxdoo library. It would not be difficult to add a server for RESTful applications. The architecture intends such additions.

http://www.cs.uml.edu/~dlipman/thesis-liberated.pdf 

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>32195</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2013-02-08 14:31:18 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>LIBERATED certainly looks interesting, Derrell. In fact, Thomas and I were talking about it just last week. Still, we decided to got with the simple approach of just creating a thin convenience wrapper around SinonJS&#39;s FakeServer.

Fixed with 2231d27b9df459fda657167a4cc81fce9ab31d3b (master).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37200</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:21:13 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>