<bug>
          <bug_id>7213</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2013-02-07 12:12:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Generator IPC: Provide an Inter-Process Communication Interface</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:46:51 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>tool.generator</component>
          <version>2.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>32175</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2013-02-07 12:12:51 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The issue is to offload Generator functionality to modules living in another 
process, pot. written in a foreign lanuage.

So this bug is about generic interfaces (like defining a textual protocol over 
sockets), and the infrastructure in the core Generator to make use of them.

This would allow to break up Generator functionality, experiment with different 
implementations, and provide functionality in foreign programming languages. 
The core Generator would be more of a &#39;glue&#39; for the external parts.

This could also be leveraged for parallelism (e.g. many slave processes 
compiling class files). A first attempt in this regard has been made with 
bug#2366 (using Pyro), parallelizing multiple Generator processes. This bug 
goes beyond it, as it doesn&#39;t rely on a Generator process on the other side.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>32177</commentid>
            <who name="Thomas Herchenroeder">thron7</who>
            <bug_when>2013-02-07 12:51:21 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Serialized AST Format:

A central point of this bug would be defining and implementing a textual 
serialized format for our syntax trees. Many core activities of the Generator 
revolve around ASTs (producing them, consuming them), like parsing, 
compressing, optimizations, dependency analysis, etc. A serialization format 
would allow to pass ASTs from and to foreign modules, allowing modules in 
totally different languages work with each other. 

The format should be textual, as it is easiest to parse and produce in any 
given language or runtime. My current idea is an S-expression syntax where each 
expression defines a node with possible subnodes, as

  (&lt;node-type&gt; (&lt;attributes&gt;) (&lt;child-nodes&gt;))

So the AST for the program &quot;var a = 3 + 4;&quot; would be

  (var ( (line 1) (column 1) (value &quot;var&quot;))
    ( (definition ( (line 1) (column 5) )
        ( (assignment ( (line 1) (column 5) (operator &quot;ASSIGN&quot;) (value &quot;=&quot;))
            ( (identifier ((line 1) (column 5) (value &quot;a&quot;)) ())
              (operation ( (line 1) (column 11) (operator &quot;ADD&quot;) (value &quot;+&quot;))
                ( (constant ((line 1) (column 9) (constantType &quot;number&quot;) 
(detail &quot;int&quot;) (value &quot;3&quot;)) ())
                  (constant ((line 1) (column 9) (constantType &quot;number&quot;) 
(detail &quot;int&quot;) (value &quot;4&quot;)) ())
                ))))))))


An additional concern here are scopes:

Currently, scope information is maintained along with the AST, as a &quot;shadow 
tree&quot; of scope nodes that are linked to the corresponding AST nodes. This 
linking is via references in code, but you wouldn&#39;t want to embed a scope 
definition with e.g. every var in the AST that belongs to it (too much 
repetition). The solution would be to use labels as references, so e.g. many 
vars can refer to the same scope they belong to using the same label:

  defining a scope (e.g. for a function definition) is reflected in an 
attribute of this node like:

     (scope (new #4711AC)         // &lt;--- unique label within tree
                 (parent #4712AB)     // &lt;--- reference to parent scope, global 
scope gets label #global)
     )

  referencing a scope (e.g. for a scoped variable) is reflected in the same 
attribute, with additional properties:

     (scope (parent #4711AC)
                 (kind  &quot;decl&quot;)             // &lt;--- the other being &quot;use&quot;, for 
use locations
     )

A tree walker could assign the labels to the scope nodes before serializing the 
AST.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35687</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:46:51 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>