<bug>
          <bug_id>7319</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2013-03-25 18:21:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>iOS: Native scrolling via -webkit-overflow-scrolling: touch; CSS slows down if Touch handler was loaded</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 09:37:59 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.event</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Mustafa Sak">mustafa.sak</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>32519</commentid>
            <who name="Mustafa Sak">mustafa.sak</who>
            <bug_when>2013-03-25 18:21:00 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Using native scrolling for div&#39;s of iOS is more scale-able. 
The performance is very fast. But our touch event handler slows it down. 

Point on a scrollable div and scroll up and down. In a profiler you can see a massive call of event dispatcher. This seems to decrease the acceleration. Because if you disable touch event handler manually, scrolling runs perfectly, even with a huge amount on child elements in the scroll container.


We should try to find a generic way to prevent firing touch-move events on scrolling natively.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>32521</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-03-26 08:03:48 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #0)
&gt; We should try to find a generic way to prevent firing touch-move events on
&gt; scrolling natively.

As there is no build in support for native touch scrolling, I can&#39;t think of a generic solution to that as far as I understand the idea. Could you be a bit mor precise about how you think that could work?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36192</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 09:37:59 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year or we don&#39;t think it will be fixed in the near future.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>