<bug>
          <bug_id>7378</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2013-05-02 10:16:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Layout not recalculating correctly when items are added later on</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2013-10-07 08:13:47 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.layout</component>
          <version>2.1.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>3.0.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Raphael Schweikert">raphael.schweikert</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>32667</commentid>
            <who name="Raphael Schweikert">raphael.schweikert</who>
            <bug_when>2013-05-02 10:16:06 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I’m sorry for being able to come up with a more succinct headline but I can’t seem to really pinpoint this bug.

I was having this strange trouble with my custom (albeit simple) layout manager. The item I added to the qx.ui.container.Composite was given the right size but any item I added to that inner Composite would either not be visible at all or (in some cases) be much too small and not respect the layout constraints I had given.

I was sure that there was something wrong with my layout manager. I have been able to reduce my test case somewhat and then send it off to the Qooxdoo mailing list. However, I have not received a single response in almost a week so I’m starting to think that there isn’t a big obvious problem with my code.

I have since simplified the test case further: http://tinyurl.com/ctfws83. I am using the `current` version of the playground here but the `2.1.1` version shows the exact same symptoms.

Several things to note:

• The grey panels are the Composites managed by either a basic layout (top) or my custom layout (bottom).
• The select boxes are added asynchronously (using setTimeout). Changing the code to run synchronously fixes my problem but is impossible in my case.
• Sometimes, after a few retries, the select box will appear in the bottom box as well but will have the wrong position and is not clickable (it‘s also missing an arrow).
• Changing the select box to a qx.ui.basic.Label will seem to work better (the item is displayed at least) but the root problem of it not having the correct layout properties persists.
• Asynchronously setting the contents of myContainer and basicContainer isn’t a problem, just asynchronously setting the contents of their content is a problem.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>32680</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-05-03 08:22:16 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report. Took a quick look at it and could not see the root of the issue right away.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33794</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-08-30 13:25:11 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I checked the code and found the root of the problem. It is in the _computeSizeHint method of your custom layout. It always returns the same values not depending on its children. If the size hint stays the same, no changes has been detected and the rendering will be skipped. So either you return at least one calculated value for the size hint or you invalidate the layout cache [1] on the child before rendering.

[1] child.invalidateLayoutCache();</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33798</commentid>
            <who name="Raphael Schweikert">raphael.schweikert</who>
            <bug_when>2013-08-30 14:01:11 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>All right. Thanks a lot for checking this out for me.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>