<bug>
          <bug_id>743</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2007-12-11 12:53:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>POST-Requests not properly working in qx.io.remote.XmlHttpTransport</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2007-12-13 08:26:12 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.io</component>
          <version>0.7.2</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>INVALID</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>major</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="David Werner">david.werner</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2589</commentid>
            <who name="David Werner">david.werner</who>
            <bug_when>2007-12-11 12:53:19 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I  stumbled across this bug, because the server responds with HTTP 414 (Request-URI Too Long) for a special POST request with many, many parameters. 

This happens because the parameters are appended to the request&#39;s URL in qx.io.remote.XmlHttpTransport . And they are not included in the request&#39;s body, too!

Seems to be the same in branch &quot;legacy_0_7_x&quot;.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2591</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2007-12-12 15:04:16 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>This has been a topic of discussion in the past.  It&#39;s deemed not a bug; rather a feature.  Some people like to send parameters in a POST request as if it were a GET, in addition to the form fields typically used in a POST request.  If you use request.setParameter() then the parameter will be sent as part of the URL.  If you use setFormField() then it will be sent in the body.

The whole Request interface could really use a facelift (or possibly even reconstructive surgery) but for now, that&#39;s the way you make the distinction.

Cheers,

Derrell
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2592</commentid>
            <who name="David Werner">david.werner</who>
            <bug_when>2007-12-12 15:46:45 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext> (In reply to comment #1)
&gt;  It&#39;s deemed not a bug; rather a feature.  Some people like to send parameters in a 
&gt; POST request as if it were a GET, 

Nevertheless, it should not be the default behavior I think ... ;-)
It&#39;s a bit strange to send parameters via URL if you want to use the POST method.

&gt; in addition to the form fields typically used in a POST request. 

But they are not additionally sent in the body. So, is it a bug after all?
Else you could use the GET method in the first place.

&gt; If you use setFormField() then it will be sent in the body.

Ah, thanks! :-)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2593</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2007-12-12 16:47:31 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>If you search the archives, you&#39;ll find a thread discussing this.  In short, there were those who wanted to issue a POST with form data while also sending *different* data in the URL as parameters, a la GET.  I agree it seems strange, but that was the decision.  Just use the two different interfaces for the two different purposes -- setParameter() to add it to the URL and setFormField() to add it to the body -- and you should be all set.

Cheers,

Derrell
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2594</commentid>
            <who name="David Werner">david.werner</who>
            <bug_when>2007-12-13 08:26:12 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #3)
&gt; In short, there were those who wanted to issue a POST with form data while also 
&gt; sending *different* data in the URL as parameters, a la GET.  

I see! Sorry for the misunderstanding. ;-)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>