<bug>
          <bug_id>7457</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2013-06-13 20:21:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Add Ability to Theme for Readonly Controls</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2013-07-29 08:22:07 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.theming</component>
          <version>2.1.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WORKSFORME</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>3.0</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Aaron Opfer">me</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          <cc>dietrich.streifert</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>32939</commentid>
            <who name="Aaron Opfer">me</who>
            <bug_when>2013-06-13 20:21:17 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>We have a form that has several read-only and editable elements. We have a usability problem where the read-only fields look exactly like the other nearby editable fields and are not distinguishable until one attempts to edit the content and fails.

We could use disabled state, however, the disabled state is used elsewhere in the application to denote forms that need data that has not been loaded yet, or forms that cannot be utilized until a prior step is first completed. We feel that by using the disabled state on these read-only elements would only create more confusion by implying that more data is loading or that the data is unimportant in some way.

The ideal solution for us would be to have an additional state for theming elements that are marked readonly.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>32941</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-06-14 08:43:43 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report. Adding a separate state should not be much and as you made your use case clear, I think its worth adding it event out themes do not need use it.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>32943</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2013-06-14 10:35:43 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>@Aaron:

Please read this thread regarding related to this bug:

http://qooxdoo.678.n2.nabble.com/CheckBox-fields-and-readOnly-td7196506.html

Unfortunately the core team closed the bug because the use case is missing.

See also bug http://bugzilla.qooxdoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=6051</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33013</commentid>
            <who name="Aaron Opfer">me</who>
            <bug_when>2013-06-19 17:57:24 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #2)
&gt; @Aaron:
&gt; 
&gt; Please read this thread regarding related to this bug:
&gt; 
&gt; http://qooxdoo.678.n2.nabble.com/CheckBox-fields-and-readOnly-td7196506.html
&gt; 
&gt; Unfortunately the core team closed the bug because the use case is missing.
&gt; 
&gt; See also bug http://bugzilla.qooxdoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=6051

From my comprehension of that bug description, it was specifically regarding adding readonly state to checkboxes. That isn&#39;t quite what I am looking for.

My issue pertains to readOnly state on text entry areas. When particular users do not have permission to change certain fields, we would still like the user to be able to copy text from them, thus readOnly state works great for this. However, the user&#39;s lack of permission to change the field is not communicated clearly until the user attempts to make changes and becomes frustrated at the lack of response until the user gives up or figures out what is going on. It doesn&#39;t help that they&#39;re typically in a form of ~10 other text fields, all typically editable.

However, if we had the ability to apply a style to readonly text fields, such as a lighter border and/or background, it would tell the user at a glance that the field is different than the other fields, yet not disabled like other fields.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33143</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-06-28 13:53:29 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Just wanted to add the state bug did see that there is already exactly the same thing I wanted to add. :D
Just use the state &quot;readonly&quot;.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>