<bug>
          <bug_id>7503</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2013-07-02 08:57:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Application swipe-able up and down on iOS</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2013-08-26 09:13:27 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.core</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>iOS</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>3.0</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33184</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2013-07-02 08:57:02 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Since the new mouse emulation code or since the diet merge to master, on iOS the background reacts on swipe gestures moving the whole app content, additionally the corresponding events seem to be captured so that swipes over eg. the table pane are not usable anymore because there is allways an additional movement of the entire application.

Reproducible on iOS 6.1.3 (iPad3) when comparing the two table demos of version 2.1 and devel:

1. Try to swipe over the app background moving up and down with the 2.1 demo:

http://demo.qooxdoo.org/2.1/demobrowser/demo/table/Table.html?qxenv:qx.theme:qx.theme.Indigo

the app does not move and the table content scrolls if you swipe up/down in the table pane.


2. Try to swipe over the app background on the current devel demo:

http://demo.qooxdoo.org/devel/demobrowser/demo/table/Table.html?qxenv:qx.theme:qx.theme.Indigo

the app moves up and down. There is nearly no chance to scroll the table content through swipes.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33226</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-07-05 11:00:55 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This is kind of intension. With the introduction of emulate mouse, we removed all &quot;half backed&quot; touch support of the framework and replaced it with the mouse emulation layer. This means we removed the default touch scrolling of scroll areas. As the mouse emulation is a feature which needs to be enabled, the default behavior is not touch ready. Nevertheless, if you check out the widget browser in devel, you should see how it feels with the emulate mouse enabled and all the scrolling should be fine.
I am still not 100% sure if we can switch on the mouse emulation without breaking anything so we chose the save path for desktop apps and disable the mouse emulation by default and make the user enable it.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33233</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2013-07-05 11:25:56 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>But wouldn&#39;t it be good to have the old behaviour when &quot;qx.emulatemouse&quot; is set to false?

Otherwise users will complain that applications updated and build with default qooxdoo 3 are not usable anymore on iPad.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33235</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2013-07-05 12:19:11 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&#39;ve just tested my app with the following settings in config.json and a fresh build:

  &quot;jobs&quot; :
  {
    &quot;common&quot; :
    {
      &quot;environment&quot; :
      {
        &quot;qx.nativeScrollBars&quot; : true,
        &quot;qx.dynlocale&quot; : false,
        &quot;qx.dyntheme&quot; : false,
        &quot;qx.debug&quot; : false,
        &quot;qx.aspects&quot; : false,
        &quot;qx.emulatemouse&quot; : true
      }
    },


I&#39;m still able to swipe the complete app up and down:

    http://cpr2.visionet-world.de

This is the pre diet app showing the desired behaviour:

    http://db.reanimationsregister.de</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33262</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-07-08 15:20:55 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>You are right. Seems to be a regression because that once worked as expected. I committed a fix with 3382a38ec0d76f9471326a8fdc83a8bb27818103</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33268</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2013-07-09 09:25:42 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Martin,

yes the app swipe is gone, but now tapping on a textfield does not focus the field and thus does not show the virtual keyboard IF the app is build with qx.emulatemouse true.

If I use a build with qx.emulatemouse set to false, the app is swipeable again but I&#39;m again able to set the focus to textfields and the keyboard shows up as expected.

I don&#39;t know if this is related to this bug or if this is some other problem, but I&#39;m reopening the bug so it raises again up.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33276</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2013-07-09 11:09:22 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #2)
&gt; But wouldn&#39;t it be good to have the old behaviour when &quot;qx.emulatemouse&quot; is set
&gt; to false?
&gt; 
&gt; Otherwise users will complain that applications updated and build with default
&gt; qooxdoo 3 are not usable anymore on iPad.

Still the above ist true. Please consider changing the desktop to be NOT swipable, regardless wether qx.emulatemouse is set true or false.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33281</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-07-09 11:55:34 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I opened up a separate bug for that: #7521</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33283</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-07-09 12:32:50 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #6)
&gt; (In reply to comment #2)
&gt; &gt; But wouldn&#39;t it be good to have the old behaviour when &quot;qx.emulatemouse&quot; is set
&gt; &gt; to false?
&gt; &gt; 
&gt; &gt; Otherwise users will complain that applications updated and build with default
&gt; &gt; qooxdoo 3 are not usable anymore on iPad.
&gt; 
&gt; Still the above ist true. Please consider changing the desktop to be NOT
&gt; swipable, regardless wether qx.emulatemouse is set true or false.


As this is a major release we have the opportunity to change things like this. I don&#39;t want to have the same functionality in the framework twice so we decided to replace it with the mouse emulation which is far more sophisticated but needs to be enabled. I guess thats a fair trade. ;)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>