<bug>
          <bug_id>7624</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2013-08-05 11:29:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>password field doesn&#39;t work on Android 2.1</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:25:10 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>mobile.widget</component>
          <version>3.0</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>3.5</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Wayne">w.si</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Christopher Zuendorf">christopher.zuendorf</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Christopher Zuendorf">christopher.zuendorf</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33540</commentid>
            <who name="Wayne">w.si</who>
            <bug_when>2013-08-05 11:29:47 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I have a stone-age HTC Hero, running on Android 2.1 + WebKit 3.1. Tapping on password field on that machine in the built-in browser (doesn&#39;t support Chrome) doesn&#39;t bring up the soft keyboard although tapping on textfield does.

BTW tapping on the textfield doesn&#39;t clean up the placeholder text.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33544</commentid>
            <who name="Christopher Zuendorf">christopher.zuendorf</who>
            <bug_when>2013-08-05 11:46:23 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>There are several issues with HTML password fields on Android 2.1 . 

One of them was the &quot;Duplicated TextField&quot; effect which we fixed in 3.0 :
https://code.google.com/p/android/issues/detail?id=30964


We tested the passwordField on many devices and as far as I know it works quite ok, but not perfect.

Some things are not fixable from the website context.

It might by possible that you have to tap twice on the passwordField. Could you try that?


Could you provide a playground example for the problem you mentioned about the placeholder text?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33545</commentid>
            <who name="Wayne">w.si</who>
            <bug_when>2013-08-05 11:54:36 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi, thanks again for your quick feedback. The double-tap doesn&#39;t work, at least on that device. It just simply zoomed in the page. The placeholder text issue can also be reproduced via http://demo.qooxdoo.org/current/mobileshowcase/index.html#%2Fform.

I understand any device still running Android 2 may be of too low spec to run qx.mobile apps. So I&#39;m happy if you say you won&#39;t fix the bug. I just reported it in case there is any easy fix.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>33546</commentid>
            <who name="Christopher Zuendorf">christopher.zuendorf</who>
            <bug_when>2013-08-05 12:58:59 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>qx.Mobile apps work quite well on Android 2. But this PasswordField bug is one thing which occurs again and again. 

We tested it on Google Nexus S, HTC Desire and LG Optimus Black. On these devices everything was fine.

The good thing: many Android 2 devices can be upgraded to Android 4. For example the Nexus S or the Optimus Black, too.

Thank you for reporting this bug. There are too many devices out there for testing them all, and every bug report helps us improving our framework.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>38651</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:25:10 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>