<bug>
          <bug_id>773</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-01-25 12:14:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>row height in a table</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2008-09-03 01:16:25 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.table</component>
          <version>0.7.3</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="cyrille rigault">cyrille.rigault</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>cyrille.rigault</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2803</commentid>
            <who name="cyrille rigault">cyrille.rigault</who>
            <bug_when>2008-01-25 12:14:21 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I would like to display images (thumbnails) in a table in a specific column.
Depending on the row, the number of images to display is different (I will have my own renderer, as the Image renderer only displays one image).
The problem is that:
1) the row height is fixed, and not dependent on the data displayed (static vs dynamic)
2) the row height is the same for all rows. If I want to display 5 images in a row, it will take 5*32=160 pixels height for instance, and if for the others, there is only one image (32 pixels here), each row will have 160 pixels height.

=&gt; is there a solution to have dynamic row height per row ?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2805</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2008-01-25 14:31:44 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>The answer to your question is, &quot;not yet.&quot;  I have begun work on variable row height.  As soon as it is in a usable state, I&#39;ll make an announcement on the list.  I&#39;m hoping to have time to work on that starting in a week or so.  It&#39;s a non-trivial problem so I expect it to take a few weeks to get it working properly.  Hopefully within a month or so you should hear of availability for a *testing* version of this, and it will then, I expect, be released officially with a future 0.7.x version or 0.8.

Derrell
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5006</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-02 23:11:07 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Derrell seems to have given up one this topic for the moment.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5021</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-03 01:16:25 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>&gt; Derrell seems to have given up one this topic for the moment.

Well I didn&#39;t give up on it, I implemented a new widget that supports it.

The Table widget does not lend itself to variable row heights.  Instead, I implemented the Progressive widget which has a Table component that supports variable row height.  When variable row height is a requirement, Progressive&#39;s Table is the way to go.

Derrell
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>