<bug>
          <bug_id>7802</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2013-10-18 11:18:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Splitpane adds widgets in a confusing way</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-11-18 09:16:32 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.panes</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Mustafa Sak">mustafa.sak</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>alexander.steitz</cc>
    
    <cc>andreas.parusel</cc>
    
    <cc>daniel.wagner</cc>
    
    <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>34101</commentid>
            <who name="Mustafa Sak">mustafa.sak</who>
            <bug_when>2013-10-18 11:18:48 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>You can add more than two widgets to the split pane, the pane cares only about children of index 2 and 3 but the layout determines the widget in index 2 as first widget and the absolute last added widget as second. This causes in a problem: 
e.g. The pane will care about widget 2 and 3 but the layout is rendering 2 and 4 (if added three widgets)

as can be seen here http://tinyurl.com/psq4opw


I would expect the pane has always two widgets, a call of add() causes in a rotation of widgets from right to left respectively bottom to top.

Further more I would love to be able to set widgets on a given position first (left/top) and second (right/bottom)

We can use protected _addAt() method but an public one would be helpfull especially because the offset for widgets is 2 (child control splitter and slider are previously added)

as can be seen here http://tinyurl.com/oajq6on</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>34119</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2013-10-22 13:55:12 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>From my point of view this bug can be split up into two.

1. Make sure the &quot;add&quot; method is causing a exception in debug mode whenever more than two widgets are added.

2. Provide a API to easily add a widget at a defined position, e.g. removing the left widget and adding a new widget at this left position with one API call.


I guess this would be easier to understand and it won&#39;t be necessary to add some magic concerning the rotating of the widgets.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>34131</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-10-24 08:05:12 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #2)
&gt; From my point of view this bug can be split up into two.
&gt; 
&gt; 1. Make sure the &quot;add&quot; method is causing a exception in debug mode whenever
&gt; more than two widgets are added.
&gt; 
&gt; 2. Provide a API to easily add a widget at a defined position, e.g. removing
&gt; the left widget and adding a new widget at this left position with one API
&gt; call.
&gt; 
&gt; 
&gt; I guess this would be easier to understand and it won&#39;t be necessary to add
&gt; some magic concerning the rotating of the widgets.

+1</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>41615</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-11-18 09:16:32 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>