<bug>
          <bug_id>7827</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2013-10-30 08:50:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>dynamic decorators do not work</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-11-18 09:16:30 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core</component>
          <version>3.0</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="cyrille rigault">cyrillerigault</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>34175</commentid>
            <who name="cyrille rigault">cyrillerigault</who>
            <bug_when>2013-10-30 08:50:19 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I am porting my application from Qooxdoo 2.1 to 3.0 and I discovered some problems concerning decorators. I spent some time understanding why it doesn&#39;t work and found some issues.

My application uses dynamic decorators, in the sense that users may change borders of objects using an interface. One decorator is used per object. When this happens, I tried two strategies:

1) first strategy - dispose the old decorator then assign a new one (as I did in 2.1)
If the decorator is disposed before assigning the new one to the component, the component _applyDecorator() method calls getCssClassName() on a disposed object, which returns qx-undefined, and the old decorator class is not removed from the component. =&gt; decoration is not pro
perly applied to the widget.

2) second strategy - dispose an old decorator after assigning a new one
In qooxdoo 3.0, the decorator class is removed from the HTML component, but not from the style sheet.
As object hashes are re-used from disposed objects, a new decorator may use a hash from a disposed decorator.
When so, the new decorator will have the same css classname as the disposed one, and when Widget._applyDecorator() calls qx.theme.manager.Decoration.addCssClass(), the new decorator properties will not be applied, as they already exist in the style sheet for this hash.
So, the new decorator properties will not be applied !


If I do not dispose Decorators, it works fine, but I may have hundreds of unused objects in my application.


Here is how I temporarily? solved the problem:
- I use a subclassed version of qx.ui.decoration.Decorator, that only defines a destructor which:
. gets the css selector of the decorator to dispose
. removes the css selector from the style sheet
destruct : function() {
    var selector = &quot;.&quot;+qx.theme.manager.Decoration.getInstance().getCssClassName(this);
    qx.ui.style.Stylesheet.getInstance().removeRule( selector);
  }
- I only dispose an old decorator after assigning the new one to the widget (another option is to use resetDecorator()).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>34198</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-11-04 11:24:48 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report. Your suggested fix sounds reasonable and could be added. Are you interested in taking care of that yourself? If so, just file a pull request and I&#39;ll pull it in.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>41607</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-11-18 09:16:30 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>