<bug>
          <bug_id>7837</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2013-10-31 16:11:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Grow layout icw column width and padding doesn&#39;t allow column width zero</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 09:57:38 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.layout</component>
          <version>3.0.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Jeroen">Jeroen.Smit</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>34189</commentid>
            <who name="Jeroen">Jeroen.Smit</who>
            <bug_when>2013-10-31 16:11:53 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>In version 1.4.1. I was showing a control with a buttonbar on the right that would become “visible” when the mouse got close and was hidden when the mouse moved away. In 3.0.1 I am not able to use the same code because the column in which I added the buttons is not hidden completely anymore.

I made a playground example showing the issue: http://tinyurl.com/ojwbpvm

In short, the issue is that the column I want to hide by setting the width to zero doesn’t get a width of zero when I also apply padding to the control containing the grid layout.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>34194</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-11-04 10:46:31 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report. Thinking about the situation make it clear whats happening. The is a change which came up with the diet initiative we did for the 3.0 release. The code still works the same way it did pre diet but the content is visible now because we don&#39;t have an inner content div to hide the elements in the padding area. Here is why: We render all the children with position: absolute in the container. So the padding we use in only a logic input number for the JavaScript layout calculation which means, adding a padding-right subtracts the padding from the width and thats it. So in your case, the right column get rendered with a width of 0 pixel at the starting position of -5px from the right corner (right padding). The button gets rendered as usual starting at the mentioned position which makes it visible in the padding area. Pre 3.0, the padding was the offset between the container and content div and the content div had a overflow: hidden so everything rendered outside the padding area has been invisible.

Now that we know the problem, I&#39;m not sure if we can fix that issue. :( I would suggest a workaround in your code by additionally hiding the button.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>34203</commentid>
            <who name="Jeroen">Jeroen.Smit</who>
            <bug_when>2013-11-04 12:09:46 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I reversed applying the padding in my code: removed it from the control and added it to the buttons within the extra column. Visually the same as before.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>34209</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2013-11-05 08:15:34 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Sounds good.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36214</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 09:57:38 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year or we don&#39;t think it will be fixed in the near future.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>