<bug>
          <bug_id>801</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-03-06 16:21:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Layout problem with resizable table / treevirtual</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:23:03 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.tree</component>
          <version>0.7.3</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>DUPLICATE</resolution>
          <dup_id>800</dup_id>
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>major</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.7.4</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Bryan Coutch">bryan.coutch</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>helder.magalhaes</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2884</commentid>
            <who name="Bryan Coutch">bryan.coutch</who>
            <bug_when>2008-03-06 16:21:16 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I have been working on a qooxdoo layout problem that I encountered, and quite frankly, it has me stumped.

I have included a small(-ish) program that demonstrates some of the main problems I have been having.

I have a qx.ui.window.Window presenting a wizard-like interface.  The left-hand navigation is a TreeVirtual (just a table in this example, has the same problem).  The problem here is that if I have more rows than can fit in the visible area, the window gets stretched until every row is visible, stuttering one row at a time.  If you have 100’s of nodes in the navigation tree, the bottom of the window will eventually disappear.  It’s impossible to shrink the window height smaller than the number of visible rows in the table.  The only way around this that I’ve found is to set an absolute table height, certainly not an ideal solution.

The 2nd problem is similar, with the table on the right hand side.  That table prevents me from shrinking the window width.  If you expand the width of the window, the flex columns will take up more space, and you will not be able to shrink the window again.

The 3rd problem is with the right hand table in IE6.  As soon the window is displayed, It will just keep expanding forever.  Setting an absolute width on the table fixes the expanding forever problem, but then what’s the point of having a resizable window?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2892</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2008-03-10 17:36:25 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Clearly a duplicate: same description, although no attachments. A mistake during bug report creation, I believe...

*** This bug has been marked as a duplicate of bug 800 ***</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37875</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:23:03 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>