<bug>
          <bug_id>8077</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2014-01-31 14:25:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Calendar: allow to only select weekdays</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-02-04 14:38:02 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>website.widgets</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>VERIFIED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>4.0</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          <cc>derrell.lipman</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>34918</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2014-01-31 14:25:35 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Suppose you&#39;d like to use the calendar to let a customer select a service date 
(e.g. to call him back). For this use case it is necessary that the customer is 
only allowed to select weekdays (Monday till Friday).

The Saturdays and Sundays should not be clickable and it should be possible to 
style these days with an own appearance.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>34936</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2014-02-03 14:48:26 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Added a new config option &quot;selectableWeekDays&quot;. This is an Array of week days (index 0 is Sunday like in the Date object). To allow only week days, use

calendar.setConfig(&quot;selectableWeekDays&quot;, [1, 2, 3, 4, 5]);

In the UI, unavailable week day buttons will get the &quot;disabled&quot; attribute. Let me know if this is sufficient for styling purposes.

Fixed with 95920b78a6dc30583bee949cecf3027ce0e79d83 (master)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>34938</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2014-02-03 15:17:37 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Suggestion, while you&#39;re working on this...

Instead of just allowing the user to specify an array of weekdays, how about making it more general. Maybe the application requires selection of dates only within a particular range, i.e., Wednesdays or Fridays during the dates 5 February 2014 until 6 March 2014.

I&#39;d suggest an interface such as a user-provided &quot;accept&quot; function which returns true if the selected date is acceptable; false otherwise... or possibly return null if the date is acceptable; or, if the date is not acceptable, a string to display to the user (in some standard fashion) as to what dates are acceptable.

Feel free to re-close this bug if this suggestion is out of scope. It just seems a reasonable extension.

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>34942</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2014-02-03 17:50:11 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #3)

I like that idea, Derrell. Limiting the selectable week days and configuring date ranges (bug #8078) were the specific requirements we had, but an &quot;accept&quot; function could be a useful alternative option. Could you please open a separate report for that?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>34944</commentid>
            <who name="Alexander Steitz">alexander.steitz</who>
            <bug_when>2014-02-04 10:58:02 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Works as expected and the &#39;disabled&#39; state is fine to use for styling.

@Derrell:
I set this bug back to &#39;Resolved&#39; since from my point of view the task is done. Your proposal to extend the functionality of the calendar should be subject of an own bug report. It&#39;s worth an extra bug report :)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>34948</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2014-02-04 14:38:02 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #5)
&gt; Works as expected and the &#39;disabled&#39; state is fine to use for styling.
&gt; 
&gt; @Derrell:
&gt; I set this bug back to &#39;Resolved&#39; since from my point of view the task is done.
&gt; Your proposal to extend the functionality of the calendar should be subject of
&gt; an own bug report. It&#39;s worth an extra bug report :)

See bug #8085.

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>