<bug>
          <bug_id>812</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-03-27 08:06:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Focus handler causing &#39;length&#39; is null or not an object</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:20:29 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core</component>
          <version>0.7.3</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>0.7.4</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2918</commentid>
            <who name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</who>
            <bug_when>2008-03-27 08:06:28 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Over the time that we have been using qooxdoo we have had scattered instances of our application causing this error under IE7 in Windows (XP and possibly others):

1819672 ERROR: qx.event.handler.EventHandler[61]: Failed to dispatch key 
event: TypeError - &#39;length&#39; is null or not an object (#-2146823281)

This was typically with a build version. It caused the debug log window to pop up (normally it&#39;s suppressed for build). It normally occurred when setting focus back to the browser window running the application, perhaps by using the alt-Tab sequence under Windows.

It just happened to me when running a source version so I&#39;ve broken to the VS2003 debugger and spent some time analysing the code.

The call sequence is that a Tab key press has been made on the main qooxdoo document. The code is calling through to qx.event.handler.FocusHandler.getWidgetAfter() with parentContainer set to the qooxdoo document &quot;qx.ui.core.ClientDocument&quot; and widget set to a table control which had focus.

getWidgetAfter() is enumerating all the children of the ClientDocument via _getAllAfter(). This is so it can find the next control to use for focus, based on the position of the controls in the layout.

I had created a number of context menus and they had been disposed. However, similar to bug 693 these were still members of the top level document because they are not automatically removed.

Therefore when the disposed context menu was found in _getAllAfter() the code tried to enumerate children of the menu:

      var children = parent.getChildren();
      var child;
      var len = children.length;

In this case children is null, causing the exception.

Clearly I can work around this in my code by proper removal from the document. As I stated in bug 693 removal from the document should be automatic for any widget added to it if it is disposed.

However, I strongly feel that the FocusHandler code should be more robust by adding a check for disposed children in _getAllAfter:

    _getAllAfter : function(parent, widget, arr)
    {
      var children = parent.getChildren();
      var child;
      var len = children.length;

      for (var i=0; i&lt;len; i++)
      {
        child = children[i];

        if (child.isDisposed() || (!(child instanceof qx.ui.core.Parent) &amp;&amp; !(child instanceof qx.ui.basic.Terminator))) {
          continue;
        }

Hugh</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2919</commentid>
            <who name="Hugh Gibson">hgibson</who>
            <bug_when>2008-03-27 08:25:54 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Note that an alternative to auto-remove from the document or the explicit checking of disposed children is a debug test for isDisposed() and if so, logging an error message that the child should be removed from the document.

This would have saved me a lot of time and effort.

Hugh</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5319</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-06 15:29:42 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>To Fabian</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>6620</commentid>
            <who name="Fabian Jakobs">fabian.jakobs</who>
            <bug_when>2008-12-03 14:42:28 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>fixed in rev. 16823</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>36908</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:20:29 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>