<bug>
          <bug_id>823</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-04-18 09:52:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Enhancements for API Viewer</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 15:22:45 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>app.apiviewer.desktop</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>1.5</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Gabriel Munteanu">jajalinux</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Adrian Olaru">adrian.olaru</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2950</commentid>
            <who name="Jonathan Weiß">qooxdoo-bugs</who>
            <bug_when>2008-04-18 09:52:30 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>1. Add a &quot;Table of contents&quot; section to the beginning of each page containing hyper links to 
 - Constructor
 - Events
 - Properties
 - Methods
 - Static Methods
 - Appearances

2. Add a dependency graph for every class.

3. Add a class diagram for every widget.

4. New method type &quot;internal&quot;: this method is not private, but will not be considered for changes in the API</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>3795</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-07-11 14:29:21 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I do not think this is realistic in the 0.8 timeframe.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5155</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-03 20:17:53 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Long grown priorities normalized to P5 to increase a few of them afterwards.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>21278</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2010-11-15 10:23:50 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Especially the first suggestion could be interesting.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>22337</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-01-18 10:36:28 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Gabriel, please have a word with me before taking care of that bug. Not every mentioned enhancement is worth the effort.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24144</commentid>
            <who name="Gabriel Munteanu">jajalinux</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-20 10:27:28 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>fixed on trunk with rev. 26873.

observations:
1. [related to internal toggle]. when listing the package qx.bom.client [http://demo.qooxdoo.org/current/apiviewer/#qx.bom.client] in the current version, we list the internal classes of the package, even if the private toggle is off. Now that we have an &quot;internal&quot; toggle, do we want to not show these classes when the internal toggle is off? i kept the current behavior now.
2. we need an icon for the &quot;internal&quot; toggle button. Who should I address to provide one?

[related to TOC below]

3. there are cases , when protected, private and internal toggles are off, that certain sections are not visible [display: none]. the table of contents shows them. Check qx.bom.client.Browser class and click on methods_static item. What I did was to enable the toggle in the case a certain section is not shown due to this. As the user can have different toggle setup, the TOC could vary depending on his preferences. I say we should have a NOT changeable TOC, so the user would know what the class contains regardless of his toggle setup.
4. a special case is the inherited toggle. there are cases when for example &quot;Events&quot; section gets enabled when the inherited button is enabled, but the events item does not exist in the TOC, as the class doesn&#39;t have events of its own. I say we should have in TOC, only the class&#39; own items, and not the inherited ones too.
5. from the code, I see that we could have an &quot;appearances&quot; section, yet i couldn&#39;t find any example of such a class with &quot;appearances&quot;. can you give me an example? also, we have no icons for &quot;appearances&quot; class members. Should I remove this section ? [it adds an empty div container in the DOM of the page]</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24175</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-21 08:56:36 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #5)
&gt; fixed on trunk with rev. 26873.
&gt; 
&gt; observations:
&gt; 1. [related to internal toggle]. when listing the package qx.bom.client
&gt; [http://demo.qooxdoo.org/current/apiviewer/#qx.bom.client] in the current
&gt; version, we list the internal classes of the package, even if the private
&gt; toggle is off. Now that we have an &quot;internal&quot; toggle, do we want to not show
&gt; these classes when the internal toggle is off? i kept the current behavior now.

I guess thats ok to keep it the way it is. The package documentation should always reflect whats in the package an the internal classes do have a different color which is enough for me.


&gt; 2. we need an icon for the &quot;internal&quot; toggle button. Who should I address to
&gt; provide one?

As far as I know, the Icons used in the API-viewer are from an Eclipse icon set. But its best to ask Andreas. I recall that he had this icon set and hopefully he can give you a fitting icon. 


&gt; [related to TOC below]
&gt; 
&gt; 3. there are cases , when protected, private and internal toggles are off, that
&gt; certain sections are not visible [display: none]. the table of contents shows
&gt; them. Check qx.bom.client.Browser class and click on methods_static item. What
&gt; I did was to enable the toggle in the case a certain section is not shown due
&gt; to this. As the user can have different toggle setup, the TOC could vary
&gt; depending on his preferences. I say we should have a NOT changeable TOC, so the
&gt; user would know what the class contains regardless of his toggle setup.

Agreed! Keep the TOC always the same.


&gt; 4. a special case is the inherited toggle. there are cases when for example
&gt; &quot;Events&quot; section gets enabled when the inherited button is enabled, but the
&gt; events item does not exist in the TOC, as the class doesn&#39;t have events of its
&gt; own. I say we should have in TOC, only the class&#39; own items, and not the
&gt; inherited ones too.

Hm, thats a good question. On the one hand, I would like to have the TOC reflect the current page but on the other hand, the current class. As we can&#39;t have both without changing the TOC on runtime, I think we need to do that. My suggestion is to keep the TOC as described in 3 as long as inherited is not enabled. If enabled / disabled, we should update the TOC if necessary.


&gt; 5. from the code, I see that we could have an &quot;appearances&quot; section, yet i
&gt; couldn&#39;t find any example of such a class with &quot;appearances&quot;. can you give me
&gt; an example? also, we have no icons for &quot;appearances&quot; class members. Should I
&gt; remove this section ? [it adds an empty div container in the DOM of the page]

I can&#39;t recall why it landed in the code at all. I don&#39;t think we have an example for that. Could you make a blame and check out the history of that code? Maybe that gives you some more information about who added it and whats the state of that code.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24221</commentid>
            <who name="Gabriel Munteanu">jajalinux</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-27 14:35:40 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>the &quot;appearances&quot; panel has been introduced by fjakobs with rev. 6897.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24229</commentid>
            <who name="Gabriel Munteanu">jajalinux</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-28 10:43:33 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>i can&#39;t seem to mark it as solved, as it depends on other 3 bugs.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24254</commentid>
            <who name="Gabriel Munteanu">jajalinux</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-29 17:03:37 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext> http://demo.qooxdoo.org/devel/apiviewer/#qx.ui.core.Widget
At least in Chrome the icon for Methods-Static overlaps the text 
 i.e. in the new navigation bar you introduced.
 ae@united.domain: Also, please use the same wording as in the content below, e.g. &quot;Methods-Static&quot; --&gt; &quot;Static methods&quot;</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24255</commentid>
            <who name="Gabriel Munteanu">jajalinux</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-29 17:04:38 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>If a section like &quot;Properties&quot; was closed, you should open it when a user selects &quot;Properties&quot; from the navigation.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24257</commentid>
            <who name="Gabriel Munteanu">jajalinux</who>
            <bug_when>2011-04-29 17:11:58 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This auto expand also seems to be broken when selecting a search result for a class that is currently open but does have the corresponding section collapsed.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>24293</commentid>
            <who name="Gabriel Munteanu">jajalinux</who>
            <bug_when>2011-05-02 13:56:37 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>fixed on trunk with rev. 26982.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>37794</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 15:22:45 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Closed all bugs already shipped with a release.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>