<bug>
          <bug_id>8353</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2014-05-16 09:01:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Focus event test fails in Chrome</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-05-21 16:37:11 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.event</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>3.5.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Chrome</cf_browser>
          <cf_browser_version>34, 35 beta</cf_browser_version>

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40286</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2014-05-16 09:01:57 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>qx.test.event.type.Focus.testRelatedTarget fails in Chrome (34 stable and 35 beta). This test has failed occasionally in automated test runs for a while but as of today (8c9514a359614b681f257e90fc8c98c0f1b15b6f) it also fails when executed manually.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40363</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2014-05-21 16:37:11 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The test creates two ui.form.TextFields and focuses the first one, then focuses the second one and checks if the focus event&#39;s relatedTarget is the first field.
event.handler.Focus.__onNativeFocus doesn&#39;t use the native relatedTarget property but instead stores the focused element in a property and uses the previous value as the relatedTarget for the qooxdoo event when the native focus event triggers a property change. In Chrome, focusing the second field will under very specific circumstances trigger a focusout event on the first field. event.handler.Focus listens for this events and resets its focus property to null so that when __onNativeFocus is called, relatedTarget is also set to null. For reasons neither Martin nor myself understand, this focusout event is always fired if the test code is executed in the Test Runner&#39;s iframe (but not in any other qx app&#39;s iframe) and also if the app containing the test code is loaded from the browser cache, but never if the app is loaded after clearing the cache. That would point to a timing issue masked by longer times but the bug is also present if nocache parameters are added to the script tags.

TL;DR: We don&#39;t grok what causes the problem so we added a workaround where we store the native focus event&#39;s relatedTarget and use that if the handler&#39;s focus property is null.

Fixed (hopefully) with
7fc8f18d8d5d95864047987f857333685fc27274 on master
40e06a813c565c8f87d491be2a2b902ed83977f4 on branch_3_5_x</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>