<bug>
          <bug_id>8393</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2014-05-30 15:04:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>No tap events when moving the mouse while clicking</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-06-02 14:10:07 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.event</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>4.0</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Internet Explorer</cf_browser>
          <cf_browser_version>10</cf_browser_version>

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40434</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2014-05-30 15:04:52 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>In IE 10, no tap events are fired if the mouse is moved at all between pressing and releasing the button.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40435</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2014-05-30 15:13:55 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>There were two problems here:

1) qx.event.handler.GestureCore._isBelowTapMaxDistance used the pointerType property to get the maximum allowed pixel distance between pointerdown and pointerup events. In IE 10, the value of this property is an integer, not a string as expected. That&#39;s why the check behaved as if the max distance was 0 and no events were fired unless pointerdown and pointerup occurred at the exact same coordinates. Fixed by using the cross-browser getPointerType method instead (with b1097e36ab611d1a231889ff7fb80e4b5efcf169 on master).

2) The browser always fires click events, no matter how far apart the mousedown and mouseup events occurred. So our max distance of 10 pixels feels very small, e.g. when you&#39;re moving the cursor down a list of items and clicking each: If your cursor isn&#39;t very slow, no items will be selected. I increased the max distance to 25 pixels but even that isn&#39;t really enough. We should verify if we really need the distance check, at least when a mouse is used.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40443</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2014-06-02 13:09:34 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Even removing the max distance check has no effect since there&#39;s another check in GestureCore.gestureFinish that aborts the gesture if the target differs from the one in gesturestart. This is like the native behavior of the &#39;click&#39; event, however a click is always fired on the document.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40444</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2014-06-02 14:10:07 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>We decided to keep the target check since it&#39;s the correct behavior, even if it means sacrificing a small bit of user convenience. Also further increased the max distance value to 50 pixels for the mouse (with 57a3221855c052c2a7c7aff6e04b3bb3b89b8a55).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>