<bug>
          <bug_id>8447</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2014-06-25 11:33:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Target of drag event is wrong</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-10-29 09:34:36 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WORKSFORME</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>minor</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Mustafa Sak">mustafa.sak</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          <cc>alexander.steitz</cc>
    
    <cc>andreas.parusel</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40581</commentid>
            <who name="Mustafa Sak">mustafa.sak</who>
            <bug_when>2014-06-25 11:33:19 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Please try out this playground example: http://tinyurl.com/m9nsbba

Drag the gray box above the green one. The log will print &quot;green&quot; twice, which points you to the fact, that the green box was taken as drag target.

Recommended to take the gray box as drag target.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40647</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-07-02 10:06:11 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The sample does not seem to work. Could you check what&#39;s wrong with the sample?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40648</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-07-02 10:07:53 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>My bad, seems tow work. :(</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40667</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-07-03 12:49:07 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Just checkend the behavior. Could not see that the target was green. That would have surprised me anyway because the target is defined as the element the listener is registered so it should always be the root.
As for the original target. This is defined as the target of the event initializing the action. In the drag &amp; drop case, this is the move event which start the drag &amp; drop session. So if the session start on the root, the root element will be the original target or, if the session starts over the green widget, it will be this widget. This is the defined behavior and did not change from 3.5 to 4.0.
But in 3.5, the offset until the drag &amp; drop starts is much lesser than in 4.0 which is 3px compared 50 px. Thats why this effect is nut that visible in older versions. To get back to the old behavior, I introduced a new static named MIN_DRAG_DISTANCE which is by default 5 px and is use for the min drag distance until the drag &amp; drop sequence is started.

maser: dd0e9681e4ecbf66feb5f9d6d81ca08b65ccbb63
4.0.x: 518fa8b06e5290d3288a5268dd7ba43b5660bfec</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40688</commentid>
            <who name="Mustafa Sak">mustafa.sak</who>
            <bug_when>2014-07-04 10:44:59 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Works almost fine. Mind you would start to drag in the right inner edge of an widget. Because of MIN_DRAG_DISTANCE the Original target would not be the expected one.

Recommended to get the target from &quot;pointerdown&quot; event as original target of drag events.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40701</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-07-07 08:01:40 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This could be fixed even though it has a much lower priority now because it is the same behavior we have before. To be honest, I don&#39;t think its worth the effort at all.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>