<bug>
          <bug_id>8515</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2014-08-05 14:07:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Move contents of folder tool/admin/www into a separate repository</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-12-16 11:44:25 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>other</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>4.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Tobias Oberrauch">tobias.oberrauch</assigned_to>
          <cc>derrell.lipman</cc>
    
    <cc>tobias.oberrauch</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40908</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-08-05 14:07:07 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The framework repo contains all themes / data necessary for the qooxdoo.org website. All this data is only necessary if you work with the qooxdoo homepage in general. So for the common user, it is not necessary to check out those files. In the first place it would be good to check if we can simply move those files to another repo. As far as I know, parts of the manual rely on the resources of in these folders so there need to be a way to access the resources to build the manual. So it would be good to come up with a plan how to move the content and still be able to have the same functionality as before.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40909</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2014-08-05 14:21:29 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #0)
&gt;  As far as I know, parts of the manual rely on the
&gt; resources of in these folders so there need to be a way to access the resources
&gt; to build the manual. So it would be good to come up with a plan how to move the
&gt; content and still be able to have the same functionality as before.

You might consider creating a separate repository for the website stuff, and then including that repository as a &quot;git submodule&quot; in the framework repo. Those needing to build the manual could do the &quot;git submodule init ; git submodule update&quot; commands, which will bring in the external module. Those not needing to build the manual can just carry on without issuing those commands, and the external (website) repo will not be copied into their working tree.

Derrell</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>40915</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-08-06 08:12:55 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Sounds like a good idea, thanks Derrell. :)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>41340</commentid>
            <who name="Tobias Oberrauch">tobias.oberrauch</who>
            <bug_when>2014-10-08 16:24:49 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Hi Derrell,

we took you great idea and create a new repo for the website stuff.
https://github.com/qooxdoo/www

Cheers Tobias</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>