<bug>
          <bug_id>8580</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2014-09-05 11:54:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>ui.treevirtual.Treevirtual: dragging an item does not set the item as selected</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-09-11 09:04:51 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.treevirtual</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WORKSFORME</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>minor</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          
          <reporter>qooxdoo</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>41131</commentid>
            <who name="">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2014-09-05 11:54:18 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Steps to reproduce:

Open http://tinyurl.com/nadavns (Playground demo). Drag an unselected item.

Observed:

Dragging starts without the item set as selected. So later calls to datamodel.getSelectedNodes() does not include the dragged item.

Expected: 

The dragged item should be set as selected first (or with key modifier added to the selection) as seen in the v3.5 playground (for your convenience http://tinyurl.com/pv3h5af).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>41139</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-09-08 08:54:45 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>This is by design and has been changed in from 3.5 to 4.0 version. It reflects native OS behavior of e.g. OSX which also does handle it that way. If you want to have that, you can simply do it yourself by using the getDragTarget() on any drag event and add the element to the selection.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>41140</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-09-08 08:55:04 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>41144</commentid>
            <who name="">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2014-09-08 12:54:50 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I can live with &quot;Works for me&quot;, thanks for the quick hint to the solution to restore the old behaviour.

Just as note: the old behaviour was like it is in Windows or KDE desktop (havent&#39;t tried Gnome etc.) and also e.g. Google Chrome.  Given the current market shares the default behaviour now is uncommon to most (desktop) users (ok I mean M* users not KDE :-).  As it is intended: what about making it configurable?  Rationale: even if I easily can implement the old (normal?) behaviour, I have to do it for every drag handling.  If I asume one would want consistent behaviour I would want to define this globally per app (app/os?) but not for each drag&amp;drop handler.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>41161</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-09-11 09:04:51 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #3)
&gt; I can live with &quot;Works for me&quot;, thanks for the quick hint to the solution to
&gt; restore the old behaviour.
&gt; 
&gt; Just as note: the old behaviour was like it is in Windows or KDE desktop
&gt; (havent&#39;t tried Gnome etc.) and also e.g. Google Chrome.  Given the current
&gt; market shares the default behaviour now is uncommon to most (desktop) users (ok
&gt; I mean M* users not KDE :-).  As it is intended: what about making it
&gt; configurable?  Rationale: even if I easily can implement the old (normal?)
&gt; behaviour, I have to do it for every drag handling.  If I asume one would want
&gt; consistent behaviour I would want to define this globally per app (app/os?) but
&gt; not for each drag&amp;drop handler.

I currently have no idea how I could get that done in any generic handler infrastructure because the drag action would need to change the selection which could be quite different for any kind of widget (think of custom widgets). As there is a way to get the desired behavior, I don&#39;t see any urgent need to take action.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>