<bug>
          <bug_id>8655</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2014-10-24 10:38:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Fix next widgets relying on event capturing</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-11-26 13:28:27 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>next</product>
          <component>core</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Christian Hagendorn">christian.hagendorn</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>41447</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-10-24 10:38:19 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>With the old event layer, we had a event capturing for all events which made it quite easy to implement a slider e.g. With the new layer, we don&#39;t have that feature until now but some widgets still rely on its availability. We should either
- fix the widget code so it works like expected without capturing
- introduce a capturing mechanism for the new layer

The widgets found in a quick check which behave wrong:
- Slider
- Carousel
- Removable List-Items in the mobile showcase

IT&#39;s pretty easy to reproduce. Just start dragging the slider, move over to the overview page and release the mouse button. Moving back to the slider will still update the slider as the buttons was still pressed.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>41714</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-11-26 13:28:27 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>This was a big one because all widgets relied on the track event. But the track event did not end when the pointerup was on a different target than the start event. So we took a look at how the track event is implemented and decided to move the whole track handling from the gesture handler to its own handler. This offered an elegant and easy way to stop track events based on the pointerup of the document element instead of the original target. With that almost all widgets could be fixed without much change in the widget or app code itself.

next: 0fe7f09d5379b354d5e200ada897180f8be746cd</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>