<bug>
          <bug_id>8861</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2015-01-09 14:25:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Bad table performance with custom HeaderRenderer</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2015-01-12 16:40:49 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.table</component>
          <version>4.0.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>NEW</bug_status>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Andreas Fink">andreas.fink</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>42119</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Fink">andreas.fink</who>
            <bug_when>2015-01-09 14:25:47 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>We have discovered, that some tables in our qooxdoo app have heavy performance problems while rendering.
After some time spend with debugging I found out that this only effects tables with custom HeaderRenderer. It seems that adding custom Renderer to the table columns produces many calls to the createHederCell function of the HeaderRenderer. The time needed from the constructor call of the table to the appear event of the table raised with 40 columns from 600 ms to 4 seconds…
 
I was able to work around this performance problem by implementing our own class extending qx.ui.table.pane.Model. There I removed the “headerCellRendererChanged” Listener inside the setTableColumnModel function. It seems that we doesn’t need this functionality. A HeaderRenderer never changes after the table appears. It seems like a bug to me and maybe it is best to add this listener after the table appeared. 

Here is a playground example to reproduce the problem (mind the comment):
http://tinyurl.com/lk5m9g9</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>42141</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2015-01-12 16:40:49 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report. Your solutions sounds like a quick fix which does not solve but delay the problem. Nevertheless, this is much better than the current implementation. Do you want to file a pull request for that?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>