<bug>
          <bug_id>8896</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2015-02-02 10:08:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>current &quot;virtual&quot; navigationBar concept is confusing and doesn&#39;t fit to next.</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2015-03-23 14:16:21 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>next</product>
          <component>ui</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Andreas Parusel">andreas.parusel</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>42338</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Parusel">andreas.parusel</who>
            <bug_when>2015-02-02 10:08:32 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>More than once, I had stumbled over the navBar&#39;s current behavior: For any app there only exists one single navBar-container. The contents of this container get swapped depending on which page is displayed (happens in qx.ui.container.Navigation._update()).

In my opinion this is confusing and doesn&#39;t fit to next&#39;s low-level philosophy where the DOM should resemble the app&#39;s current state: During debugging it easily happens that you are stepping through the code of &quot;pageA&quot; while the navBar still says &quot;pageB&quot; because its contents haven&#39;t been swapped yet. Trying to query pageA&#39;s navBar-contents will fail because they are not in the DOM yet (but accessible within the class) and so on. All this is confusing and feels like a misfit.

I think a concept where each page, or even smaller building-blocks like lists or menus (see iOS), would have their own navBar-instance would be more concise.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>42741</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2015-03-09 14:52:34 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Each NavigationPage now creates its own navigation bar. As before, this element is not in the DOM until container.Navigation._update is called, but it&#39;s always accessible from the page itself by calling this.getNavigationBar()</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>42742</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2015-03-09 15:14:59 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Fixed with 1bae33fe3526b90aa80f04f72cc574e6247d6830</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>42862</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Parusel">andreas.parusel</who>
            <bug_when>2015-03-16 10:48:19 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>It&#39;s definitely way better than before.

What still doesn&#39;t feel 100% right is the fact that only one navigationbar is visible at each time in the DOM. If I have an app with say 3 pages, q(&quot;.page&quot;).length is 3 while q(&quot;.navigationbar&quot;).length is 1. Intuitively should be 3 too.

Is this maybe still possible or would it involve big architectural changes?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>42922</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2015-03-23 14:16:21 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Good point. Changed container.Navigation so that the navigation bars of all pages are added to the DOM and and toggled using the CSS display property. Fixed with 9410a42ee1f324865d782a1cdfe2aafe6de84f9a</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>