<bug>
          <bug_id>8984</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2015-03-04 15:33:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Cordova/PhoneGap support is incomplete and partly outdated</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2015-03-24 15:37:31 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>next</product>
          <component>other</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Andreas Parusel">andreas.parusel</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>42700</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Parusel">andreas.parusel</who>
            <bug_when>2015-03-04 15:33:34 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I had a look at the PhoneGap-specific code in qx.ui.page.Page and I noticed the following things:

1. Incompleteness: The Cordova-support in the framework is from a time where it was a iOS and Android game. 
Today there are a lot more platforms like windows, firefoxos and soon even a desktop platform and the Cordova-API seems to get more and more fragmented among its platforms. For example there is no &quot;backbutton&quot; event fired by cordova on windows platform anymore. To accomplish support for the physical back button, one has to interact directly with the winJS-framework.

2. Outdated: Support for Androids menu-button is baked into the framework. As far as I know there is no menu-button anymore on devices which shipped with Android 4.0 or newer. 

From a framework perspective, it&#39;s maybe worth considering to move the Cordova-specific stuff away from the framework and to the application.

If it stays inside the framework, a clear decision has to be made and communicated wehere to cross the line, e.g. which platforms should be supported and which minimal sets of features.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>42701</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2015-03-05 08:04:27 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Totally agree, either we should add propper support or drop it. At the moment, I would suggest the second option.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>42852</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Parusel">andreas.parusel</who>
            <bug_when>2015-03-16 08:01:01 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Another good example is qx.ui.dialog.Manager.

There are phone gap-specific conditions intended to invoke native dialogs. As fas as I can tell, this doesn&#39;t work anymore or at least not out the phonegap-box without additional phonegap-plugins.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>42932</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2015-03-24 15:37:31 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Removed outdated PhoneGap/Cordova support with a5d39dab4e0108764dcb18a485df12008df04c01</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>