<bug>
          <bug_id>9</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2006-06-07 13:16:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Add a Splashscreen widget</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2014-03-03 08:46:01 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>LATER</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P5</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          <votes>22</votes>
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Sebastian Werner">info</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>badams</cc>
    
    <cc>daniel</cc>
    
    <cc>gradinf</cc>
    
    <cc>helder.magalhaes</cc>
    
    <cc>info</cc>
    
    <cc>j-b.briaud</cc>
    
    <cc>kentilton</cc>
    
    <cc>skar.karthikeyan</cc>
          <qa_contact name="qooxdoo bugs mailing list">qooxdoo-bugs</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>11</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2006-06-07 13:16:36 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>qooxdoo should support Slashscreens to indicate application loading. There should be an easy method to customize the loading screen of qooxdoo, if added sometimes.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>2817</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2008-01-30 17:52:30 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>A splash screen could also be available for each widget to show individual loading status.

In a complex application, one may have several heavy widgets which load independently. In these conditions, an individual splash screen (for each widget) could be more useful, as the user would be able to interact with the already loaded widgets (and still receive visual feedback on the loading status of the remaining widgets).</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>5160</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2008-09-03 20:17:55 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Long grown priorities normalized to P5 to increase a few of them afterwards.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>9310</commentid>
            <who name="Helder Magalhães">helder.magalhaes</who>
            <bug_when>2009-04-16 11:03:37 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #0)
&gt; qooxdoo should support Slashscreens to indicate application loading. There
&gt; should be an easy method to customize the loading screen of qooxdoo, if added
&gt; sometimes.

This seems to be (possibly) already supported through the use of a progressive loader [1]. Of course if would be nice if this was supported for any widget, naturally configured through a property, but it seems like this may already have been addressed...?

[1] http://demo.qooxdoo.org/0.8.2/demobrowser/index.html#progressive~ProgressiveLoader.html</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>15985</commentid>
            <who name="Sebastian Werner">info</who>
            <bug_when>2009-12-23 17:41:31 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>It seems to be better to not talk about a &quot;Widget&quot; here. It is more or less a simple HTML page which dynamically inserts the first script file when the document is ready.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>16018</commentid>
            <who name="skar">skar.karthikeyan</who>
            <bug_when>2010-01-04 12:25:32 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&#39;d like this feature too :)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18595</commentid>
            <who name="Christian Boulanger">info</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-08 17:55:12 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>There are two different requests here, I think: a) one for a splash widget that can be used AFTER the qooxdoo classes have been loaded and set up, and b) one that asks for a splash screen displayed while the initial code is loading. I think the bug should be about b), since a) can be implemented easily using a popup widget, while b) needs active changes by the framework developers. 

Such a splash screen would need to be painted by the bootstrap code, using pure HTML/DOM, since none of the widget infrastructure exists at this point. Ideally, it would display an icon and some text (which would default to qooxdoo branding stuff) and a bar indicating the load progress. 

All of this could be done using the generator, which would create the necessary code and insert it into the bootstrap code (source) or the final package code (build). In the source version, the bar could be advanced after one source file has been loaded, in the build version, after each part of the compiled code. Since the generator knows how many files/parts the code consists of, it should be very easy to implement. All kind of aspects of this system (whether to be shown at all, what icon/text to use, etc.) could be configured through the config.json file.

I think such a system would not only be nice for the end user (since they &quot;have something to look at&quot; while the code loads), but also is a plus in branding/marketing, since it informs the user prominently (unless configured otherwise) that the qooxdoo library is being used. 
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18596</commentid>
            <who name="Derrell Lipman">derrell.lipman</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-08 18:01:14 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Note also that qx.ui.progressive.Progressive and its FunctionCaller renderer can also help with this. Immediately after the code has been downloaded, the progress bar begins to show progress of initializing and generating the gui, and the user can see the gui progressing if so desired by the developer. An example is provided in the demobrowser at http://demo.qooxdoo.org/devel/demobrowser/#progressive~ProgressiveLoader.html

Derrell
</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>18599</commentid>
            <who name="Kenny Tilton">kentilton</who>
            <bug_when>2010-06-08 20:14:29 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #6)
&gt; There are two different requests here, I think: a) one for a splash widget that
&gt; can be used AFTER the qooxdoo classes have been loaded and set up, and b) one
&gt; that asks for a splash screen displayed while the initial code is loading. I
&gt; think the bug should be about b), since a) can be implemented easily using a
&gt; popup widget, while b) needs active changes by the framework developers. 

Yes, my concern is (b), and even if it is just HTML it would help to have that autogenerated by create-application.py. And as gravy, a noscript tag to alert folks who might have JS off. I can get either to work, but not both.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>35382</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2014-03-03 08:46:01 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>Move open issues to RESOLVED – LATER, whose last comment is older than a year.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>