<bug>
          <bug_id>9149</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2015-05-22 16:40:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Loading SVGs is partly broken on IE</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2015-07-16 08:57:45 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>core.io</component>
          <version>4.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>5.0.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Aleksandar Josipovic">nanexxo+qooxdoo</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          
          <qa_contact name="Richard Sternagel">richard.sternagel</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Internet Explorer</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43326</commentid>
            <who name="Aleksandar Josipovic">nanexxo+qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2015-05-22 16:40:28 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The way qooxdoo handles loading images doesn&#39;t work reliably for SVGs on IE.

Currently, the only way to make a SVG show up in IE11 is to set the scale property together with the dimensions of the image. 

non-scale playground link: http://tinyurl.com/pf5q2do
scale playground link: http://tinyurl.com/omgocln

And this will only work while the ImageLoader hasn&#39;t cached the result.
demo: http://tinyurl.com/ov8eyt3
This behavior has been reported here: http://bugzilla.qooxdoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=8623.

When testing these on IE10, only the one case where the image isn&#39;t set to scale didn&#39;t work.

There are two reasons why this is the case for both versions.
First, there is a difference between IE10 and IE11 which is mentioned in the bugreport linked above. When the ImageLoader loads an image via an img element, the element on IE11 won&#39;t have the attributes width and height set, even if the image is loaded, whereas on IE10 it will have them set.

This means for IE11 the check on line 295 in the ImageLoader 

      var isImageAvailable = function(imgElem) {
        return (imgElem &amp;&amp; imgElem.height !== 0);
      };

      // [BUG #7497]: IE11 doesn&#39;t properly emit an error event
      // when loading fails so augment success check
      if (event.type === &quot;load&quot; &amp;&amp; isImageAvailable(element))

will fail for every SVG request.
Would appending the element to the DOM be to drastic? If the element gets appended the height/width of the element can be determined and then qooxdoo could proceed as usual. Maybe restrict the appending to IE11.. I&#39;m not entirely sure how to fix this.

Second is naturalHeight/Width. IE10 and IE11 don&#39;t have these attributes set when the source is a SVG, which explains why it doesn&#39;t show when using IE10 as the ImageLoader assumes a image width and height of 0.
I&#39;m not sure why exactly the naturalHeight/Width attributes are used in this case. For every requested image a new img element is created without any dimensions set on the element. Shouldn&#39;t the naturalHeight and height always be identical given these circumstances?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43329</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2015-05-26 07:56:46 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the report. Sounds like you have invested a lot of time to get to that result. Have you thought of putting all that knowledge into code and supply a pull request?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43376</commentid>
            <who name="Aleksandar Josipovic">nanexxo+qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2015-06-11 15:38:59 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Done.
https://github.com/qooxdoo/qooxdoo/pull/137</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43377</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2015-06-11 15:49:41 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks. :)</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43462</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2015-07-16 08:57:45 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Thanks for the great pull request. Merged it to master and cherry-picked the commits to branch as well.

master: bd2834834c32089f0eee9bff4ba1968d784bcd4a
5.0.x: 59a21e2965b46c227c110a57b6bb8b87fadca01f</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>