<bug>
          <bug_id>9175</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2015-06-23 10:05:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Microsoft Edge: native scrollbar does not scroll when clicking on the scrollbar buttons</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2015-09-15 11:49:27 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.bars</component>
          <version>5.0</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows</op_sys>
          <bug_status>VERIFIED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>major</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>5.0.1</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</assigned_to>
          <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>Edge</cf_browser>
          <cf_browser_version>20.10162.0.0</cf_browser_version>

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43404</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2015-06-23 10:05:56 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Using Windows 10 Pro Insider Preview Build 10130
Browser Spartan 15.10130.0.0

Clicking on the scrollbar up down or left right buttons of a native scrollbar shows no reaction, while the non native scrollbar buttons work as expected.

To reproduce open the following demo in the spartan browser:

http://demo.qooxdoo.org/5.0/demobrowser/index.html#widget~ScrollBar.html</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43429</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2015-07-02 07:49:32 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&#39;ve tested this again wit the current Windows 10 Pro Insider Preview Build 10159 released yesterday, and the bug is still present.

As Edge will be the new default browser in Windows 10, this should be fixed until official realease on Juli 29.

I&#39;ve verified this with our application.

I&#39;m not able to verify this with the demobrowser at
http://demo.qooxdoo.org/5.0/demobrowser/index.html because the demobrowser does currently not start with the latest edge browser anymore.

Note that this bug is also reproducable in 
http://demo.qooxdoo.org/4.1/demobrowser/index.html#widget~ScrollBar.html</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43441</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2015-07-06 08:40:11 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Another test with current Windows 10 Insider Preview Build 10162 and Microsoft Edge 20.10162.0.0.

The bug is still present.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43443</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2015-07-06 11:29:33 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>@Daniel, could you have a look, please?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43446</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2015-07-06 14:37:29 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I could reproduce the problem in Microsoft Edge 20.10158.0.0 using a very simple demo application with just this code:

      var scrollBar = new qx.ui.core.scroll.NativeScrollBar(&quot;vertical&quot;).set({
        width: 50,
        height: 200,
        maximum: 500
      });

      this.getRoot().add(scrollBar, {top: 50, left: 50});

The problem is that no native scroll events are fired on the DOM element containing the scroll bar. I tried removing the touch-action: none style but that doesn&#39;t help, and neither does disabling qooxdoo&#39;s pointer and scroll event handling. I&#39;m officially at my wit&#39;s end, any ideas would be appreciated.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43447</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2015-07-06 15:29:17 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>@Daniel: a simple fiddle (pure JS) receives scroll events on a div containing another, larger div:

http://jsfiddle.net/thungyex/

tested with edge 20.10162.0.0

scroll events are generated for scroll knob dragging, clicking in between scroll knob and scroll bar buttons and the scroll bar buttons themselves.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43448</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2015-07-06 15:38:53 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #5)
&gt; @Daniel: a simple fiddle (pure JS) receives scroll events on a div containing
&gt; another, larger div:
&gt; 
&gt; http://jsfiddle.net/thungyex/
&gt; 
&gt; tested with edge 20.10162.0.0
&gt; 
&gt; scroll events are generated for scroll knob dragging, clicking in between
&gt; scroll knob and scroll bar buttons and the scroll bar buttons themselves.

Yes, the problem is definitely caused by framework code. But it&#39;s not any native scroll listener or the pointer event layer so I don&#39;t know where else to look.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43449</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2015-07-06 17:05:55 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Ah OK! Then I&#39;ve misunderstood your comment:

(In reply to comment #4)
&gt; The problem is that no native scroll events are fired on the DOM element
&gt; containing the scroll bar. 

Then the problem is that the event gets lost while bubbling up? Or does some other element intercept the events so they never show up?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43450</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2015-07-06 17:15:43 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #7)
&gt; Ah OK! Then I&#39;ve misunderstood your comment:
&gt; 
&gt; (In reply to comment #4)
&gt; &gt; The problem is that no native scroll events are fired on the DOM element
&gt; &gt; containing the scroll bar. 

Right, that should have been &#39;no native events are fired in a qooxdoo application&#39;.

&gt; 
&gt; Then the problem is that the event gets lost while bubbling up? Or does some
&gt; other element intercept the events so they never show up?

Yes, that seems likely, which is why I tried searching the framework for any &#39;scroll&#39; listeners and disabling them if stopPropagation or preventDefault are used in the callback. Didn&#39;t help, though :(</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43451</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2015-07-06 17:55:22 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Some more information: I went back in history with the online demobrowser and found that it does not work back to qooxdoo 1.0.

So this is not something introduced in the latest few versions.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43452</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2015-07-06 18:36:25 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>@Daniel: I think I nailed it!

Open the edge debugger (F12). Select the scrollbar element (via dom explorer) and disable the width (for vertical scroll bars) or height (horizontal scroll bars) attribute in the css editor.

After this the scroll bars work as expected!

So setting a width or height is causing the faulty behaviour.

I think this is a bug in edge.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43454</commentid>
            <who name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</who>
            <bug_when>2015-07-07 09:36:32 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>(In reply to comment #10)
&gt; @Daniel: I think I nailed it!
&gt; 
&gt; Open the edge debugger (F12). Select the scrollbar element (via dom explorer)
&gt; and disable the width (for vertical scroll bars) or height (horizontal scroll
&gt; bars) attribute in the css editor.
&gt; 
&gt; After this the scroll bars work as expected!
&gt; 
&gt; So setting a width or height is causing the faulty behaviour.
&gt; 
&gt; I think this is a bug in edge.

You&#39;re absolutely right. I went over the code that computes the scrollbar width/height and found a workaround for the exact same problem in IE in qx.ui.core.ScrollNativeScrollBar (line 287). Extending the fix to Edge solves the problem. I guess MS faithfully ported that old IE bug over to Edge :) Thank you very much for taking the time to investigate this issue.

Fixed with
53e11fda354d39642abe960d4f039649cf87f1bf master
bc63d9740771763757a7ee4cdb5d225ecf69d23f branch_5_0_x</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43456</commentid>
            <who name="Dietrich Streifert">dietrich.streifert</who>
            <bug_when>2015-07-08 17:10:51 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>I&#39;ve build our apps with current master including the native ms edge scroll bar fix and native scroll bars work as they should.

Thank you for the fix Daniel!</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43546</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2015-09-14 16:09:59 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Cherry-picked fix onto branch_4_1_x as well with commit 1c19e853.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>