<bug>
          <bug_id>9192</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2015-08-12 14:56:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Element used instead of Widget for drag and drop</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2015-09-15 14:03:51 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop</component>
          <version>master</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>NEW</bug_status>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P2</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Cajus Pollmeier">pollmeier</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</assigned_to>
          <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43486</commentid>
            <who name="Cajus Pollmeier">pollmeier</who>
            <bug_when>2015-08-12 14:56:06 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>We have several cases where we run into errors when dragging and dropping. That is caused by an invalid usage of the original target widget.

See: https://github.com/qooxdoo/qooxdoo/pull/142</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43510</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2015-08-21 15:39:43 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Cajus, thanks for the report.

As you mention in your PR&#39;s comment, the mixin code sometimes seems to try to operate on a DOM element whereas it expects only to handle qooxdoo widgets. Usually such widgets are attached to an event, but there might be occasions just to get handed a DOM element (see qx.ui.core.EventHandler L296).

What are the &quot;several cases&quot; specifically that you run into problems. Is it limited to certain browsers/OSes? That would be good to know.

Anyway, one should make the mixin code more defensive in that it determines the widget related to a DOM element, but only after an appropriate check. Would you add such a check for widget to your PR?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43512</commentid>
            <who name="Cajus Pollmeier">pollmeier</who>
            <bug_when>2015-08-21 16:24:18 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Can you direct me to the place where the &quot;drag&quot; event is fired with a qx Widget? Maybe there&#39;s some magic I don&#39;t see or understand, but it looks like it is always fired with an Element. Is there a place where it is mapped?

It is browser independent and OS independent.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43550</commentid>
            <who name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</who>
            <bug_when>2015-09-15 14:03:51 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The patch looks a bit too easy. What if a widget will be returned? The &#39;getWidgetByElement&#39; can not handle widgets as input so there should be a check if its a widget or DOM element.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>