<bug>
          <bug_id>9208</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2015-09-14 11:42:00 +0200</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Several issues when closing Window widget by ESC key</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2015-09-29 14:39:37 +0200</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.layout</component>
          <version>5.0</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>NEW</bug_status>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>minor</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Joseph Karras">stylkarr</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>gnikolaidis</cc>
    
    <cc>qooxdoo</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Martin Wittemann">martin.wittemann</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43544</commentid>
            <who name="Joseph Karras">stylkarr</who>
            <bug_when>2015-09-14 11:42:24 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>The problem is harder to describe than see in action, so here is a playground application that demonstrates it:

http://tinyurl.com/nsszdt6

1st bug: Click the button to open the window, hover the hover area and press ESC on your keyboard -&gt; an exception is thrown

2nd bug: Click the button to open the window, hover your mouse over the edge of the window to change the cursor to its resize variant, press ESC on your keyboard -&gt; cursor is not reset</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43563</commentid>
            <who name="Andreas Ecker">qooxdoo</who>
            <bug_when>2015-09-22 09:39:00 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>Joseph, thanks for the report. Confirmed the issues. 

For future reports incorporating multiple albeit similar issues, please choose individual bug entries (which of course could refer to each other easily). 

I adjusted the issue title to better reflect the actual issues. Your initial &quot;Layout queue call on null getContentElement() for popups of disposed windows&quot; suggests you did some analysis already? If you have suggestions for a fix, please feel free to provide more info or even pull requests, thanks.</thetext>
          </long_desc>
          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43576</commentid>
            <who name="Joseph Karras">stylkarr</who>
            <bug_when>2015-09-29 14:39:37 +0200</bug_when>
            <thetext>No I don&#39;t have a fix to suggest :(. I did some analysis, but I don&#39;t know how the internals of the layouts are working. Anyway, here is what I have found, while debugging:

I saw that the renderLayout function [1] asks its disposed children to render. So whenever a child layout item is execute its renderLayout function [2] the getContentElement() was returning correctly null because that item is disposed.

A simple fix would be to skip renderLayout() when a disposed child is encountered.

[1] https://github.com/qooxdoo/qooxdoo/blob/release_5_0_1/framework/source/class/qx/ui/layout/Canvas.js#L179 
[2] https://github.com/qooxdoo/qooxdoo/blob/release_5_0_1/framework/source/class/qx/ui/core/Widget.js#L1023</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>