<bug>
          <bug_id>9248</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2016-01-29 12:05:00 +0100</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Pointerup outside checkbox still toggles its value</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2016-01-29 12:06:39 +0100</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Unclassified</classification>
          <product>framework</product>
          <component>desktop.form</component>
          <version>5.0.1</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>iOS</op_sys>
          <bug_status>UNCONFIRMED</bug_status>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>minor</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>unspecified</target_milestone>
          
          
          
          
          <reporter>bader</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Unassigned">none</assigned_to>
          <cc>bader</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Daniel Wagner">daniel.wagner</qa_contact>
          <cf_browser>---</cf_browser>
          

      

      

      

          <long_desc isprivate="0">
            <commentid>43685</commentid>
            <who name="">bader</who>
            <bug_when>2016-01-29 12:05:51 +0100</bug_when>
            <thetext>I am using a vanilla desktop checkbox like in http://demo.qooxdoo.org/current/showcase/#Form

On a desktop computer I can do a mousedown on the checkbox, drag the cursor outside it and then release the mouse button. The state of the checkbox has not changed, as expected.

If I do the same on an iPad (just with touch events), the state of the checkbox does change when I release the finger outside the checkbox. I would expect it to behave the same as with mouse events.

I have currently no opportunity to test it on an iPhone or any android device.

On the mobile version of the checkbox it works as expected. The difference is, the mobile widget has an own listener on &quot;tap&quot;. The desktop version inherits from qx.ui.form.ToggleButton which has listeners (amongst others) on pointerup and pointerout. The pointerup listener fires an execute event (which finally toggles the checkbox value) if the widget does not have the state &quot;abandonded&quot;. This state is set in the pointerout listener.

But the pointerout event is only fired after touchend/touchcancel (see qx.event.handler.PointerCore, l. 274 ff.). Thus, when one holds his finger down and moves it outside the widget, no pointerout is fired. The pointerout listener in ToggleButton is not fired and the state &quot;abandonded&quot; is not set. 

Is this behaviour intentional?</thetext>
          </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>